<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Five Minunte Reads</title>
    <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Five Minunte Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 16:49:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://fiveminutesread.github.io/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spider-Man battles Baldurs Gate in Bafta Games Awards</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/4b1a0d0e-dcc1-11ee-bb08-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 16:49:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/4b1a0d0e-dcc1-11ee-bb08-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Spider-Man battles Baldur&amp;rsquo;s Gate in Bafta Games Awards CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. Please share your best photos of the United States with CNN iReport.&#xA;Baldur&amp;rsquo;s Gate 3 leads the way with 10 nominations. Spider-Man 2 and Alan Wake 2 also in the running for Best Game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boy, 11, died trying social media craze - family</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/9b0754e2-dcc7-11ee-8c61-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 16:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/9b0754e2-dcc7-11ee-8c61-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Boy, 11, died trying social media craze - family Tommie-lee Gracie Billington died at a house in Lancaster on Saturday. His grandmother Tina Burns said he had been at a sleepover. She said he was taking part in a social media craze that involves sniffing or inhaling toxic fumes. The 11-year-old&amp;rsquo;s family say they are devastated by his death.&#xA;Police said the boy&amp;rsquo;s death was being treated as unexplained. They said whether he had inhaled aerosols was one line of inquiry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The worlds largest robots are setting sail</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/d2309930-dcc5-11ee-9a0c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/d2309930-dcc5-11ee-9a0c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The world&amp;rsquo;s largest robots are setting sail Ocean Infinity is building a fleet of 23 vessels that will survey the seabed for offshore wind farm operators and check underwater infrastructure for the oil and gas industry. The new vessel, the Armada, has cameras, microphones, radars, GPS and all manner of satellite communications. But for a ship that&amp;rsquo;s 78m in length there are only 16 people on board. A traditional ship carrying out the same kind of work would need a crew of 40 or 50.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concern as the gambling industry embraces AI</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/712d3382-daae-11ee-9a38-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:06:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/712d3382-daae-11ee-9a38-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Concern as the gambling industry embraces AI Danny Cheetham started visiting local bookies aged 18, gambling on the Fixed Odds Betting Terminals (FOBTs) It wasn&amp;rsquo;t long before he transitioned to online games. The ease of access and the solitary nature of online gambling exacerbated his habits, he says. The ethical dilemma here is whether the pursuit of profit is being prioritised. EquinEdge uses AI to analyse data such as horse performance, track conditions, and jockey and trainer statistics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Download now</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/72549814-dcc9-11ee-a2b8-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 10:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/72549814-dcc9-11ee-a2b8-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Download now With the latest news and analysis from our journalists around the world and the unique human stories behind current events, we&amp;rsquo;ve got the best of our journalism in one place on the BBC News app. Depending on the contract you have, data charges may apply for accessing the internet on your mobile device. The BBC does not charge you to access mobile content. You may find some costs are included in your existing price plan or that you can opt for a data package that gives reduced charges for accessing the internet.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
