<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 10:44:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>EU opens investigations into Apple, Meta and Google</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/31f81764-ea98-11ee-ad5a-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 10:44:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/31f81764-ea98-11ee-ad5a-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>EU opens investigations into Apple, Meta and Google Alphabet, which owns Google, Meta, and Apple are all being looked into for potential breaches of the Digital Markets Act (DMA) If they are found to have broken the rules, the firms can face huge fines of up to 10% of their annual turnover. The investigation will take around 12 months to complete. We will now investigate the companies&amp;rsquo; compliance with the DMA, to ensure open and contestable digital markets in Europe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyber-attack on voter data to be linked to China</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/44d44742-ea9b-11ee-911e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 10:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/44d44742-ea9b-11ee-911e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Cyber-attack on voter data to be linked to China The attacks on the Electoral Commission took place in August 2021 but were only revealed last year. Several MPs and peers who have been critical of Beijing are thought to have also been targeted in cyber-attacks. Deputy Prime Minister Oliver Dowden will address Parliament on Monday about the threat. It is now thought that Mr Dowden will suggest those behind the attack had links to Beijing, as well as laying out how the UK will respond to what it deems a wider threat.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dragon Ball theme park to be built in Saudi Arabia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/495b2a5a-ea9c-11ee-b1ea-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 03:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/495b2a5a-ea9c-11ee-b1ea-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Dragon Ball theme park to be built in Saudi Arabia The theme park will feature a 70m (229. 6ft) dragon at its centre. It will be the world&amp;rsquo;s first theme park based on the popular Japanese series. The announcement has been met with criticism for its human rights record.&#xA;It comes just weeks after the death of the show&amp;rsquo;s creator, Akira Toriyama. The Dragon Ball comic series debuted in 1984. It follows a boy named Son Goku in his quest to collect magical dragon balls.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nationwide payments back to normal after delays</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/acfe1486-e87c-11ee-953f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 16:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/acfe1486-e87c-11ee-953f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Nationwide payments back to normal after delays Customers of UK;s biggest building society reported a range of problems, including transferring money and buying a train ticket. Nationwide says the IT issue has now been resolved but payment backlogs took a few hours to clear. Firm is currently trying to buy Virgin Money in a £2. 9bn deal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Murdoch must have known of phone hacking, court hears</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/aec662ee-e6f3-11ee-96f7-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 18:16:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/aec662ee-e6f3-11ee-96f7-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Murdoch must have known of phone hacking, court hears Lawyers for Prince Harry told a hearing his damages claim next year will seek to link News Group Newspapers (NGN) executives to knowledge of hacking and other unlawful activity. News of the World tabloid was closed down in 2011 over hacking claims and its former editor Andy Coulson was later jailed. Prince Harry&amp;rsquo;s claim of unlawful intrusion by private investigators working for newspapers is likely to continue to trial next January.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ex-takeaway worker guilty after being found with £2bn in Bitcoin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b7cae620-e6f4-11ee-ade8-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 17:50:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b7cae620-e6f4-11ee-ade8-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Ex-takeaway worker guilty after being found with £2bn in Bitcoin Jian Wen, 42, from north London, was involved in converting the currency into assets including multi-million-pound houses and jewellery. She posed as an employee of an international jewellery company. The value of the Bitcoin was worth around £2bn at the time of initial estimates.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kate hospital says any privacy breach would be investigated</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6b031f66-e6f3-11ee-926f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 16:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6b031f66-e6f3-11ee-926f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Kate hospital says any privacy breach would be investigated The hospital where Catherine, Princess of Wales, underwent abdominal surgery has said any breach of patient information would be investigated. The hospital has said #34;any breach#34;&amp;quot; of patient info would be investigation. The princess had abdominal surgery at St Mary&amp;rsquo;s Hospital in London. London Clinic says it has &amp;rsquo;no place&amp;rsquo; for those intentionally breaching trust.&#xA;It follows reports a staff member tried to access her medical information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GB News shows hosted by MPs broke Ofcom rules</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/411874be-e52a-11ee-8528-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 11:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/411874be-e52a-11ee-8528-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>GB News shows hosted by MPs broke Ofcom rules Ofcom said shows hosted by Sir Jacob Rees-Mogg, Esther McVey and Philip Davies broke rules stating politicians should not usually front news coverage. The regulator said repeated contraventions of the relevant part of its code could lead to a sanction, which could include a fine or - in the most serious cases - revoking a broadcasting licence. Sir Jacob hosts State of the Nation every Monday to Thursday evening.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Star Wars&#39; Millennium Falcon features on new 50p</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ca4a46d6-e52f-11ee-acff-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 08:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ca4a46d6-e52f-11ee-acff-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Star Wars&amp;rsquo; Millennium Falcon features on new 50p The coin depicts a silhouette of the fictional starship and the Rebel Alliance Starbird symbol. It is one of a series of coins dedicated to the vehicles featured in the Star Wars films. Other coins launching in 2024 will feature the TIE Fighter, X-Wing and Death Star II.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The WhatsApp group that saved trafficked women</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/cbb90e4a-e52e-11ee-87b2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/cbb90e4a-e52e-11ee-87b2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The WhatsApp group that saved trafficked women BBC Africa Eye investigates how a WhatsApp group helped save more than 50 Malawian women trafficked to Oman to work in slave-like conditions. WARNING: Some people may find details in this story distressing. A 32-year-old woman breaks down in tears as she relives the abuse she experienced when she found herself working as a maid in Oman. Malawi woman says she was forced to have anal sex by her boss.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sainsbury&#39;s deliveries cancelled due to tech issues</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/cee95646-e395-11ee-8328-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 12:30:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/cee95646-e395-11ee-8328-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Sainsbury&amp;rsquo;s deliveries cancelled due to tech issues Sainsbury&amp;rsquo;s says it will not be able to fulfil the vast majority of online deliveries on Saturday. Customers have been contacting the supermarket on social media to report issues with their online orders. Sainsbury#39;s apologised, explaining it was caused by an overnight software update. It said customers can now place new orders to be delivered tomorrow.&#xA;BBC News visited three Sainsbury#39;s Local stores in central London.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workaholics Anonymous: &#39;I couldn&#39;t step away from the computer&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/8a8f4504-e39b-11ee-b980-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 03:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/8a8f4504-e39b-11ee-b980-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Workaholics Anonymous: &amp;lsquo;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t step away from the computer&amp;rsquo; Playwright James Graham turned to Workaholics Anonymous for help after realising work addiction had become a problem for him. He joined a support group session to hear how it has affected other people#39;s lives. One woman describes how she had spent the evening struggling against the urge to meet a self-imposed deadline after putting her son to bed. Workaholics Anonymous brings together people from across the UK.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I was cyberbullied while pregnant, says Meghan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ae0fa058-de7a-11ee-a3c7-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 04:37:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ae0fa058-de7a-11ee-a3c7-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>I was cyberbullied while pregnant, says Meghan Meghan was the keynote speaker on a panel marking International Women&amp;rsquo;s Day at the annual SXSW festival in Austin, Texas. She said she now keeps her distance from such comments for her wellbeing. Prince Harry was in the front row of the audience watching the event. The 42-year-old former Suits actress also discussed issues ranging from the importance of diverse representation to portrayals of motherhood in film and entertainment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boy, 11, died trying social media craze - family</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/9b0754e2-dcc7-11ee-8c61-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 16:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/9b0754e2-dcc7-11ee-8c61-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Boy, 11, died trying social media craze - family Tommie-lee Gracie Billington died at a house in Lancaster on Saturday. His grandmother Tina Burns said he had been at a sleepover. She said he was taking part in a social media craze that involves sniffing or inhaling toxic fumes. The 11-year-old&amp;rsquo;s family say they are devastated by his death.&#xA;Police said the boy&amp;rsquo;s death was being treated as unexplained. They said whether he had inhaled aerosols was one line of inquiry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The worlds largest robots are setting sail</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/d2309930-dcc5-11ee-9a0c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/d2309930-dcc5-11ee-9a0c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The world&amp;rsquo;s largest robots are setting sail Ocean Infinity is building a fleet of 23 vessels that will survey the seabed for offshore wind farm operators and check underwater infrastructure for the oil and gas industry. The new vessel, the Armada, has cameras, microphones, radars, GPS and all manner of satellite communications. But for a ship that&amp;rsquo;s 78m in length there are only 16 people on board. A traditional ship carrying out the same kind of work would need a crew of 40 or 50.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concern as the gambling industry embraces AI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/712d3382-daae-11ee-9a38-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:06:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/712d3382-daae-11ee-9a38-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Concern as the gambling industry embraces AI Danny Cheetham started visiting local bookies aged 18, gambling on the Fixed Odds Betting Terminals (FOBTs) It wasn&amp;rsquo;t long before he transitioned to online games. The ease of access and the solitary nature of online gambling exacerbated his habits, he says. The ethical dilemma here is whether the pursuit of profit is being prioritised. EquinEdge uses AI to analyse data such as horse performance, track conditions, and jockey and trainer statistics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Download now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/071bbe7a-dd90-11ee-9e93-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 10:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/071bbe7a-dd90-11ee-9e93-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Download now With the latest news and analysis from our journalists around the world and the unique human stories behind current events, we&amp;rsquo;ve got the best of our journalism in one place on the BBC News app. Depending on the contract you have, data charges may apply for accessing the internet on your mobile device. The BBC does not charge you to access mobile content. You may find some costs are included in your existing price plan or that you can opt for a data package that gives reduced charges for accessing the internet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Download now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2e669eba-deed-11ee-be1c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 10:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2e669eba-deed-11ee-be1c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Download now With the latest news and analysis from our journalists around the world and the unique human stories behind current events, we&amp;rsquo;ve got the best of our journalism in one place on the BBC News app. Depending on the contract you have, data charges may apply for accessing the internet on your mobile device. The BBC does not charge you to access mobile content. You may find some costs are included in your existing price plan or that you can opt for a data package that gives reduced charges for accessing the internet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Download now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/64aa8604-e2d4-11ee-858e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 10:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/64aa8604-e2d4-11ee-858e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Download now With the latest news and analysis from our journalists around the world and the unique human stories behind current events, we#39;ve got the best of our journalism in one place on the BBC News app. Depending on the contract you have, data charges may apply for accessing the internet on your mobile device. The BBC does not charge you to access mobile content. You may find some costs are included in your existing price plan or that you can opt for a data package that gives reduced charges for accessing the internet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Download now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/72549814-dcc9-11ee-a2b8-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 10:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/72549814-dcc9-11ee-a2b8-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Download now With the latest news and analysis from our journalists around the world and the unique human stories behind current events, we&amp;rsquo;ve got the best of our journalism in one place on the BBC News app. Depending on the contract you have, data charges may apply for accessing the internet on your mobile device. The BBC does not charge you to access mobile content. You may find some costs are included in your existing price plan or that you can opt for a data package that gives reduced charges for accessing the internet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Download now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/7e15482a-de7b-11ee-8b86-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 10:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/7e15482a-de7b-11ee-8b86-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Download now With the latest news and analysis from our journalists around the world and the unique human stories behind current events, we&amp;rsquo;ve got the best of our journalism in one place on the BBC News app. Depending on the contract you have, data charges may apply for accessing the internet on your mobile device. The BBC does not charge you to access mobile content. You may find some costs are included in your existing price plan or that you can opt for a data package that gives reduced charges for accessing the internet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Download now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/8fd9143c-e9e4-11ee-b002-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 10:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/8fd9143c-e9e4-11ee-b002-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Download now With the latest news and analysis from our journalists around the world and the unique human stories behind current events, we&amp;rsquo;ve got the best of our journalism in one place on the BBC News app. Depending on the contract you have, data charges may apply for accessing the internet on your mobile device. The BBC does not charge you to access mobile content. You may find some costs are included in your existing price plan or that you can opt for a data package that gives reduced charges for accessing the internet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Download now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a2afbc64-e07f-11ee-917b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 10:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a2afbc64-e07f-11ee-917b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Download now With the latest news and analysis from our journalists around the world and the unique human stories behind current events, we&amp;rsquo;ve got the best of our journalism in one place on the BBC News app. Depending on the contract you have, data charges may apply for accessing the internet on your mobile device. The BBC does not charge you to access mobile content. You may find some costs are included in your existing price plan or that you can opt for a data package that gives reduced charges for accessing the internet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Download now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/cc9aee16-eaa4-11ee-81eb-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 10:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/cc9aee16-eaa4-11ee-81eb-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Download now With the latest news and analysis from our journalists around the world and the unique human stories behind current events, we&amp;rsquo;ve got the best of our journalism in one place on the BBC News app. Depending on the contract you have, data charges may apply for accessing the internet on your mobile device. The BBC does not charge you to access mobile content. You may find some costs are included in your existing price plan or that you can opt for a data package that gives reduced charges for accessing the internet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Download now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/d1d94944-e532-11ee-a4dd-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 10:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/d1d94944-e532-11ee-a4dd-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Download now With the latest news and analysis from our journalists around the world and the unique human stories behind current events, we#39;ve got the best of our journalism in one place on the BBC News app. Depending on the contract you have, data charges may apply for accessing the internet on your mobile device. The BBC does not charge you to access mobile content. You may find some costs are included in your existing price plan or that you can opt for a data package that gives reduced charges for accessing the internet.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
