<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on Five Minunte Reads</title>
    <link>https://fiveminread.com/categories/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Five Minunte Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 18:23:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://fiveminread.com/categories/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dharshini David: An election giveaway but taxes will still rise</title>
      <link>https://fiveminread.com/post/6df9ba2a-dbec-11ee-bcc8-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 18:23:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminread.com/post/6df9ba2a-dbec-11ee-bcc8-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Dharshini David: An election giveaway but taxes will still rise Chancellor Jeremy Hunt was on his feet for one hour and five minutes. His Budget contained a relatively modest amount of treats. Many are still going to see their tax bills rise. But £11bn will be going on that National Insurance cut - a tax giveaway that will be a relief to workers.&#xA;Almost half will come from changing the treatment of &amp;ldquo;non-doms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Election poll tracker: How do the parties compare?</title>
      <link>https://fiveminread.com/post/a18cb32a-dbf5-11ee-a984-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 13:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminread.com/post/a18cb32a-dbf5-11ee-a984-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Election poll tracker: How do the parties compare? Conservative MPs will be hoping that the tax cuts announced in the Budget will please voters. Chancellor Jeremy Hunt cut the main rate of National Insurance for employees from 12% to 10%. Now he&amp;rsquo;s gone further with an additional cut to 8% and he also cut the rate for self-employed people. The latest poll by Ipsos MORI has the Tories down to 20 per cent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top court says states cant ban Trump from ballots</title>
      <link>https://fiveminread.com/post/c981f4fa-daa9-11ee-9f6f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 19:46:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminread.com/post/c981f4fa-daa9-11ee-9f6f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Top court says states can&amp;rsquo;t ban Trump from ballots Colorado had barred Mr Trump from its Republican primary, arguing he incited the 2021 Capitol riot. The court ruled that only Congress, rather than the states, has that power. Mr Trump is the front-runner for the Republican nomination and looks likely to face a rematch with Democratic President Joe Biden in November. Mr Trump said the decision was &amp;lsquo;very well crafted&amp;rsquo; and will bring the country together.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
