<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sports on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/sports/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sports on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 23:45:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/sports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>US Open champion Clark leads Players as McIlroy toils</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2a140628-e3ab-11ee-97d3-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 23:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2a140628-e3ab-11ee-97d3-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>US Open champion Clark leads Players as McIlroy toils Wyndham Clark four shots clear at halfway point of Players Championship. US Open champion carded a second seven-under-par 65. Xander Schauffele and Nick Taylor are on 10 under, with Matt Fitzpatrick and Maverick McNealy a stroke further back. Rory McIlroy slipped back to six under with a 73.&#xA;Scheffler posts five birdies in his 69 despite playing most of the round in discomfort.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emma Barnett to join Radio 4&#39;s Today programme</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b646f208-e2d0-11ee-9a20-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 11:41:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b646f208-e2d0-11ee-9a20-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Emma Barnett to join Radio 4&amp;rsquo;s Today programme Barnett will replace Martha Kearney, who announced she would leave in April. She will also front documentaries and set piece interviews for the BBC as part of her new role. Barnett said she was delighted to be joining a programme that occupies such a unique space in British life. Barnett will join Amol Rajan, Mishal Husain, Justin Webb and Nick Robinson as one of Today#39;s main presenters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freeman &#39;furious&#39; at last-minute delay to hospital</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/58be216e-e083-11ee-9b68-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 12:01:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/58be216e-e083-11ee-9b68-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Freeman &amp;lsquo;furious&amp;rsquo; at last-minute delay to hospital NHS Lothian had suggested a phased opening while the problem was fixed. But Ms Freeman ruled this was unsafe. She was furious to learn about ventilation problems with the Sick Kids in Edinburgh just days before it was due to open in 2019. The former SNP cabinet secretary used her witness statement to the inquiry to criticise NHS Lothians.&#xA;Ms Freeman said news of the problems was a &amp;ldquo;big bolt from the blue.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raducanu loses to Sabalenka at Indian Wells</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6fa3662a-e086-11ee-819d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 07:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6fa3662a-e086-11ee-819d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Raducanu loses to Sabalenka at Indian Wells Britain&amp;rsquo;s Emma Raducanu beaten 6-3 7-5 by Aryna Sabalenka. The 21-year-old was a wildcard at the tournament following an injury-disrupted 2023. Raducanu reached the fourth round in California last year. Raducanu beat Dayana Yastremska in straight sets.&#xA;It was the first time the English player had recorded back-to-back wins since successfully coming through three in a row at Indian Wells 12 months ago. Raducanu made her return to the tour in January following an eight-month absence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Djokovic knocked out by lucky loser at Indian Wells</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6294431a-e085-11ee-a73f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 07:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6294431a-e085-11ee-a73f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Djokovic knocked out by lucky loser at Indian Wells World number one Novak Djokovic beaten by Luca Nardi at Indian Wells. Italian Nardi, ranked 123 in the world, had originally been knocked out in qualifying but reached the main draw after another player&amp;rsquo;s withdrawal. He hit 34 winners in a 6-4 3-6 6-3 win over the 24-time Grand Slam champion, converting match point with an ace. Nardi was beaten by Belgium&amp;rsquo;s David Goffin in the final round of qualifying.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women race Cresta Run event for first time in 103 years</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/0e5318e0-deea-11ee-9647-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 06:06:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/0e5318e0-deea-11ee-9647-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Women race Cresta Run event for first time in 103 years Cresta Run is one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular skiing events. It is held every year on the banks of the River Elbe. The event has been banned since the 1970s due to health and safety concerns. It has now been allowed to resume after a 10-year ban.&#xA;Alcott was riding the Cresta to highlight the first women&amp;rsquo;s race since 1921.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raducanu moves on to round three at Indian Wells</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/44a0dfc2-de77-11ee-992d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 22:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/44a0dfc2-de77-11ee-992d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Raducanu moves on to round three at Indian Wells Raducanu raced into a 4-0 lead in just 18 minutes during the first set. Yastremska stepped to the back of the court between games, holding her stomach and then retiring from the contest. Raducanu will face Peyton Stearns or Aryna Sabalenka in round three. Cameron Norrie beats Lorenzo Sonego to reach round three.&#xA;Wild card Raducanu broke Yastremska&amp;rsquo;s serve in the opening game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raducanu moves on to round three at Indian Wells</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/aedf9508-de7d-11ee-8ae3-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 22:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/aedf9508-de7d-11ee-8ae3-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Raducanu moves on to round three at Indian Wells Raducanu raced into a 4-0 lead in just 18 minutes during the first set. Yastremska stepped to the back of the court between games, holding her stomach and then retiring from the contest. Raducanu will face Peyton Stearns or Aryna Sabalenka in round three. Cameron Norrie beats Lorenzo Sonego to reach round three.&#xA;Wild card Raducanu broke Yastremska&amp;rsquo;s serve in the opening game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keegan: &#39;I&#39;d have probably punched Ofsted staff&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a4a7dcc0-dd89-11ee-9904-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 17:44:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a4a7dcc0-dd89-11ee-9904-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Keegan: &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;d have probably punched Ofsted staff&amp;rsquo; Gillian Keegan told the Association of School and College Leaders (ASCL) that inspectors had been ‘really rude’ Union boss said the remarks made light of violence in schools. Ofsted chief inspector Sir Martyn Oliver said inspectors and school staff alike should act with professionalism, courtesy and respect. Sir Martyn said it was “early days” since starting his role in January. He referred to the suicide of head teacher Ruth Perry as a tragedy that should “never happen again” Mrs Perry took her own life while waiting for an Ofsted report and the inquest ruled the inspection had contributed to her death.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rangers fan dies in Lisbon after Europa League match</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2aecd540-dd91-11ee-96fb-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 15:42:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2aecd540-dd91-11ee-96fb-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Rangers fan dies in Lisbon after Europa League match Thomas McAllister, 25, from Glasgow, had travelled to Portugal for Thursday&amp;rsquo;s round of 16 game, which ended 2-2. Rangers chief executive James Bisgrove said: &amp;ldquo;On behalf of the club, I want to pass on my sincere condolences to Thomas&amp;rsquo; loved ones, family and his friends. The club stands ready to assist Thomas&amp;rsquo; family in whichever way we can in the coming days and weeks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18-year-old becomes youngest British F1 driver in history</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2e991366-dd87-11ee-a26f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 15:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2e991366-dd87-11ee-a26f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>18-year-old becomes youngest British F1 driver in history The 18-year-old from Chelmsford will be the youngest British driver to start an F1 race and third youngest debutant behind Max Verstappen (17) and Lance Stroll (18) However, Bearman is being thrown in at the deep end at this weekend&amp;rsquo;s Saudi Arabian Grand Prix. British teenager Bearman replaces Sainz for Saudi GP. A member of the Ferrari driver academy since 2021, he drove in two practice sessions for the Haas team last year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YouTuber Paul to fight ex-champion Tyson</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/da990408-dcc1-11ee-8062-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 16:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/da990408-dcc1-11ee-8062-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>YouTuber Paul to fight ex-champion Tyson It is unclear if it will be an official fight or an exhibition bout. It will be staged in Texas and broadcast live on streaming platform Netflix. Paul, 27, beat Ryan Bourland in his 10th professional fight last Saturday. Tyson&amp;rsquo;s professional career ended in 2005 and he will turn 58 three weeks before facing Paul.&#xA;Tyson was the first heavyweight boxer to simultaneously hold the WBA, WBC and IBF titles in 1987.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
