<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Africa on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/africa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Africa on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:20:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/africa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The WhatsApp group that saved trafficked women</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/cbb90e4a-e52e-11ee-87b2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/cbb90e4a-e52e-11ee-87b2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The WhatsApp group that saved trafficked women BBC Africa Eye investigates how a WhatsApp group helped save more than 50 Malawian women trafficked to Oman to work in slave-like conditions. WARNING: Some people may find details in this story distressing. A 32-year-old woman breaks down in tears as she relives the abuse she experienced when she found herself working as a maid in Oman. Malawi woman says she was forced to have anal sex by her boss.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Idris Elba &#39;dreams big&#39; with West African eco-city plan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1c268de8-e468-11ee-94af-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 01:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1c268de8-e468-11ee-94af-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Idris Elba &amp;lsquo;dreams big&amp;rsquo; with West African eco-city plan Hollywood actor Idris Elba has a big dream for Sierra Leone. He wants to regenerate a beautiful island off its coast and turn it into an eco-friendly city. The project also intends to bring wind-powered renewable electricity for the first time to the West African nation. Elba was brought into the project by his childhood friend Siaka Stevens, the grandson of a former Sierra Leonean president of the same name.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
