<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Africa on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/africa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Africa on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 17:03:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/africa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>F1 Q&lt;title&gt;A: Your questions answered after Australian GP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/614118d4-ebb2-11ee-8aa1-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 17:03:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/614118d4-ebb2-11ee-8aa1-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>F1 QA: Your questions answered after Australian GP There is no appetite among F1 stakeholders for a tyre war, says Andrew Benson. Carlos Sainz led Charles Leclerc to a Ferrari one-two in Melbourne on Sunday. Lewis Hamilton and Max Verstappen had to retire their cars. George Russell crashed in the final lap of the race.&#xA;The Pirelli tyres supplied to F1 are very thermally sensitive. They typically require gentle treatment to prevent them overheating.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Africa&#39;s deadly love affair with guns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b20ae44c-e938-11ee-89d2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b20ae44c-e938-11ee-89d2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>South Africa&amp;rsquo;s deadly love affair with guns Penson Menson has been carrying a gun wherever he goes in South Africa. He says he has had to use his gun multiple times to protect himself. Menson: &amp;ldquo;I never know when I will be attacked by someone who wants to kill me&amp;rdquo; He says the police and government have failed to do enough to protect the public. South African law states that most people with a gun licence can carry a firearm if it is concealed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ex-boss of Poundland owner dies from gunshot wound</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/3f3d3d5a-e87c-11ee-90cf-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 15:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/3f3d3d5a-e87c-11ee-90cf-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Ex-boss of Poundland owner dies from gunshot wound Markus Jooste, the former head of the Steinhoff retail group, has died. The 63-year-old succumbed to a gunshot wound in hospital, police said. Local media reported he shot himself at his home in the southern town of Hermanus. He was ordered to pay a $25m fine - said to be the biggest in South Africa&amp;rsquo;s history.&#xA;Steinhoff International Holdings is based in South Africa but also listed in Germany.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fresh defeats in the Lords over Rwanda bill</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/e07c6d40-e6f0-11ee-b585-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 19:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/e07c6d40-e6f0-11ee-b585-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Fresh defeats in the Lords over Rwanda bill MPs will now have to vote on the bill again, delaying the passage of the bill until after Easter. The legislation aims to revive the government#39;s plan to send some asylum seekers to Rwanda. It declares the east African country is safe, after deportation flights were stalled by the Supreme Court. Labour&amp;rsquo;s proposals on domestic and international law were passed by 271 to 228 votes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fresh defeat in the Lords over Rwanda bill</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/5585d6f6-e6e4-11ee-945b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 17:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/5585d6f6-e6e4-11ee-945b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Fresh defeat in the Lords over Rwanda bill The bill must now return to the Commons to be passed. It aims to stop people making the dangerous journey across the Channel. The Supreme Court ruled the government&amp;rsquo;s plan could lead to human rights breaches. The bill declares the east African country is safe, after deportation flights were stalled.&#xA;The bill must now return to the Commons in a process known as #34;ping pong.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Famine looms in Sudan as civil war survivors tell of killings and rapes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/4aa54120-e6f5-11ee-9d94-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/4aa54120-e6f5-11ee-9d94-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Famine looms in Sudan as civil war survivors tell of killings and rapes Sudan&amp;rsquo;s civil war could trigger the world&amp;rsquo;s largest hunger crisis, say UN officials. Civilians have given graphic accounts of rape, ethnic violence and street executions. There are also fears that a repeat of what the US called genocide 20 years ago may be beginning to unfold. In mid-February, the Sudanese army retook the city - one of three along the River Nile that form Sudan#39;s wider capital, Khartoum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The WhatsApp group that saved trafficked women</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/cbb90e4a-e52e-11ee-87b2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/cbb90e4a-e52e-11ee-87b2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The WhatsApp group that saved trafficked women BBC Africa Eye investigates how a WhatsApp group helped save more than 50 Malawian women trafficked to Oman to work in slave-like conditions. WARNING: Some people may find details in this story distressing. A 32-year-old woman breaks down in tears as she relives the abuse she experienced when she found herself working as a maid in Oman. Malawi woman says she was forced to have anal sex by her boss.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Idris Elba &#39;dreams big&#39; with West African eco-city plan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1c268de8-e468-11ee-94af-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 01:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1c268de8-e468-11ee-94af-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Idris Elba &amp;lsquo;dreams big&amp;rsquo; with West African eco-city plan Hollywood actor Idris Elba has a big dream for Sierra Leone. He wants to regenerate a beautiful island off its coast and turn it into an eco-friendly city. The project also intends to bring wind-powered renewable electricity for the first time to the West African nation. Elba was brought into the project by his childhood friend Siaka Stevens, the grandson of a former Sierra Leonean president of the same name.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
