<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Us on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/us/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Us on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 15:31:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/us/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Campaigning dad of Damilola Taylor dies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a9168f8e-e92f-11ee-9bbe-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 15:31:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a9168f8e-e92f-11ee-9bbe-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Campaigning dad of Damilola Taylor dies The former Nigerian civil servant dedicated years to improving the lives of disadvantaged children in the wake of his son&amp;rsquo;s death. He set up the Damilola Taylor Trust to campaign against knife crime. Mr Taylor died on Saturday aged 75 with prostate cancer. He was 10 when he was stabbed in the leg and left to die in a south London stairwell in 2000.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Outpouring of support for Kate after cancer news</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/7cbeb2ee-e93a-11ee-8e3c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 14:43:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/7cbeb2ee-e93a-11ee-8e3c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Outpouring of support for Kate after cancer news Princess of Wales reveals she is being treated for cancer. She has been receiving chemotherapy since late February. Cancer charities have praised her openness, while world leaders, friends and celebrities have wished her well. The news has also led to calls for her and her family to be given privacy.&#xA;Catherine said she and Prince William had taken time to sensitively share the state of her health with their children.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harry and Meghan reach out to Kate after cancer news</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/9da0ab50-e92d-11ee-91e4-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 13:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/9da0ab50-e92d-11ee-91e4-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Harry and Meghan reach out to Kate after cancer news The Duke and Duchess of Sussex have reached out to the Prince and Princess of Wales, the BBC understands. The contact is understood to have been made privately. Prince Harry and Meghan said they wished health and healing for Catherine. The princess is confident that she will make a full recovery.&#xA;Catherine had abdominal surgery in January, but it was not known then there was any cancer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Briton becomes first woman to finish one of world&#39;s toughest races</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2be828e8-e92e-11ee-a363-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 11:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2be828e8-e92e-11ee-a363-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Briton becomes first woman to finish one of world&amp;rsquo;s toughest races Jasmin Paris from Midlothian completed the Barkley Marathons in Tennessee with just one minute 39 seconds to spare of the 60-hour cut off. The course, at Frozen Head State Park, changes every year but covers 100 miles involving 60,000ft of climb and descent. Only 20 people have ever made it to the end of the race within the allotted 60 hours since it was extended to 100 miles in 1989.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Verstappen takes Australia pole with Hamilton 11th</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/446d8a70-e942-11ee-af62-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 08:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/446d8a70-e942-11ee-af62-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Verstappen takes Australia pole with Hamilton 11th Red Bull&amp;rsquo;s Max Verstappen fights off a challenge from Ferrari driver Carlos Sainz to take pole position for the Australian Grand Prix. Red Bull#39;s Max VerStappen fought off a challenges from Ferrari&amp;rsquo;s Carlos Sianz to claim pole position. Sainz was quickest in the first two parts of qualifying but the world champion bounced back in the top 10 shootout. Lando Norris will start third ahead of Ferrari#39;s Charles Leclerc after a grid penalty for Red Bull&amp;rsquo;s Sergio Perez.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>London landmarks join Earth Hour lights switch-off</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6626ea82-e93b-11ee-847b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 07:36:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6626ea82-e93b-11ee-847b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>London landmarks join Earth Hour lights switch-off The annual Earth Hour, spearheaded by the World Wide Fund for Nature (WWF), is observed around the world. Previous years have seen Big Ben, the Eiffel Tower, and the Sydney Opera House turn out the lights. WWF suggests individuals use the 60 minutes, between 20:30 and 21:30, to do something positive for the planet. Lit-up landmarks that will go dark for the hour include the Barbican Arts Centre, the Old Bailey, Tower Bridge, and the OXO Tower.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From the desert to the icy waters of Wales</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/d316da58-e931-11ee-b362-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 07:11:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/d316da58-e931-11ee-b362-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>From the desert to the icy waters of Wales Amr Madbouly is a decarbonisation engineer at the Tata steelworks in Port Talbot. He has become an enthusiastic promoter of Welsh nature on social media. The average air temperature in Cairo, like the average water temperature, doesn#39;t fall much below 20C. Amr, 34, from Bridgend, loves to go and plunge into a river or waterfall.&#xA;He was inspired to move to Wales by a desire to live close to its mountains and waterfalls.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My father&#39;s diary left me wondering whether he was a killer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/3b9bd72a-e939-11ee-8202-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 06:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/3b9bd72a-e939-11ee-8202-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>My father&amp;rsquo;s diary left me wondering whether he was a killer Saul Wordsworth&amp;rsquo;s father Christopher may have taken a terrible secret to his grave. He knew all about his quick temper and explosive outbursts of rage. But a set of his diaries inherited by Saul hinted at something altogether darker. The passage she highlighted referred to hiding a body until a search party had gone.&#xA;Growing up in Harpenden, Hertfordshire, Saul knew his father as a teller of tall tales.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Oasis&#39; first tour venues, 30 years on</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/5549aa36-e938-11ee-9fbf-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 02:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/5549aa36-e938-11ee-9fbf-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Revisiting Oasis&amp;rsquo; first tour venues, 30 years on Exactly 30 years ago, a little-known band called Oasis set out on their first headline tour. Mark Davyd was asked to book a gig by a rising Scottish band called Whiteout at his venue in Kent in March 1994. He wasn#39;t keen when he found out that an unfamiliar Mancunian group would also be on the bill. He wanted to put on a local support act instead - but the agent stressed it was a joint headlined tour.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Nazi hunter and the lost IRA documentary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a006552c-e93f-11ee-9ba0-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 02:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a006552c-e93f-11ee-9ba0-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The Nazi hunter and the lost IRA documentary The film was made in 1972 when the IRA was at its lowest ebb. It shows the group planning and carrying out attacks.&#xA;Former IRA members who took part in the film said they were unaware of Aldouby#39;s intelligence connections. Also among those filmed handling guns and bombs was Martin McGuinness, then a rising young IRA leader.&#xA;As a Sinn Féin politician he became the deputy first minister of Northern Ireland.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Nazi hunter and the lost IRA documentary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/e0534710-e936-11ee-a294-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 02:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/e0534710-e936-11ee-a294-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The Nazi hunter and the lost IRA documentary Zwy Aldouby filmed the majority of the IRA secret leadership between March and June 1972. The film has not been seen by the public for almost 50 years. It is the subject of a new BBC documentary called #34;The Secret Army. The documentary will be on BBC iPlayer on 27 March.&#xA;Former IRA members who took part in the film said they were unaware of Aldouby intelligence connections.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High rural house prices force locals into renting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/11d25c6e-e93b-11ee-8002-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 02:35:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/11d25c6e-e93b-11ee-8002-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>High rural house prices force locals into renting A 19% increase in rural renting has outpaced rises in London and other cities. House prices in rural counties are the most unaffordable outside London at an average of £309,000. In the Cotswolds, locals like Sophie Brown are finding they have been priced out of the property market. Gloucestershire Rural Community Council (GRCC) has been dealing with the problem.&#xA;Holiday lettings and second-home buying had seen many landlords take properties out of the longer-term private rental sector.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moscow concert hall attack videos examined</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f0260ed2-e933-11ee-960b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f0260ed2-e933-11ee-960b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Moscow concert hall attack videos examined CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;We don&#39;t live, we&#39;re just alive&#39;: Afghan girls despair at Taliban school ban</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/86f73c5c-e93c-11ee-92d0-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/86f73c5c-e93c-11ee-92d0-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;We don&amp;rsquo;t live, we&amp;rsquo;re just alive&amp;rsquo;: Afghan girls despair at Taliban school ban More than 900 days have now passed since girls over 12 were first banned. Taliban have repeatedly promised they would be readmitted once a number of issues were resolved. But they have made little comment as a third new school year started this week. The BBC has asked the Taliban#39;s education minister for an explanation, but he has so far not responded.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First J-Pop, then K-Pop - could I-Pop be next?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/38ce4002-e937-11ee-b0d3-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/38ce4002-e937-11ee-b0d3-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>First J-Pop, then K-Pop - could I-Pop be next? Ri, Zo, Sim, and Suchi are said to be India;s first mainstream girl group in more than 20 years. W.i.S.H. is an acronym of World inka Stage Hai, or the world is their stage. W.i.S.H. want to change that and get to the top by spreading a positive message of sisterhood and female empowerment. She describes their debut single, Lazeez, as a song that #34;celebrates the modern woman and encourages self-love.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Africa&#39;s deadly love affair with guns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b20ae44c-e938-11ee-89d2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b20ae44c-e938-11ee-89d2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>South Africa&amp;rsquo;s deadly love affair with guns Penson Menson has been carrying a gun wherever he goes in South Africa. He says he has had to use his gun multiple times to protect himself. Menson: &amp;ldquo;I never know when I will be attacked by someone who wants to kill me&amp;rdquo; He says the police and government have failed to do enough to protect the public. South African law states that most people with a gun licence can carry a firearm if it is concealed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man killed in Kilkeel house named locally</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2e085288-e884-11ee-993d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 16:37:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2e085288-e884-11ee-993d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Man killed in Kilkeel house named locally Bobbie McKee, 69, was found dead in a house in Kilkeel on Thursday. A woman, also in her 60s, sustained serious head injuries in the incident. A 25-year-old man arrested on suspicion of murder and attempted murder remains in custody. DUP assembly member for South Down Diane Forsythe described a #34;lovely family#34;&amp;quot; at the centre of the incident.&#xA;However, at this time, we are not treating this as a firearms-related report.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FA defends new England kit over flag design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/176deb02-e873-11ee-9c81-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 16:21:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/176deb02-e873-11ee-9c81-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>FA defends new England kit over flag design The FA has defended the St George#39;s Cross design on its new England kit. The body said it understood what the flag #34;means to our fans. It added the fresh 2024 home kit was meant as a tribute to the 1966 World Cup winning team. Prime Minister Rishi Sunak said he preferred the original and the national flag was a source of pride and identity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FA defends new England kit over flag design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/44d98486-e885-11ee-8bab-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 16:21:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/44d98486-e885-11ee-8bab-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>FA defends new England kit over flag design The FA has defended the St George#39;s Cross design on its new England kit. The body said it understood what the flag #34;means to our fans. Nike said its design was to celebrate the 1966 World Cup team. Both the prime minister and Labour leader criticised the design.&#xA;Prime Minister Rishi Sunak said he preferred the original and the national flag was a source of pride and identity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nationwide payments back to normal after delays</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/acfe1486-e87c-11ee-953f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 16:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/acfe1486-e87c-11ee-953f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Nationwide payments back to normal after delays Customers of UK;s biggest building society reported a range of problems, including transferring money and buying a train ticket. Nationwide says the IT issue has now been resolved but payment backlogs took a few hours to clear. Firm is currently trying to buy Virgin Money in a £2. 9bn deal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ex-boss of Poundland owner dies from gunshot wound</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/3f3d3d5a-e87c-11ee-90cf-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 15:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/3f3d3d5a-e87c-11ee-90cf-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Ex-boss of Poundland owner dies from gunshot wound Markus Jooste, the former head of the Steinhoff retail group, has died. The 63-year-old succumbed to a gunshot wound in hospital, police said. Local media reported he shot himself at his home in the southern town of Hermanus. He was ordered to pay a $25m fine - said to be the biggest in South Africa&amp;rsquo;s history.&#xA;Steinhoff International Holdings is based in South Africa but also listed in Germany.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Row erupts over German football kit deal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/dfd6c5c0-e87b-11ee-b8db-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 15:50:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/dfd6c5c0-e87b-11ee-b8db-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Row erupts over German football kit deal The contract will pass from the German company to US firm Nike from 2027. The DFB said the deal made financial sense and would support grassroots German football. However, according to reports in the German press, Nike agreed to pay about €100m (£86m; $108m) per year. The DFB said on X, formerly Twitter, that it understood the emotional reaction to its decision.&#xA;Bavarian premier Markus Soeder said the national team always plays in the three stripes of Adidas.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Funeral held for teenage stabbing victim</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/831731a0-e883-11ee-86e2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 15:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/831731a0-e883-11ee-86e2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Funeral held for teenage stabbing victim Mason Rist, 15, died after being attacked by a number of people on 27 January. His best friend, Max Dixon, also died in the incident. Family and friends gathered at South Bristol Methodist Church on Thursday. Reverend Sally Spencer said the family were being &amp;lsquo;really brave and courageous&amp;rsquo; The service was held in memory of the young man who was killed in a car crash last month.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaysia rejects offer to host Commonwealth Games</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6597a91c-e87d-11ee-bf9c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 15:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6597a91c-e87d-11ee-bf9c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Malaysia rejects offer to host Commonwealth Games The Commonwealth Games Federation (CGF) offered Malaysia £100m as supporting funds after the Australian state of Victoria withdrew as host. But Malaysia;s sports ministry said the offer ;will not cover the overall cost of hosting a large-scale sports event. The economic impact could not be identified in this short timeframe, it added. The confidential process to determine a host is continuing with other interested Commonwealth Games Associations, said a CGF spokesperson.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man who stabbed victim in neck jailed for 28 years</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ff6d56d4-e884-11ee-be04-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 13:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ff6d56d4-e884-11ee-be04-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Man who stabbed victim in neck jailed for 28 years James Smith, 36, of Llanelli, stabbed Ashley Sarsero, 26, in the neck. Smith was handed a life sentence and told he would serve a minimum of 28 years in jail before being eligible for parole. He was jailed at Swansea Crown Court. Steven Morgan, also 36, was sentenced to four-and-a-half years for helping Smith flee the scene.&#xA;The jury in the three-week trial heard Smith and Morgan had been invited into Mr Sarsero#39;s home in the Maestir area of Felinfoel by his mother.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Send &#39;arrogant&#39; Starmer a message, Sunak tells voters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/417be7ac-e876-11ee-bfb7-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 12:59:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/417be7ac-e876-11ee-bfb7-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Send &amp;lsquo;arrogant&amp;rsquo; Starmer a message, Sunak tells voters PM claims Labour leader has no plan for how to run the country. Mr Sunak said voters should look to councils like Birmingham to see what Labour would do if they win power. Many Conservatives are braced for a bad night on 2 May when council elections are being held across England and Wales. Hundreds of job losses, services slashed, streetlights being dimmed or switched off, making the streets less safe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skier in coma after ravine fall in Bulgaria</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/51af3418-e848-11ee-b9ce-ed33906497a8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/51af3418-e848-11ee-b9ce-ed33906497a8/</guid>
      <description>Skier in coma after ravine fall in Bulgaria Olivia Corbiere, from Aston near Sheffield, suffered serious injuries, including a brain bleed and lung damage, in the accident on Sunday. She had to be placed in an induced coma and needed brain surgery. Her injuries included severe head trauma, a broken eye socket and a broken pelvis.&#xA;To date, more than £23,000 has been raised. Mrs Corbiere said she did not know what her long-term prognosis will be.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MacIntyre taunts American hosts with Ryder Cup score</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a2e0ddc6-e886-11ee-866f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 09:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a2e0ddc6-e886-11ee-866f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>MacIntyre taunts American hosts with Ryder Cup score MacIntyre took advantage of a quirk of the tournament that allows players to choose wording for their caddie#39;s bib. The Scot opted for #39:EUR 16. 5-11. 5 USA and posted it on Twitter.&#xA;MacIntyre, 27, was unbeaten with two and a half points at the Marco Simone Country Club as Luke Donald#39;s side won back the Ryder Cup. He did not pair up with English caddie Mike Burrows until a month later.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leclerc tops Australian GP second practice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/4bd845c2-e887-11ee-a6a1-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 08:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/4bd845c2-e887-11ee-a6a1-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Leclerc tops Australian GP second practice Ferrari&amp;rsquo;s Charles Leclerc was 0. 381 seconds faster than Red Bull&amp;rsquo;s Max Verstappen. Carlos Sainz was third, from Lance Stroll and Fernando Alonso of Aston Martin and George Russell of Mercedes. Lewis Hamilton in the second Mercedes was 18th fastest.&#xA;Verstappen ran later than his rivals because of the enforced delay to his programme. He should have had the better of the track conditions when he set his fastest lap.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Couple adopted vulnerable children to abuse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/d87244c8-e87e-11ee-8219-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 06:26:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/d87244c8-e87e-11ee-8219-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Couple adopted vulnerable children to abuse The abuse began with Couple A in Gloucestershire, who specifically asked to adopt an emotionally disturbed child so they could assault them. The couple, eventually jailed in 2018, went on to adopt four siblings, beginning a cycle of sexual abuse that lasted for years. Couple A, who cannot be named for legal reasons, adopted the four young siblings, who had been abused by their birth parents, in the 1990s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Help my brother first&#39;: Gazan girl&#39;s plea as entire family killed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/fe27ec46-e873-11ee-9568-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 06:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/fe27ec46-e873-11ee-9568-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Help my brother first&amp;rsquo;: Gazan girl&amp;rsquo;s plea as entire family killed Alma Jaroor, 12, was buried under the rubble of a five-storey building in downtown Gaza City for over three hours. In video recorded by a Palestinian rescuer, a shout comes from under mounds of smashed concrete. 3 months on, Alma tells the BBC her story, at length and in detail. Tarazan was 18 months old when he was killed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘I want to help people fly – and keep them safe’</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/e6ebbf80-e87d-11ee-847b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/e6ebbf80-e87d-11ee-847b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>‘I want to help people fly – and keep them safe’ Pooja Umashankar has returned from Sri Lanka to study aircraft maintenance engineering at the University of South Wales. For years, airlines and engineering firms have struggled to hire maintenance engineers. There is now a global shortage numbering in the tens of thousands, and aviation is expected to balloon in coming decades. Around 700,000 engineers will have to enter the profession between now and 2040.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do interest rates affect me?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/e7495566-e880-11ee-9cf3-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 12:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/e7495566-e880-11ee-9cf3-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How do interest rates affect me? Interest rates set by the Bank of England affect mortgage, credit card and savings rates for millions of people across the UK. The base rate, currently 5. 25%, is what it charges other lenders to borrow money. It has a target to keep UK inflation at 2%.&#xA;The Bank may decide to raise rates to encourage people to spend less. The idea is that this helps to bring inflation down by dampening demand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All you need to know about April train strikes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1e009d84-e882-11ee-9d43-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 14:23:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1e009d84-e882-11ee-9d43-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>All you need to know about April train strikes Train drivers at 16 train firms will take part in rolling one-day walk outs between 5 and 8 April. London Underground drivers will strike on Monday 8 April and Saturday 4 May. Aslef members will also refuse to work on rest days from Thursday 4 to Saturday 6 April and from Monday 8 to Tuesday 9 April. Rail passengers with advance tickets can be refunded fee-free if the train they are booked on is cancelled, delayed or rescheduled due to strikes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who gets 15 hours of free childcare and when do I apply?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2a722096-e883-11ee-93c8-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 14:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2a722096-e883-11ee-93c8-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Who gets 15 hours of free childcare and when do I apply? Working parents in England can apply for 15 hours of free weekly childcare for their two-year-olds. The government hopes that extending free childcare to this age group from April 2024 - and to all under-5s in 2025 - will get more parents back to work. Extra help with childcare costs is being rolled out in stages. The help you can get depends on the age of your child, and whether you are working, or receiving certain benefits.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which debts and bills should I pay first?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/9accd360-e881-11ee-94b2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 09:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/9accd360-e881-11ee-94b2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Which debts and bills should I pay first? 11 million adults in the UK struggle to pay their bills in January. This is a rise of 3. 1 million compared with 2022. Citizens Advice says you should work out how much you owe and who to pay.&#xA;There are what are known as priority debts and bills. If you do not pay them, you could lose your home or face court proceedings.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
