<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Us on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/us/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Us on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 18:51:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/us/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Two ministers quit government in mini-reshuffle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/3bc64aa6-eba4-11ee-8112-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 18:51:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/3bc64aa6-eba4-11ee-8112-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Two ministers quit government in mini-reshuffle Robert Halfon and James Heappey have both announced they will not stand at the next election. The resignations are part of a trend of Conservative MPs standing down. Some, like Theresa May and Dominic Raab, are veterans. Others, like Dehenna Davison and Nicola Richards, are relatively young.&#xA;Before the 2010 election, 150 MPs announced they would stand down, mainly from the Labour party. All of them want to do something else with their lives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pupils are injured in crush at school gate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/73e1fe06-ebb0-11ee-a4c4-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 18:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/73e1fe06-ebb0-11ee-a4c4-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Pupils are injured in crush at school gate Gordano School in Portishead, near Bristol, says the gate was not open in time at the end of the school day. Glyn said his son had two black eyes and print marks on parts of his body from other students. The school says it is investigating what happened and will update the community. Glyn said he hoped the school was going to support the pupils.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pupils injured in crush at school gate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6469f202-eba7-11ee-afc5-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 18:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6469f202-eba7-11ee-afc5-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Pupils injured in crush at school gate Gordano School in Portishead, near Bristol, says the gate was not open in time at the end of the school day. Glyn said his son had two black eyes and print marks on parts of his body from other students. The school says it is investigating what happened and will update the community. Glyn said he hoped the school was going to support the pupils.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Church limited Clapham attacker&#39;s attendance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2de41b4c-eba5-11ee-8487-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 18:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2de41b4c-eba5-11ee-8487-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Church limited Clapham attacker&amp;rsquo;s attendance Abdul Shokoor Ezedi, 35, arrived in the UK in 2016 from Afghanistan. He was granted asylum after two applications and an appeal. A key factor was his June 2018 baptism at Grange Road Baptist Church in Jarrow. He won asylum in 2020 after proving his conversion to Christianity.&#xA;The letter was sent to the First Tier Tribunal, which handles asylum applications. It was sent eight months after the case was referred to the tribunal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>North Korea censors Alan Titchmarsh&#39;s trousers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1723422c-eba8-11ee-aa05-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 17:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1723422c-eba8-11ee-aa05-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>North Korea censors Alan Titchmarsh&amp;rsquo;s trousers Central TV aired a 2010 edition of Alan Titchmarsh&amp;rsquo;s Garden Secrets for its morning audience. Jeans are seen as a symbol of western imperialism in the secretive state and as such are banned. Mr Titch marsh said the news has given him &amp;lsquo;a bit of street cred&amp;rsquo; North Korea has banned denim trousers since the 1990s. Leader Kim Jong-il declared denim trousers to be a symbol of Western imperialism.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F1 Q&lt;title&gt;A: Your questions answered after Australian GP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/614118d4-ebb2-11ee-8aa1-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 17:03:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/614118d4-ebb2-11ee-8aa1-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>F1 QA: Your questions answered after Australian GP There is no appetite among F1 stakeholders for a tyre war, says Andrew Benson. Carlos Sainz led Charles Leclerc to a Ferrari one-two in Melbourne on Sunday. Lewis Hamilton and Max Verstappen had to retire their cars. George Russell crashed in the final lap of the race.&#xA;The Pirelli tyres supplied to F1 are very thermally sensitive. They typically require gentle treatment to prevent them overheating.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Springsteen first US musician to land Ivors honour</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/84f37efc-ebad-11ee-ae76-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 17:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/84f37efc-ebad-11ee-ae76-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Springsteen first US musician to land Ivors honour The star will be the first US musician to be given the prize. The prize recognises writing that has enriched the cultural fabric of the UK. Only 24 other people have ever received the fellowship, including Sir Elton John, Sir Paul McCartney and Kate Bush. Last year, the prize went to Sting, who used the opportunity to warn of the dangers that AI posed to songwriters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Care worker migrant surge &#39;should&#39;ve been obvious&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2318f72a-ebad-11ee-8b5a-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 16:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2318f72a-ebad-11ee-8b5a-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Care worker migrant surge &amp;lsquo;should&amp;rsquo;ve been obvious&amp;rsquo; The Home Office has a limited understanding of the social care system. It &amp;ldquo;should have been obvious that lots of migrants would arrive for jobs in care, the former borders watchdog has said. The Home Office says it has a ‘limited understanding’ of social care. David Neal says the immigration system has invited large numbers of low-skilled care workers into the UK.&#xA;His findings are in a report published after he was sacked.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assange judges seek no death penalty pledge from US</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/d41bbf10-eba5-11ee-bafb-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 16:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/d41bbf10-eba5-11ee-bafb-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Assange judges seek no death penalty pledge from US US authorities say Mr Assange endangered lives by publishing thousands of classified documents. His lawyers have argued that the case is a form of &amp;ldquo;state retaliation. The court adjourned its final decision on Mr Assange&amp;rsquo;s extradition by three weeks to give the US government time to comply with its order. Wikileaks published confidential US documents in 2010 and 2011.&#xA;Mr Assange was widely condemned for failing to redact the names of intelligence operatives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baltimore bridge collapses after being hit by ship</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/bb14199c-eba8-11ee-ba9f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 15:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/bb14199c-eba8-11ee-ba9f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Baltimore bridge collapses after being hit by ship Six people are unaccounted for and a number of vehicles were detected in the water. The Singapore-flagged container ship, Dali, struck a support column on the 47-year-old bridge at 01:30 local time (05:30 GMT) Authorities said they were part of a construction crew repairing potholes at the time. A US federal government agency said the vessel &amp;ldquo;lost propulsion as it was leaving the port.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK approach to China is &#39;robust&#39;, Sunak says</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/c2f7f2e6-ebad-11ee-bd07-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 15:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/c2f7f2e6-ebad-11ee-bd07-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>UK approach to China is &amp;lsquo;robust&amp;rsquo;, Sunak says Prime Minister Rishi Sunak defended the government&amp;rsquo;s approach to China. Comes after some MPs criticised the response to cyber-attacks against the Electoral Commission and UK politicians. The government has blamed the attacks on Beijing-linked hackers. Downing Street has played down suggestions the government is preparing to do this.&#xA;Prime Minister says EU countries have gone further in protecting themselves. He says China represents the greatest state-based threat to our economic security.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What we know about Baltimore bridge collapse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/23e9aa22-eba9-11ee-8e16-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 15:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/23e9aa22-eba9-11ee-8e16-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What we know about Baltimore bridge collapse The Francis Scott Key Bridge was opened in 1977. It spanned the Patapsco River and Baltimore harbour. A container ship crashed into the bridge early on Tuesday morning. Between seven and 20 people are believed to be in the river.&#xA;Maryland Governor Wes Moore has declared a state of emergency. The bridge was the third longest of its type in the world. The collapse happened at around 01:30 local time (05:30 GMT) on Tuesday.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Council and firm fined over engineer&#39;s storm death</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a602f4bc-ebb0-11ee-b7cf-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 15:03:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a602f4bc-ebb0-11ee-b7cf-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Council and firm fined over engineer&amp;rsquo;s storm death Matt Campbell was killed in Slieve Gullion Park in September 2018. A 200-year-old beech tree was uprooted and crushed him. amber weather warning was in place in Northern Ireland due to Storm Ali. Council and construction firm fined a total of £50,000.&#xA;Mr Campbell had been working for Lagan Construction Ltd as an electrical engineer. He was finishing up work in the park when he went back to lock up a pumping station.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Border Force response to Hamas attack victims probed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f3dcb824-ebad-11ee-aec4-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 14:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f3dcb824-ebad-11ee-aec4-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Border Force response to Hamas attack victims probed The Jewish Representative Council for Greater Manchester said two Israeli nationals had faced aggressive questioning by UK Border Force officials at Manchester Airport. The Home Office has launched a review. About 1,200 people were killed when Hamas militia stormed across Gaza&amp;rsquo;s border into Israel on 7 October in coordinated attacks. Manchester Airport said it was in touch with the Home Office.&#xA;Mr Cleverly replied on the social media platform: &amp;ldquo;We do not tolerate antisemitism or any form of discrimination.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thief sold stolen gems to at least 45 buyers on eBay, British Museum says</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b837d4d2-ebaa-11ee-b66d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 14:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b837d4d2-ebaa-11ee-b66d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Thief sold stolen gems to at least 45 buyers on eBay, British Museum says The British Museum has launched proceedings against a former staff member who they believe stole and damaged at least 1,800 of its items. The High Court has ordered the disclosure of eBay and PayPal records from the eBay account of the suspect, former curator Dr Peter Higgs. The court was told Dr Higgs intended to dispute the claims.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>King will attend Easter church service at Windsor</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/dde7044e-ebac-11ee-b622-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 13:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/dde7044e-ebac-11ee-b622-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>King will attend Easter church service at Windsor The King and Queen will attend the Easter Sunday service at St George&amp;rsquo;s Chapel at Windsor Castle. It will be one of the most significant events King Charles will have attended since his cancer diagnosis last month. But the Prince and Princess of Wales will not be there, as Catherine continues with her cancer treatment. The King will be with Queen Camilla, who has been carrying a number of solo royal engagements in her husband&amp;rsquo;s absence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BBC to explore reform of licence fee</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b9cb22e8-eba7-11ee-a0a5-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 13:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b9cb22e8-eba7-11ee-a0a5-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>BBC to explore reform of licence fee Davie said the BBC will look at the licence fee&amp;rsquo;s scope, how progressive it is and how it is enforced. In a speech on Tuesday, Davie said &amp;ldquo;it is right to ask fundamental questions about its longevity. But he added that we should be. Davie says annual savings target will now rise by £200m to £700m a year by 2028.&#xA;BBC income has effectively fallen by around 30% between 2010 and 2020.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Papa Johns pizza to shut nearly a tenth of UK sites</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/4f779a10-ebad-11ee-9c6e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 13:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/4f779a10-ebad-11ee-9c6e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Papa Johns pizza to shut nearly a tenth of UK sites Papa Johns says 43 of its restaurants are &amp;rsquo;no longer financially viable&amp;rsquo; The chain has 450 restaurants plus others in service stations and holiday parks. It has not said how many jobs will be hit by the closures. Revolution Bars has said it could sell all or part of its outlets. The closures are all in England and extend from Harrogate, North Yorkshire to St Helens, Merseyside, Billericay, Essex and Eastbourne, East Sussex.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In pictures: Baltimore bridge collapse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/93c48434-eba9-11ee-8bd6-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 13:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/93c48434-eba9-11ee-8bd6-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>In pictures: Baltimore bridge collapse The Francis Scott Key Bridge in Baltimore collapsed into the Patapsco River after a container ship crashed into it. Two people have been pulled from the water. Sonar has detected multiple vehicles underwater, where the temperature is around 8C (47F) All shipping traffic in and out of the Port of Baltimore has been suspended.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who is Julian Assange and why is he facing extradition?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/5a69d3b4-ebaa-11ee-987b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 11:50:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/5a69d3b4-ebaa-11ee-987b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Who is Julian Assange and why is he facing extradition? Julian Assange will find out on 20 May whether he will be extradited to the US. The UK courts had agreed to send him to be tried for disclosing military secrets. But he asked the High Court for permission to appeal against that decision. Mr Assange gained a reputation for computer programming as a teenager.&#xA;WikiLeaks published documents that suggested the US military had killed hundreds of civilians in unreported incidents during the war in Afghanistan.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaked emails reveal child gender service concerns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/42b086b0-ebae-11ee-b842-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 02:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/42b086b0-ebae-11ee-b842-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Leaked emails reveal child gender service concerns Hospital executives voiced worry about the cancellation of appointments, patients lacking information and poor communication with the new services. The controversial Gender Identity Development Service (Gids), which is run by the Tavistock and Portman NHS Foundation Trust, is due to close later this week. NHS England insisted patients would have &amp;ldquo;continuity of care. The sole NHS gender identity service for children in England and Wales will close in 2020.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bowen: Biden has decided strong words are not enough</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/fea16a56-eba9-11ee-8c25-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 22:33:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/fea16a56-eba9-11ee-8c25-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Bowen: Biden has decided strong words are not enough President Biden has decided that strong words are not enough. Removing diplomatic protection from Israel&amp;rsquo;s conduct of the war is a significant step. It shows the depth of the rift that has opened between the White House and Israel and its prime minister, Benjamin Netanyahu. The US president is deeply attached to Israel and calls himself a Zionist.&#xA;He wants freedom for the hostages as well as the destruction of Hamas as a military force.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can my landlord put up my rent, keep my deposit or evict me?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b8165262-ebaf-11ee-89d9-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 12:07:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b8165262-ebaf-11ee-89d9-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Can my landlord put up my rent, keep my deposit or evict me? The average cost of renting in the UK rose by 9% in the year to February. It is the highest annual increase since records began in 2015. Most tenants in England and Wales have an assured shorthold tenancy. About one in five households have a guaranteed tenancy in England.&#xA;Renting rules are different in England, Scotland, Wales and Northern Ireland.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doctors&#39; A&lt;title&gt;E safety warnings snubbed by watchdog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/053cb2ca-eaa7-11ee-9a10-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 11:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/053cb2ca-eaa7-11ee-9a10-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Doctors&amp;rsquo; AE safety warnings snubbed by watchdog Aamp;E consultants at Glasgow&amp;rsquo;s Queen Elizabeth University Hospital wrote to Healthcare Improvement Scotland (HIS) to warn patient safety was being compromised. They offered 18 months worth of evidence of overcrowding and staff shortages to back their claims. But HIS did not ask for this evidence. HIS has issued a &amp;ldquo;sincere and unreserved apology&amp;rdquo;&amp;quot; to the consultants and upheld two complaints about the way it handled their whistleblowing letter about patient safety.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opposition leads race for Senegal presidency - reports</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/60075f70-eaa2-11ee-a069-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 10:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/60075f70-eaa2-11ee-a069-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Opposition leads race for Senegal presidency - reports Bassirou Diomaye Faye is leading the race, according to local media. The ruling coalition&amp;rsquo;s choice, Amadou Ba, has denied that he has lost. Mr Faye, 44, was a senior official in the Pastef party led by Ousmane Sonko. First set of tallies announced on television showed Mr Faye had won the majority of votes.&#xA;The results led to five opposition candidates declaring him the winner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyber-attack on voter data to be linked to China</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/44d44742-ea9b-11ee-911e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 10:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/44d44742-ea9b-11ee-911e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Cyber-attack on voter data to be linked to China The attacks on the Electoral Commission took place in August 2021 but were only revealed last year. Several MPs and peers who have been critical of Beijing are thought to have also been targeted in cyber-attacks. Deputy Prime Minister Oliver Dowden will address Parliament on Monday about the threat. It is now thought that Mr Dowden will suggest those behind the attack had links to Beijing, as well as laying out how the UK will respond to what it deems a wider threat.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;It&#39;s on another level, completely alien in darts&#39; - the rapid rise of Luke Littler</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/3b8497fa-eaa0-11ee-9e7d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 10:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/3b8497fa-eaa0-11ee-9e7d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;It&amp;rsquo;s on another level, completely alien in darts&amp;rsquo; - the rapid rise of Luke Littler Luke Littler is the youngest ever PDC World Championship finalist. The 17-year-old has earned more than £350,000 in prize money in the past three months. His manager is Martin Foulds, whose ZXF Sports Management firm also looks after other top players including World Matchplay champion Nathan Aspinall. Darts star says travelling can take its toll on players.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Olivia Colman: I&#39;d be paid more if I was Oliver</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/16dc5862-ea9a-11ee-af8e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 09:40:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/16dc5862-ea9a-11ee-af8e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Olivia Colman: I&amp;rsquo;d be paid more if I was Oliver Olivia Colman says she would be paid a lot more if she was a man. Says she knows of one pay disparity which was a 12,000% difference. The issue of equal pay in Hollywood burst into the open a decade ago. The latest top 10 list of the best-paid actors contains just two women.&#xA;Colman joined the Hollywood A-list in 2019 when she won the best actress Oscar for playing Queen Anne in The Favourite.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the state pension and the triple lock?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/7e4398ec-ebaf-11ee-9a87-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 09:23:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/7e4398ec-ebaf-11ee-9a87-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What is the state pension and the triple lock? Pensioners generally receive an increase in line with rising prices or earnings. The state pension is a payment made every four weeks by the government to people who have reached the qualifying age. In April 2023, the state pension went up by 10. 1%.&#xA;In April 2024, the link to earnings will see an increase of 8.5%.The triple lock was designed to ensure the value of the state pension was not overtaken by the increase in the cost of living.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NI sees 20% rise in 18-49 cancer diagnoses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6d30635a-eaa6-11ee-aa18-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 07:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6d30635a-eaa6-11ee-aa18-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>NI sees 20% rise in 18-49 cancer diagnoses Figures show that, by 2019, 1,076 people aged 18-49 were diagnosed with some form of cancer. Prof Helen Coleman, who was involved in the research, said it was worrying. The research looked at early onset cancers, which means cancers diagnosed in adults under the age of 50. Cancers commonly seen in older people are now being diagnosed in younger adults.&#xA;The rise has also been seen in other western countries such as across the UK, America and Australia.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Murray in dramatic defeat by Machac in Miami</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/4dc0e730-eaa9-11ee-8e5f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 07:02:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/4dc0e730-eaa9-11ee-8e5f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Murray in dramatic defeat by Machac in Miami Andy Murray beaten 5-7 7-5 7-6 (7-5) by Tomas Machac in Miami. British number one Cameron Norrie loses to third seed Daniil Medvedev. Murray received treatment on an ankle injury late in the third set. The 36-year-old was also agitated by movement in the crowd.&#xA;Machac broke Murray for the first time at 6-5 in the second set to draw level. Murray&amp;rsquo;s frustration grew with people in the crowd moving and umpire Carlos Bernardes at the end of that set.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indians celebrate Holi - the festival of colours</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/bc0eb93c-eaa0-11ee-aca9-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 07:01:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/bc0eb93c-eaa0-11ee-aca9-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Indians celebrate Holi - the festival of colours Millions of Indians are celebrating Holi, known as the festival of colours. The festival celebrates the beginning of spring and the victory of good over evil. It is based on the Hindu legend of Holika, a female demon, who tries to kill her nephew Prahlad because he worships the Hindu god Vishnu. Holi is one of the most widely celebrated festivals in India.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Say one thing, do another? The government’s record net migration rise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/eea7467c-ea99-11ee-bb51-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 06:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/eea7467c-ea99-11ee-bb51-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Say one thing, do another? The government’s record net migration rise The 12 months to June 2022 saw the fastest population growth since the 1960s. Current projections from the Office for National Statistics put the UK on course for 74 million people by 2036 - six million more than there are today. The answer, according to the ONS, is largely immigration. Small boats are an important issue - on a human and national level.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Home Office launches &#39;stop the boats&#39; ad campaign in Vietnam</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/9d7b8d28-eaa1-11ee-b7ef-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 05:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/9d7b8d28-eaa1-11ee-b7ef-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Home Office launches &amp;lsquo;stop the boats&amp;rsquo; ad campaign in Vietnam The Home Office has launched a social media advert campaign targeting Vietnamese nationals. The government says the adverts will set out the risks of small boat crossings. They follow similar adverts in Albania, which officials claim have contributed to a 90% reduction in arrivals. Labour said the government should end the gimmicks and get a grip.&#xA;The number of people from Vietnam making the journey so far this year is up 17%, compared with the same period in 2023.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dragon Ball theme park to be built in Saudi Arabia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/495b2a5a-ea9c-11ee-b1ea-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 03:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/495b2a5a-ea9c-11ee-b1ea-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Dragon Ball theme park to be built in Saudi Arabia The theme park will feature a 70m (229. 6ft) dragon at its centre. It will be the world&amp;rsquo;s first theme park based on the popular Japanese series. The announcement has been met with criticism for its human rights record.&#xA;It comes just weeks after the death of the show&amp;rsquo;s creator, Akira Toriyama. The Dragon Ball comic series debuted in 1984. It follows a boy named Son Goku in his quest to collect magical dragon balls.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientists to hunt mysterious &#39;ghost&#39; particles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b9332974-ea9a-11ee-a7d7-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:49:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b9332974-ea9a-11ee-a7d7-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Scientists to hunt mysterious &amp;lsquo;ghost&amp;rsquo; particles New instrument will be a thousand times more sensitive to such particles than previous devices. It will smash particles into a hard surface to detect them instead of against each other like Cern&amp;rsquo;s main device the Large Hadron Collider (LHC). The current theory of particle physics is called the Standard Model. Everything in the Universe is made up of a family of 17 particles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jewish settlers set their sights on Gaza beachfront</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f5c95bbc-ea98-11ee-87f9-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 23:26:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f5c95bbc-ea98-11ee-87f9-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Jewish settlers set their sights on Gaza beachfront Daniella Weiss, 78, is the grandmother of Israel&amp;rsquo;s settler movement. She says she already has a list of 500 families ready to move to Gaza immediately. Mrs Weiss heads a radical settler organisation called Nachala, or homeland. She has been kickstarting Jewish settlements in the Israeli-occupied West Bank and East Jerusalem.&#xA;Some in the settler movement have cherished the dream - or pipedream - of returning to Gaza.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Murder arrest at Heathrow after man hit by car</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/952dfe2a-eaa2-11ee-9248-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 21:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/952dfe2a-eaa2-11ee-9248-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Murder arrest at Heathrow after man hit by car Man, 35, found injured at the scene near the junction with Arragon Road. A 33-year-old man was arrested at the airport on suspicion of assisting an offender. Police are appealing for witnesses to the incident in Barking Road, east London, to come forward. Police do not believe there to be any risk to the wider community.&#xA;Officers will remain in the area over the coming days to provide reassurance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rare white magpie caught on camera</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/28c5de60-ea9d-11ee-97fc-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 20:52:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/28c5de60-ea9d-11ee-97fc-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Rare white magpie caught on camera Amateur photographer Terry Wright photographed the creature, which he nicknamed Joy, in Pembrokeshire earlier this month. The bird is leucistic, which means it lacks pigment in its feathering. The Welsh Ornithological Society said the bird was very unusual. The 54-year-old has a condition called vitiligo, which has caused pigment loss in parts of his skin.&#xA;Mr Wright, from Abercych, said capturing the images left him feeling like &amp;ldquo;the luckiest man alive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I ran &#39;toughest race&#39; to inspire women worldwide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/18a18fa8-eaa1-11ee-8f67-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 19:21:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/18a18fa8-eaa1-11ee-8f67-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>I ran &amp;rsquo;toughest race&amp;rsquo; to inspire women worldwide Jasmin Paris is one of only 20 people to have finished the Barkley Marathons since it was extended to 100 miles in 1989. She crossed the finish line on Friday with 99 seconds to spare before the 60-hour cut-off. The annual race involves five loops of roughly 20 miles (32km) with 60,000 ft (18,000m) of ascents and descents. Jasmin slumped to the ground as she crossed the finish line.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Briton &#39;overjoyed&#39; at completing one of world&#39;s toughest races</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/92cebdb0-e9dd-11ee-a67f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 11:27:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/92cebdb0-e9dd-11ee-a67f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Briton &amp;lsquo;overjoyed&amp;rsquo; at completing one of world&amp;rsquo;s toughest races Jasmin Paris from Midlothian completed the Barkley Marathons in Tennessee with just one minute 39 seconds to spare. The course, at Frozen Head State Park, changes every year but covers 100 miles involving 60,000ft of climb and descent. Only 20 people have ever made it to the end of the race within the allotted 60 hours. Jasmin lost her voice from heavy breathing during the race.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is this a chance for a fresh start for Palestinian politics?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f805e62e-e9db-11ee-bfb4-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 11:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f805e62e-e9db-11ee-bfb4-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Is this a chance for a fresh start for Palestinian politics? The last time Palestinians had the chance to vote for their national leaders was 18 years ago. Hamas, which won the elections, and Fatah, the biggest political faction, were shooting each other in Gaza. Israel says it is intent on eliminating Hamas as a governing and military force. International eyes have turned towards the PA as the vehicle that might carry Palestinians into a new, united post-war era.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>William and Kate &#39;enormously touched&#39; by public support</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f87186f8-e9d7-11ee-a529-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 10:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f87186f8-e9d7-11ee-a529-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>William and Kate &amp;rsquo;enormously touched&amp;rsquo; by public support Catherine revealed in a video message on Friday that she had begun treatment. The Prince and Princess of Wales are &amp;rsquo;enormously touched&amp;rsquo; by the kind messages. They are &amp;lsquo;grateful&amp;rsquo; that the public have understood their request for privacy, Kensington Palace said. Catherine received her diagnosis after tests carried out following abdominal surgery.&#xA;A spokesperson for Kensington Palace said: &amp;ldquo;The Prince and Princess are both enormously touched by the kind messages from people here in the UK, across the Commonwealth and around the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harris set to become new Fine Gael leader later</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/92f836b0-e9e5-11ee-ae71-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 10:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/92f836b0-e9e5-11ee-ae71-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Harris set to become new Fine Gael leader later Nominations closed at 13:00 local time on Sunday. Mr Harris was the only candidate for the position at the close of nominations. He is set to replace Leo Varadkar, who announced on Wednesday he was stepping down as party leader and taoiseach. The 37-year-old was the early favourite, with many backing him before nominations even opened.&#xA;Ministers Helen McEntee, Paschal Donohoe and Heather Humphreys were among those to throw their support behind Mr Harris.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gunmen free Nigerian pupils taken in mass abduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/460b0d12-e9dd-11ee-bf96-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 10:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/460b0d12-e9dd-11ee-bf96-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Gunmen free Nigerian pupils taken in mass abduction Kaduna state governor Uba Sani said they had been rescued thanks to the courage of the security forces. School authorities had said more than 280 children were taken, but the army said 137 hostages had been freed. It said the operation took place in the early hours of Sunday morning. Six mass abductions this month have rocked parts of northern Nigeria.&#xA;Kidnappers had demanded $690,000 (£548,000) for the release of the Kuriga children.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alonso penalised over Russell crash incident</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/12b2ddcc-e9e8-11ee-afe5-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 09:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/12b2ddcc-e9e8-11ee-afe5-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Alonso penalised over Russell crash incident Fernando Alonso was penalised 20 seconds for dangerous driving at the Australian Grand Prix. The two-time world champion told stewards he had &amp;ldquo;got it slightly wrong. Alonso admitted he had braked too early at Turn Six and then accelerated again. The penalty dropped him from sixth place to eighth in the results.&#xA;Alonso lost control of his car on the final lap of the race and crashed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Woman arrested as missing young siblings found</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/45d67bee-e9e5-11ee-82fe-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 09:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/45d67bee-e9e5-11ee-82fe-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Woman arrested as missing young siblings found The three-year-old boy and the girls - aged five and eight - were reported missing on Friday. A woman has been arrested on suspicion of child neglect. Gloucestershire Police say the children have now been found and are safe. The woman arrested in connection with the incident remains in custody.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sainz wins in Australia after Verstappen retires</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/80588798-e9e6-11ee-a174-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 08:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/80588798-e9e6-11ee-a174-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Sainz wins in Australia after Verstappen retires Carlos Sainz leads Charles Leclerc to a Ferrari one-two in the Australian Grand Prix. Max Verstappen retires with a brake failure after just four laps. The race ended under a virtual safety car after a crash for George Russell. The Mercedes driver lost control at Turn Six on the final lap.&#xA;Alonso and Russell were called to the stewards, who penalised the Spaniard 20 seconds, dropping him to eighth place.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hygiene poverty is a sign of crisis, says charity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6b9b6f5a-e9e1-11ee-b81f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 07:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6b9b6f5a-e9e1-11ee-b81f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Hygiene poverty is a sign of crisis, says charity The Hygiene Bank helps people who cannot afford basic essential toiletries. A new survey found that more than three million people in the UK are thought to be experiencing hygiene poverty. Volunteers at one of the charity&amp;rsquo;s schemes, in Bromley, south-east London, said a school washed pupils&amp;rsquo; clothes. The charity receives donations from the community, which are sorted by volunteers.&#xA;34;It often the first sign that a family is falling into crisis when they can&amp;rsquo;t afford these basic essentials,’ she said.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;My best friend saved me by giving me his kidney&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/29e04464-e9e6-11ee-94d6-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 07:07:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/29e04464-e9e6-11ee-94d6-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;My best friend saved me by giving me his kidney&amp;rsquo; Steven Smith had been experiencing cramps and occasional vomiting. A routine blood test revealed his kidney function was down to 20%. He was told if it got any lower he would need a transplant. Steven told his best friend, Kael Ace, who was a perfect match.&#xA;Steven&amp;rsquo;s mother gave him her kidney after he was diagnosed with kidney failure. The friends used pictures to verify their 10-year friendship, which started when they joined the same rugby team.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simon Harris - a man in a hurry to the top</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/4d903cd6-e9df-11ee-bb36-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 06:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/4d903cd6-e9df-11ee-bb36-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Simon Harris - a man in a hurry to the top Simon Harris, 37, is a year younger than Leo Varadkar was when he took the same job in 2017. Harris organised his first political meeting at just 16 years of age. He was a county councillor at 22, a TD (member of the Irish Parliament) at 24. Harris dropped out of college without finishing his degree.&#xA;Mr Harris was born in 1986 and grew up in the coastal town of Greystones, County Wicklow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Having a certificate of loss proves my baby existed’</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2808b0b4-e9e0-11ee-828d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:46:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2808b0b4-e9e0-11ee-828d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>‘Having a certificate of loss proves my baby existed’ Emma Barnett wrote about the heartbreak of losing a baby this week. She said receiving a certificate to mark the miscarriage has helped her family. Here, other women share their thoughts and feelings about the government&amp;rsquo;s new scheme for bereaved parents to commemorate pregnancy losses. The morning baby loss certificates were launched I found myself pouring my details into the website to apply.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pilgrimage helped Traitors star Amanda say &#39;goodbye mum&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ebacf544-e9da-11ee-a566-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:24:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ebacf544-e9da-11ee-a566-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Pilgrimage helped Traitors star Amanda say &amp;lsquo;goodbye mum&amp;rsquo; Amanda, 56, was catapulted to public attention in the BBC&amp;rsquo;s first series of The Traitors - where she donned her hooded cloak. She is one of seven well known personalities, of differing faiths and beliefs, to tackle a modern-day pilgrimage for a new BBC Two series. Amanda&amp;rsquo;s childhood was unconventional, particularly her relationship with her mother. As a practising Catholic, she initially wanted to question her faith.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jealous K-pop fans try to dictate their idols&#39; private lives</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/221a79a4-e9da-11ee-ad6b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:07:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/221a79a4-e9da-11ee-ad6b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Jealous K-pop fans try to dictate their idols&amp;rsquo; private lives K-pop star Karina posted a handwritten apology on Instagram earlier in March. The apology came after she acknowledged that she was in a relationship with actor Lee Jae-wook. It opens a window into the world of K-pop&amp;rsquo;s super fans. They stream their favourite stars&amp;rsquo; music round the clock to boost chart rankings.&#xA;When news of Karina&amp;rsquo;s relationship broke, some fans drove a truck to her management agency.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the man in the iron lung lived life to the full</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/bda23328-e9d8-11ee-9655-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:06:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/bda23328-e9d8-11ee-9655-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How the man in the iron lung lived life to the full Paul Alexander was left quadriplegic after a serious bout of polio. He spent more than seven decades using his iron lung, longer than anyone else in history. But what was it that marked him out from so many of his peers, and kept him going? The iron lung uses a negative pressure system.&#xA;Powered by a motor, its bellows suck air out of the cylinder, creating a vacuum around the patient and forcing the lungs to expand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>England kits &#39;should connect people&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1d9c66d6-e9e3-11ee-8813-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 17:09:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1d9c66d6-e9e3-11ee-8813-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>England kits &amp;lsquo;should connect people&amp;rsquo; England&amp;rsquo;s new kit has ignited a row about national identity. Critics have branded the design &amp;ldquo;disrespectful&amp;rsquo; But battles over England shirts have a long and literally colourful back story. England taking on Brazil at Wembley is one of the great sporting occasions. Two proud footballing nations boasting instantly recognisable kits.&#xA;Manufacturer Nike has changed the cross of St George, with its horizontal bar now a combination of blues and purples rather than the red of the original flag.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Campaigning dad of Damilola Taylor dies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a9168f8e-e92f-11ee-9bbe-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 15:31:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a9168f8e-e92f-11ee-9bbe-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Campaigning dad of Damilola Taylor dies The former Nigerian civil servant dedicated years to improving the lives of disadvantaged children in the wake of his son&amp;rsquo;s death. He set up the Damilola Taylor Trust to campaign against knife crime. Mr Taylor died on Saturday aged 75 with prostate cancer. He was 10 when he was stabbed in the leg and left to die in a south London stairwell in 2000.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Outpouring of support for Kate after cancer news</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/7cbeb2ee-e93a-11ee-8e3c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 14:43:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/7cbeb2ee-e93a-11ee-8e3c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Outpouring of support for Kate after cancer news Princess of Wales reveals she is being treated for cancer. She has been receiving chemotherapy since late February. Cancer charities have praised her openness, while world leaders, friends and celebrities have wished her well. The news has also led to calls for her and her family to be given privacy.&#xA;Catherine said she and Prince William had taken time to sensitively share the state of her health with their children.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harry and Meghan reach out to Kate after cancer news</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/9da0ab50-e92d-11ee-91e4-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 13:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/9da0ab50-e92d-11ee-91e4-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Harry and Meghan reach out to Kate after cancer news The Duke and Duchess of Sussex have reached out to the Prince and Princess of Wales, the BBC understands. The contact is understood to have been made privately. Prince Harry and Meghan said they wished health and healing for Catherine. The princess is confident that she will make a full recovery.&#xA;Catherine had abdominal surgery in January, but it was not known then there was any cancer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Briton becomes first woman to finish one of world&#39;s toughest races</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2be828e8-e92e-11ee-a363-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 11:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2be828e8-e92e-11ee-a363-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Briton becomes first woman to finish one of world&amp;rsquo;s toughest races Jasmin Paris from Midlothian completed the Barkley Marathons in Tennessee with just one minute 39 seconds to spare of the 60-hour cut off. The course, at Frozen Head State Park, changes every year but covers 100 miles involving 60,000ft of climb and descent. Only 20 people have ever made it to the end of the race within the allotted 60 hours since it was extended to 100 miles in 1989.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Verstappen takes Australia pole with Hamilton 11th</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/446d8a70-e942-11ee-af62-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 08:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/446d8a70-e942-11ee-af62-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Verstappen takes Australia pole with Hamilton 11th Red Bull&amp;rsquo;s Max Verstappen fights off a challenge from Ferrari driver Carlos Sainz to take pole position for the Australian Grand Prix. Red Bull#39;s Max VerStappen fought off a challenges from Ferrari&amp;rsquo;s Carlos Sianz to claim pole position. Sainz was quickest in the first two parts of qualifying but the world champion bounced back in the top 10 shootout. Lando Norris will start third ahead of Ferrari#39;s Charles Leclerc after a grid penalty for Red Bull&amp;rsquo;s Sergio Perez.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>London landmarks join Earth Hour lights switch-off</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6626ea82-e93b-11ee-847b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 07:36:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6626ea82-e93b-11ee-847b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>London landmarks join Earth Hour lights switch-off The annual Earth Hour, spearheaded by the World Wide Fund for Nature (WWF), is observed around the world. Previous years have seen Big Ben, the Eiffel Tower, and the Sydney Opera House turn out the lights. WWF suggests individuals use the 60 minutes, between 20:30 and 21:30, to do something positive for the planet. Lit-up landmarks that will go dark for the hour include the Barbican Arts Centre, the Old Bailey, Tower Bridge, and the OXO Tower.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From the desert to the icy waters of Wales</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/d316da58-e931-11ee-b362-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 07:11:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/d316da58-e931-11ee-b362-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>From the desert to the icy waters of Wales Amr Madbouly is a decarbonisation engineer at the Tata steelworks in Port Talbot. He has become an enthusiastic promoter of Welsh nature on social media. The average air temperature in Cairo, like the average water temperature, doesn#39;t fall much below 20C. Amr, 34, from Bridgend, loves to go and plunge into a river or waterfall.&#xA;He was inspired to move to Wales by a desire to live close to its mountains and waterfalls.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My father&#39;s diary left me wondering whether he was a killer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/3b9bd72a-e939-11ee-8202-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 06:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/3b9bd72a-e939-11ee-8202-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>My father&amp;rsquo;s diary left me wondering whether he was a killer Saul Wordsworth&amp;rsquo;s father Christopher may have taken a terrible secret to his grave. He knew all about his quick temper and explosive outbursts of rage. But a set of his diaries inherited by Saul hinted at something altogether darker. The passage she highlighted referred to hiding a body until a search party had gone.&#xA;Growing up in Harpenden, Hertfordshire, Saul knew his father as a teller of tall tales.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Oasis&#39; first tour venues, 30 years on</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/5549aa36-e938-11ee-9fbf-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 02:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/5549aa36-e938-11ee-9fbf-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Revisiting Oasis&amp;rsquo; first tour venues, 30 years on Exactly 30 years ago, a little-known band called Oasis set out on their first headline tour. Mark Davyd was asked to book a gig by a rising Scottish band called Whiteout at his venue in Kent in March 1994. He wasn#39;t keen when he found out that an unfamiliar Mancunian group would also be on the bill. He wanted to put on a local support act instead - but the agent stressed it was a joint headlined tour.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Nazi hunter and the lost IRA documentary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a006552c-e93f-11ee-9ba0-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 02:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a006552c-e93f-11ee-9ba0-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The Nazi hunter and the lost IRA documentary The film was made in 1972 when the IRA was at its lowest ebb. It shows the group planning and carrying out attacks.&#xA;Former IRA members who took part in the film said they were unaware of Aldouby#39;s intelligence connections. Also among those filmed handling guns and bombs was Martin McGuinness, then a rising young IRA leader.&#xA;As a Sinn Féin politician he became the deputy first minister of Northern Ireland.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Nazi hunter and the lost IRA documentary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/e0534710-e936-11ee-a294-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 02:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/e0534710-e936-11ee-a294-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The Nazi hunter and the lost IRA documentary Zwy Aldouby filmed the majority of the IRA secret leadership between March and June 1972. The film has not been seen by the public for almost 50 years. It is the subject of a new BBC documentary called #34;The Secret Army. The documentary will be on BBC iPlayer on 27 March.&#xA;Former IRA members who took part in the film said they were unaware of Aldouby intelligence connections.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High rural house prices force locals into renting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/11d25c6e-e93b-11ee-8002-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 02:35:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/11d25c6e-e93b-11ee-8002-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>High rural house prices force locals into renting A 19% increase in rural renting has outpaced rises in London and other cities. House prices in rural counties are the most unaffordable outside London at an average of £309,000. In the Cotswolds, locals like Sophie Brown are finding they have been priced out of the property market. Gloucestershire Rural Community Council (GRCC) has been dealing with the problem.&#xA;Holiday lettings and second-home buying had seen many landlords take properties out of the longer-term private rental sector.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moscow concert hall attack videos examined</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f0260ed2-e933-11ee-960b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f0260ed2-e933-11ee-960b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Moscow concert hall attack videos examined CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;We don&#39;t live, we&#39;re just alive&#39;: Afghan girls despair at Taliban school ban</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/86f73c5c-e93c-11ee-92d0-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/86f73c5c-e93c-11ee-92d0-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;We don&amp;rsquo;t live, we&amp;rsquo;re just alive&amp;rsquo;: Afghan girls despair at Taliban school ban More than 900 days have now passed since girls over 12 were first banned. Taliban have repeatedly promised they would be readmitted once a number of issues were resolved. But they have made little comment as a third new school year started this week. The BBC has asked the Taliban#39;s education minister for an explanation, but he has so far not responded.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First J-Pop, then K-Pop - could I-Pop be next?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/38ce4002-e937-11ee-b0d3-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/38ce4002-e937-11ee-b0d3-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>First J-Pop, then K-Pop - could I-Pop be next? Ri, Zo, Sim, and Suchi are said to be India;s first mainstream girl group in more than 20 years. W.i.S.H. is an acronym of World inka Stage Hai, or the world is their stage. W.i.S.H. want to change that and get to the top by spreading a positive message of sisterhood and female empowerment. She describes their debut single, Lazeez, as a song that #34;celebrates the modern woman and encourages self-love.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Africa&#39;s deadly love affair with guns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b20ae44c-e938-11ee-89d2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b20ae44c-e938-11ee-89d2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>South Africa&amp;rsquo;s deadly love affair with guns Penson Menson has been carrying a gun wherever he goes in South Africa. He says he has had to use his gun multiple times to protect himself. Menson: &amp;ldquo;I never know when I will be attacked by someone who wants to kill me&amp;rdquo; He says the police and government have failed to do enough to protect the public. South African law states that most people with a gun licence can carry a firearm if it is concealed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man killed in Kilkeel house named locally</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2e085288-e884-11ee-993d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 16:37:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2e085288-e884-11ee-993d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Man killed in Kilkeel house named locally Bobbie McKee, 69, was found dead in a house in Kilkeel on Thursday. A woman, also in her 60s, sustained serious head injuries in the incident. A 25-year-old man arrested on suspicion of murder and attempted murder remains in custody. DUP assembly member for South Down Diane Forsythe described a #34;lovely family#34;&amp;quot; at the centre of the incident.&#xA;However, at this time, we are not treating this as a firearms-related report.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FA defends new England kit over flag design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/176deb02-e873-11ee-9c81-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 16:21:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/176deb02-e873-11ee-9c81-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>FA defends new England kit over flag design The FA has defended the St George#39;s Cross design on its new England kit. The body said it understood what the flag #34;means to our fans. It added the fresh 2024 home kit was meant as a tribute to the 1966 World Cup winning team. Prime Minister Rishi Sunak said he preferred the original and the national flag was a source of pride and identity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FA defends new England kit over flag design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/44d98486-e885-11ee-8bab-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 16:21:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/44d98486-e885-11ee-8bab-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>FA defends new England kit over flag design The FA has defended the St George#39;s Cross design on its new England kit. The body said it understood what the flag #34;means to our fans. Nike said its design was to celebrate the 1966 World Cup team. Both the prime minister and Labour leader criticised the design.&#xA;Prime Minister Rishi Sunak said he preferred the original and the national flag was a source of pride and identity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nationwide payments back to normal after delays</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/acfe1486-e87c-11ee-953f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 16:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/acfe1486-e87c-11ee-953f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Nationwide payments back to normal after delays Customers of UK;s biggest building society reported a range of problems, including transferring money and buying a train ticket. Nationwide says the IT issue has now been resolved but payment backlogs took a few hours to clear. Firm is currently trying to buy Virgin Money in a £2. 9bn deal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ex-boss of Poundland owner dies from gunshot wound</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/3f3d3d5a-e87c-11ee-90cf-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 15:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/3f3d3d5a-e87c-11ee-90cf-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Ex-boss of Poundland owner dies from gunshot wound Markus Jooste, the former head of the Steinhoff retail group, has died. The 63-year-old succumbed to a gunshot wound in hospital, police said. Local media reported he shot himself at his home in the southern town of Hermanus. He was ordered to pay a $25m fine - said to be the biggest in South Africa&amp;rsquo;s history.&#xA;Steinhoff International Holdings is based in South Africa but also listed in Germany.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Row erupts over German football kit deal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/dfd6c5c0-e87b-11ee-b8db-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 15:50:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/dfd6c5c0-e87b-11ee-b8db-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Row erupts over German football kit deal The contract will pass from the German company to US firm Nike from 2027. The DFB said the deal made financial sense and would support grassroots German football. However, according to reports in the German press, Nike agreed to pay about €100m (£86m; $108m) per year. The DFB said on X, formerly Twitter, that it understood the emotional reaction to its decision.&#xA;Bavarian premier Markus Soeder said the national team always plays in the three stripes of Adidas.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Funeral held for teenage stabbing victim</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/831731a0-e883-11ee-86e2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 15:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/831731a0-e883-11ee-86e2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Funeral held for teenage stabbing victim Mason Rist, 15, died after being attacked by a number of people on 27 January. His best friend, Max Dixon, also died in the incident. Family and friends gathered at South Bristol Methodist Church on Thursday. Reverend Sally Spencer said the family were being &amp;lsquo;really brave and courageous&amp;rsquo; The service was held in memory of the young man who was killed in a car crash last month.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malaysia rejects offer to host Commonwealth Games</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6597a91c-e87d-11ee-bf9c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 15:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6597a91c-e87d-11ee-bf9c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Malaysia rejects offer to host Commonwealth Games The Commonwealth Games Federation (CGF) offered Malaysia £100m as supporting funds after the Australian state of Victoria withdrew as host. But Malaysia;s sports ministry said the offer ;will not cover the overall cost of hosting a large-scale sports event. The economic impact could not be identified in this short timeframe, it added. The confidential process to determine a host is continuing with other interested Commonwealth Games Associations, said a CGF spokesperson.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man who stabbed victim in neck jailed for 28 years</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ff6d56d4-e884-11ee-be04-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 13:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ff6d56d4-e884-11ee-be04-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Man who stabbed victim in neck jailed for 28 years James Smith, 36, of Llanelli, stabbed Ashley Sarsero, 26, in the neck. Smith was handed a life sentence and told he would serve a minimum of 28 years in jail before being eligible for parole. He was jailed at Swansea Crown Court. Steven Morgan, also 36, was sentenced to four-and-a-half years for helping Smith flee the scene.&#xA;The jury in the three-week trial heard Smith and Morgan had been invited into Mr Sarsero#39;s home in the Maestir area of Felinfoel by his mother.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Send &#39;arrogant&#39; Starmer a message, Sunak tells voters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/417be7ac-e876-11ee-bfb7-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 12:59:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/417be7ac-e876-11ee-bfb7-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Send &amp;lsquo;arrogant&amp;rsquo; Starmer a message, Sunak tells voters PM claims Labour leader has no plan for how to run the country. Mr Sunak said voters should look to councils like Birmingham to see what Labour would do if they win power. Many Conservatives are braced for a bad night on 2 May when council elections are being held across England and Wales. Hundreds of job losses, services slashed, streetlights being dimmed or switched off, making the streets less safe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skier in coma after ravine fall in Bulgaria</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/51af3418-e848-11ee-b9ce-ed33906497a8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/51af3418-e848-11ee-b9ce-ed33906497a8/</guid>
      <description>Skier in coma after ravine fall in Bulgaria Olivia Corbiere, from Aston near Sheffield, suffered serious injuries, including a brain bleed and lung damage, in the accident on Sunday. She had to be placed in an induced coma and needed brain surgery. Her injuries included severe head trauma, a broken eye socket and a broken pelvis.&#xA;To date, more than £23,000 has been raised. Mrs Corbiere said she did not know what her long-term prognosis will be.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MacIntyre taunts American hosts with Ryder Cup score</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a2e0ddc6-e886-11ee-866f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 09:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a2e0ddc6-e886-11ee-866f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>MacIntyre taunts American hosts with Ryder Cup score MacIntyre took advantage of a quirk of the tournament that allows players to choose wording for their caddie#39;s bib. The Scot opted for #39:EUR 16. 5-11. 5 USA and posted it on Twitter.&#xA;MacIntyre, 27, was unbeaten with two and a half points at the Marco Simone Country Club as Luke Donald#39;s side won back the Ryder Cup. He did not pair up with English caddie Mike Burrows until a month later.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leclerc tops Australian GP second practice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/4bd845c2-e887-11ee-a6a1-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 08:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/4bd845c2-e887-11ee-a6a1-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Leclerc tops Australian GP second practice Ferrari&amp;rsquo;s Charles Leclerc was 0. 381 seconds faster than Red Bull&amp;rsquo;s Max Verstappen. Carlos Sainz was third, from Lance Stroll and Fernando Alonso of Aston Martin and George Russell of Mercedes. Lewis Hamilton in the second Mercedes was 18th fastest.&#xA;Verstappen ran later than his rivals because of the enforced delay to his programme. He should have had the better of the track conditions when he set his fastest lap.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Couple adopted vulnerable children to abuse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/d87244c8-e87e-11ee-8219-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 06:26:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/d87244c8-e87e-11ee-8219-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Couple adopted vulnerable children to abuse The abuse began with Couple A in Gloucestershire, who specifically asked to adopt an emotionally disturbed child so they could assault them. The couple, eventually jailed in 2018, went on to adopt four siblings, beginning a cycle of sexual abuse that lasted for years. Couple A, who cannot be named for legal reasons, adopted the four young siblings, who had been abused by their birth parents, in the 1990s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Help my brother first&#39;: Gazan girl&#39;s plea as entire family killed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/fe27ec46-e873-11ee-9568-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 06:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/fe27ec46-e873-11ee-9568-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Help my brother first&amp;rsquo;: Gazan girl&amp;rsquo;s plea as entire family killed Alma Jaroor, 12, was buried under the rubble of a five-storey building in downtown Gaza City for over three hours. In video recorded by a Palestinian rescuer, a shout comes from under mounds of smashed concrete. 3 months on, Alma tells the BBC her story, at length and in detail. Tarazan was 18 months old when he was killed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘I want to help people fly – and keep them safe’</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/e6ebbf80-e87d-11ee-847b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/e6ebbf80-e87d-11ee-847b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>‘I want to help people fly – and keep them safe’ Pooja Umashankar has returned from Sri Lanka to study aircraft maintenance engineering at the University of South Wales. For years, airlines and engineering firms have struggled to hire maintenance engineers. There is now a global shortage numbering in the tens of thousands, and aviation is expected to balloon in coming decades. Around 700,000 engineers will have to enter the profession between now and 2040.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do interest rates affect me?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/25676a5e-ebb0-11ee-b4fb-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 12:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/25676a5e-ebb0-11ee-b4fb-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How do interest rates affect me? Interest rates set by the Bank of England affect mortgage, credit card and savings rates for millions of people across the UK. The base rate, currently 5. 25%, is what it charges other lenders to borrow money. It has a target to keep UK inflation at 2%.&#xA;The Bank may decide to raise rates to encourage people to spend less. The idea is that this helps to bring inflation down by dampening demand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do interest rates affect me?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/e7495566-e880-11ee-9cf3-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 12:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/e7495566-e880-11ee-9cf3-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How do interest rates affect me? Interest rates set by the Bank of England affect mortgage, credit card and savings rates for millions of people across the UK. The base rate, currently 5. 25%, is what it charges other lenders to borrow money. It has a target to keep UK inflation at 2%.&#xA;The Bank may decide to raise rates to encourage people to spend less. The idea is that this helps to bring inflation down by dampening demand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All you need to know about April train strikes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1e009d84-e882-11ee-9d43-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 14:23:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1e009d84-e882-11ee-9d43-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>All you need to know about April train strikes Train drivers at 16 train firms will take part in rolling one-day walk outs between 5 and 8 April. London Underground drivers will strike on Monday 8 April and Saturday 4 May. Aslef members will also refuse to work on rest days from Thursday 4 to Saturday 6 April and from Monday 8 to Tuesday 9 April. Rail passengers with advance tickets can be refunded fee-free if the train they are booked on is cancelled, delayed or rescheduled due to strikes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who gets 15 hours of free childcare and when do I apply?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2a722096-e883-11ee-93c8-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 14:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2a722096-e883-11ee-93c8-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Who gets 15 hours of free childcare and when do I apply? Working parents in England can apply for 15 hours of free weekly childcare for their two-year-olds. The government hopes that extending free childcare to this age group from April 2024 - and to all under-5s in 2025 - will get more parents back to work. Extra help with childcare costs is being rolled out in stages. The help you can get depends on the age of your child, and whether you are working, or receiving certain benefits.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How are the child benefit rules changing?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/edc09b34-ebaf-11ee-865b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 14:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/edc09b34-ebaf-11ee-865b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How are the child benefit rules changing? The government says the changes will help more than half a million families. Only one person can claim child benefit for a child. There is no limit to how many children you can claim for. Child benefit is usually paid into a nominated bank account every four weeks.&#xA;You can find out how much child benefit you may be entitled to by using the government calculator.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What can I do if I can&#39;t pay my energy bill?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/498978b0-ebaf-11ee-9fdb-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 12:25:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/498978b0-ebaf-11ee-9fdb-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What can I do if I can&amp;rsquo;t pay my energy bill? Energy prices will fall in April, but many households will still struggle to pay their bills. Some will need to repay debt to suppliers and many will worry about future levels of financial support. For confidential support call the Samaritans in the UK on 08457 90 90 90, visit a local Samaritans branch or click here for details. From April, energy bills will fall by more than 12% for most people in England, Scotland and Wales.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which debts and bills should I pay first?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/9accd360-e881-11ee-94b2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 09:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/9accd360-e881-11ee-94b2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Which debts and bills should I pay first? 11 million adults in the UK struggle to pay their bills in January. This is a rise of 3. 1 million compared with 2022. Citizens Advice says you should work out how much you owe and who to pay.&#xA;There are what are known as priority debts and bills. If you do not pay them, you could lose your home or face court proceedings.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
