<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 11:54:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Veteran MP cleared of flouting Covid-19 rules</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/575a6c0c-ec3a-11ee-9367-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 11:54:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/575a6c0c-ec3a-11ee-9367-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Veteran MP cleared of flouting Covid-19 rules Sir Bernard Jenkin was alleged to have attended an event on the Parliamentary estate in December 2020. A report confirmed a WhatsApp invite to birthday drinks had been sent by his then-wife Baroness Jenkin. But it concluded the event was socially-distanced with &amp;ldquo;business and social elements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US guns pour into Haiti, fuelling surge in violence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/add36284-ec3d-11ee-b459-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 11:39:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/add36284-ec3d-11ee-b459-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>US guns pour into Haiti, fuelling surge in violence Haiti is a state out of action. Details of a presidential transitional council have still not been revealed. One of the challenges this council will have to face is the illegal trafficking of guns. The escalation in violence has sparked an exodus from the capital.&#xA;Most of the violence gripping Haiti is centred in the capital, Port-au-Prince. David had been living in Cap-Haitian for two years without his parents.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why some Tory MPs are stepping down</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/4efb9e92-ec3e-11ee-b8ee-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 08:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/4efb9e92-ec3e-11ee-b8ee-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Why some Tory MPs are stepping down 20% of Conservative MPs have announced they are jacking it in at the general election. 20% of Scottish National Party MPs have said the same. The figure is 8% for Labour MPs. The reasons for leaving the House of Commons are usually a mix of circumstance and psephology.&#xA;Robert Halfon has built up a sizeable majority in Harlow in Essex. Mr Heappey has acknowledged that &amp;ldquo;a great deal has changed in my life over the last few years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do I know if my smart meter is broken?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/5e53f3b8-ec42-11ee-8bcf-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 15:17:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/5e53f3b8-ec42-11ee-8bcf-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How do I know if my smart meter is broken? Faulty meters can mean customers rely on estimated bills. Almost four million smart meters in Great Britain were not working at the end of 2023, according to government data. Smart meters measure how much gas and electricity you use. Some customers are paying too much and struggling to get money back.&#xA;Smart meters usually come with an in-home display, which can help you track how much energy you&amp;rsquo;re using.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do I know if my smart meter is broken?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f13ea034-ebab-11ee-a756-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 15:17:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f13ea034-ebab-11ee-a756-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How do I know if my smart meter is broken? Faulty meters can mean customers rely on estimated bills. Almost four million smart meters in Great Britain were not working at the end of 2023, according to government data. Smart meters measure how much gas and electricity you use. Some customers are paying too much and struggling to get money back.&#xA;Smart meters usually come with an in-home display, which can help you track how much energy you&amp;rsquo;re using.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kate rumours linked to Russian disinformation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b8d122da-eba6-11ee-8f05-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 15:12:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b8d122da-eba6-11ee-8f05-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Kate rumours linked to Russian disinformation Security researchers believe a Russia-based disinformation group amplified and added to the frenzy of social media conspiracies about the Princess of Wales&amp;rsquo; health. The accounts involved were also spreading content opposing France&amp;rsquo;s backing for Ukraine, suggesting a wider international context for the royal rumours. Royal hashtags were shared billions of times across a range of social media platforms. The BBC had previously tracked down amateur sleuths and real social media users who started and drove speculation and conspiracy theories.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ferguson boss sacked as more ferry delays &#39;likely&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/098e3b90-ebb1-11ee-b2d3-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 14:46:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/098e3b90-ebb1-11ee-b2d3-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Ferguson boss sacked as more ferry delays &amp;rsquo;likely&#39; Chief executive David Tydeman&amp;rsquo;s contract was terminated by Ferguson Marine. The board attempt to ensure the company&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;long-term future. The company is building two delayed and over-budget CalMac ferries. The first of the two ferries is due to be completed by the end of the year.&#xA;Mr Tydeman joined the Port Glasgow shipyard in 2022. The exact reasons for his departure have not been revealed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19th Century law fires up anti-abortion push</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/91b957f8-ebab-11ee-855e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/91b957f8-ebab-11ee-855e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>19th Century law fires up anti-abortion push US anti-abortion activists, including allies of Donald Trump, have a strategy to ban abortion nationwide. It hinges on Mr Trump&amp;rsquo;s re-election in November and the use of a little-known 19th Century law. In June 2022, those appointees helped overturn Roe v Wade, rescinding the nationwide right to abortion. The American public has shown consistent support for abortion access, even in conservative states.&#xA;The movement&amp;rsquo;s ultimate goal - a federal abortion ban - has remained out of reach, a near-impossibility in a divided Congress.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Hong Kong&#39;s days as a global business hub over?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/51b5df12-ea9f-11ee-b917-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:22:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/51b5df12-ea9f-11ee-b917-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Are Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s days as a global business hub over? Authorities say it will protect the city and ensure stability. Critics are alarmed it will silence all dissent with its closed-door trials. It comes at a time when Beijing&amp;rsquo;s iron grip and US-China tensions were already driving away foreign investors who now have an &amp;ldquo;anywhere but China&amp;rdquo;&amp;quot; policy. The emphasis on national security and the danger posed by &amp;ldquo;foreign forces&amp;rsquo; raises the stakes for foreign capital and businesses operating in the city.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life sentence for man who murdered couple with fentanyl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/8d838856-e873-11ee-8f50-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 12:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/8d838856-e873-11ee-8f50-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Life sentence for man who murdered couple with fentanyl Stephen Baxter, 61, and his wife Carol, 64, were found dead at their home in West Mersea, Essex, in April 2023. Luke DWit, 34, used fake identities to manipulate the couple before he laced their medication with the drug, a trial at Chelmsford Crown Court heard. Describing the moment she found them dead, she said: #34;I have never known an emotional pain to physically hurt so much.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gething confirmed as Wales&#39; new first minister</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/835978f4-e6f2-11ee-b54c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 18:48:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/835978f4-e6f2-11ee-b54c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Gething confirmed as Wales&amp;rsquo; new first minister Vaughan Gething is the first black leader of a national government in Europe. He was backed by 27 Senedd members, Tory Andrew RT Davies had 13 votes and Plaid Cymru#39;s Rhun ap Iorwerth 11. His name now goes to the King for approval. Vaughan Gething, who represents Cardiff South and Penarth, narrowly won the Labour leadership election.&#xA;He was congratulated by the prime minister in the Commons on Wednesday, and spoke to Rishi Sunak later on Wednesday afternoon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pain, anger and disquiet as new Welsh first minister takes the stage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/5f89d64a-e6f6-11ee-8f77-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 18:48:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/5f89d64a-e6f6-11ee-8f77-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Pain, anger and disquiet as new Welsh first minister takes the stage Vaughan Gething is the first black leader of a national government in Europe. He was backed by 27 Senedd members, Tory Andrew RT Davies had 13 votes and Plaid Cymru#39;s Rhun ap Iorwerth 11. He will succeed Mark Drakeford who bowed out with an emotional speech on Tuesday. Mr Gething said he wanted to promote #34;kinder, more effective politics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man murdered couple with fentanyl after re-writing will</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/fbc67586-e6f1-11ee-9d02-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 15:48:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/fbc67586-e6f1-11ee-9d02-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Man murdered couple with fentanyl after re-writing will Stephen Baxter, 61, and his wife Carol, 64, were found dead at their home in West Mersea, Essex, in April 2023.Luke D;Wit, 34, had rewritten the couple’s will so he could seize control of their business after their deaths, Chelmsford Crown Court heard.He will be sentenced later.A bag containing both opened and unopened fentanyl patches was found.&#xA;Metal tacks, which police believe were the same ones found during a scan of Mrs Baxter;s stomach when she was alive, were also discovered in the bag.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnum-owner to cut jobs and split off ice cream</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/46104062-e5ea-11ee-9c0b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 09:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/46104062-e5ea-11ee-9c0b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Magnum-owner to cut jobs and split off ice cream Marmite and Dove soap-owner Unilever is to cut about 7,500 jobs worldwide. It is part of an extensive three-year cost-saving plan. The cuts are expected to take place in Europe, the U. S.&#xA;and the Middle East. Unilever said the shake-up would help it to #34;do fewer things better. The group also said it would split off its ice cream business which includes the Wall#39;s, Ben amp; Jerry and Magnum brands.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Badenoch dismisses speculation about ousting Sunak</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b67bc47e-e528-11ee-9440-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 11:55:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b67bc47e-e528-11ee-9440-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Badenoch dismisses speculation about ousting Sunak Business Secretary Kemi Badenoch says some MPs are speculating about ousting Rishi Sunak as prime minister. But she says this is only a small minority of MPs. It comes after a difficult week for the PM, with former Tory deputy chairman Lee Anderson defecting to Reform UK. Currently only two Tory MPs have publicly called for Mr Sunak to resign.&#xA;Sir Simon Clarke and Dame Andrea Jenkyns are among those calling for him to quit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Newly-built homes boarded up in Cornish village in planning stalemate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/0d2a1608-e52f-11ee-bc31-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 08:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/0d2a1608-e52f-11ee-bc31-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Newly-built homes boarded up in Cornish village in planning stalemate Bridge View claimed council delays and abnormal costs have left it unable to deliver 33 homes in Calstock. Cornwall Council said it was working with stakeholders to find a solution. A document published by the council in January 2024, stated there were 160 households on the waiting list for homes in the parish. The new homes at Bridge View were granted planning permission in 2018.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The WhatsApp group that saved trafficked women</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/cbb90e4a-e52e-11ee-87b2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/cbb90e4a-e52e-11ee-87b2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The WhatsApp group that saved trafficked women BBC Africa Eye investigates how a WhatsApp group helped save more than 50 Malawian women trafficked to Oman to work in slave-like conditions. WARNING: Some people may find details in this story distressing. A 32-year-old woman breaks down in tears as she relives the abuse she experienced when she found herself working as a maid in Oman. Malawi woman says she was forced to have anal sex by her boss.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Councils told to consider residents&#39; views on LTNs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ba46be60-e460-11ee-907c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 09:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ba46be60-e460-11ee-907c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Councils told to consider residents&amp;rsquo; views on LTNs Councils will have to consider local residents&amp;rsquo; views before introducing new low traffic neighbourhoods (LTNs)LTNs restrict vehicles from using some roads while prioritising other users such as cyclists and pedestrians. Labour accused ministers of trying todictate to local communities how they use their streets. draft statutory guidance is due to come into force this summer. Local authorities issue an average of 36,459 Penalty Charge Notices per scheme.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>McDonald&#39;s resolves IT issue for customers in UK</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/40a0b5d6-e2ce-11ee-b9f7-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 12:44:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/40a0b5d6-e2ce-11ee-b9f7-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>McDonald&amp;rsquo;s resolves IT issue for customers in UK Customers in Japan, Australia, New Zealand, Germany and Austria were also unable to order food owing to a series of IT issues. The issue has now been resolved in the UK and Ireland, the company said in a statement. It is unclear whether the problem has been resolved elsewhere. Downdetector, a system used to monitor IT problems in businesses, noted a spike in issues with the McDonald#39;s UK app from around 05:00 GMT on Friday.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NI &#39;back in business&#39; Murphy tells US investors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a7a76be0-e2dc-11ee-ab98-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 10:03:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a7a76be0-e2dc-11ee-ab98-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>NI &amp;lsquo;back in business&amp;rsquo; Murphy tells US investors Political stability means Northern Ireland is #34;back in business, Conor Murphy has been telling potential American investors. Murphy: &amp;ldquo;We are a nation of entrepreneurs. We are a country of innovators. We have a long way to go, but we are on the right track&amp;rdquo; The economy minister is currently in the US ahead of St Patrick#39;s Day celebrations.&#xA;He said he has been highlighting the certainty around post-Brexit trading arrangements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Labour pledges to cap resale ticket prices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/76001a90-e220-11ee-8d00-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 14:58:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/76001a90-e220-11ee-8d00-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Labour pledges to cap resale ticket prices The party will clamp down on ticket touts who rip off music and sports fans. The arts will also be given a boost if Labour wins the next general election. The party will also offer tax relief on everything from film and television to video games and theatres. The Tories said the arts would suffer if Labour won the election.&#xA;Currently, the resale of football tickets is outlawed unless it is approved by the match organisers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How fast are prices rising in the UK?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/00d0df86-e534-11ee-bc51-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 09:59:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/00d0df86-e534-11ee-bc51-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How fast are prices rising in the UK? Prices in the UK are no longer rising as fast as wages, official figures show. However, inflation of 4% in January was still significantly above the Bank of England#39;s target. This means knock-on effects for interest rates could be significant. Core inflation was 5.&#xA;1% in January, according to the Bank of England. This excludes the price of energy, food, alcohol and tobacco.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How fast are prices rising in the UK?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1dd39b02-e5f5-11ee-84f2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 09:59:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1dd39b02-e5f5-11ee-84f2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How fast are prices rising in the UK? Prices in the UK are no longer rising as fast as wages, official figures show. However, inflation of 4% in January was still significantly above the Bank of England#39;s target. This means knock-on effects for interest rates could be significant. Core inflation was 5.&#xA;1% in January, according to the Bank of England. This excludes the price of energy, food, alcohol and tobacco.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How fast are prices rising in the UK?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/da30ae84-e2da-11ee-94d4-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 09:59:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/da30ae84-e2da-11ee-94d4-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How fast are prices rising in the UK? Prices in the UK are no longer rising as fast as wages, official figures show. However, inflation of 4% in January was still significantly above the Bank of England#39;s target. This means knock-on effects for interest rates could be significant. Core inflation was 5.&#xA;1% in January, according to the Bank of England. This excludes the price of energy, food, alcohol and tobacco.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK to pay failed asylum seekers to move to Rwanda</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/9d829a44-e12f-11ee-a8c0-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 09:56:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/9d829a44-e12f-11ee-a8c0-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>UK to pay failed asylum seekers to move to Rwanda Failed asylum seekers are to be offered up to £3,000 to move to Rwanda. Scheme is understood to be a variation of an existing voluntary returns scheme. It will be open to anyone whose asylum claim has been rejected by the UK. In particular it is aimed at those who cannot return to their home countries.&#xA;The government is already trying to implement a separate scheme under which people deemed to have arrived illegally in the UK would be sent to Rwanda.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shoppers splashing out boosts economy in January</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/611101bc-e126-11ee-be60-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 09:53:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/611101bc-e126-11ee-be60-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Shoppers splashing out boosts economy in January UK economy grew by 0. 2%, official figures show, boosted by sales in shops and online and more construction activity. The services sector led the improvement, the Office for National Statistics said. This is an early estimate, but signals how the UK, which entered recession at the end of 2023, is faring.&#xA;The economy shrank by 0. 3% between October and December. It had already contracted between July and September.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bus services: &#39;They&#39;re good if they turn up&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/49f19e62-e12e-11ee-8ba7-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 09:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/49f19e62-e12e-11ee-8ba7-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Bus services: &amp;lsquo;They&amp;rsquo;re good if they turn up&amp;rsquo; Passenger watchdog Transport Focus asked people to rate 35,000 bus journeys across 34 local authorities. Overall, 80% were satisfied with their trips, but some areas scored much lower with punctuality and waiting times problems cited by many passengers. Charity Bus Users UK said cuts to services left many without bus access. Passengers least satisfied with their buses were in West Yorkshire, where service was rated at 73%.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is GDP and how does it affect me?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2977d978-e2da-11ee-848c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 08:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2977d978-e2da-11ee-848c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What is GDP and how does it affect me? GDP is an important tool for judging how well, or badly, an economy is doing. It lets the government work out how much it can afford to tax and spend. It also helps businesses decide whether to expand and hire more people. Latest figures show UK economy fell into recession at the end of 2023.&#xA;Most economists, politicians and businesses like to see GDP steadily rising.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is GDP and how does it affect me?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/5a4c02f0-e5f4-11ee-82cc-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 08:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/5a4c02f0-e5f4-11ee-82cc-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What is GDP and how does it affect me? GDP is an important tool for judging how well, or badly, an economy is doing. It lets the government work out how much it can afford to tax and spend. It also helps businesses decide whether to expand and hire more people. Latest figures show UK economy fell into recession at the end of 2023.&#xA;Most economists, politicians and businesses like to see GDP steadily rising.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is GDP and how does it affect me?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/c1b22162-e6f9-11ee-b07d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 08:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/c1b22162-e6f9-11ee-b07d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What is GDP and how does it affect me? GDP is an important tool for judging how well, or badly, an economy is doing. It lets the government work out how much it can afford to tax and spend. It also helps businesses decide whether to expand and hire more people. Latest figures show UK economy fell into recession at the end of 2023.&#xA;Most economists, politicians and businesses like to see GDP steadily rising.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why firms are bringing their manufacturing back home</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/56b66b1a-e12d-11ee-b95d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/56b66b1a-e12d-11ee-b95d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Why firms are bringing their manufacturing back home Reshoring is when a company decides to stop getting its manufacturing done overseas, such as in China, and instead returns the work to its home country. Chris Ball and Ian Whateley are the bosses of Shropshire-based Advanced Chemical Etching (Ace) Ace makes precision metal components for customers in the aerospace, automotive, electronics and telecoms sectors. More than half of UK manufacturers are now reshoring, according to a study.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How are the child benefit rules changing?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b2c931f0-e2d9-11ee-a9c7-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 14:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b2c931f0-e2d9-11ee-a9c7-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How are the child benefit rules changing? The government says the changes will help more than half a million families. Only one person can claim child benefit for a child. There is no limit to how many children you can claim for. Child benefit is usually paid into a nominated bank account every four weeks.&#xA;You can find out how much child benefit you may be entitled to by using the government calculator.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is a recession and how could it affect me?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/7ce5fbbc-e2da-11ee-b21e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 16:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/7ce5fbbc-e2da-11ee-b21e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What is a recession and how could it affect me? The Office for National Statistics publishes figures for the UK#39;s Gross Domestic Product. This is the value of all the goods and services the UK produces. The latest ONS figures show that the economy shrank 0. 3% between October and December 2023.&#xA;The Bank of England has since suggested that the downturn might already be over. UK economy grew by 0.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is a recession and how could it affect me?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/aff242d2-e5f4-11ee-a951-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 16:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/aff242d2-e5f4-11ee-a951-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What is a recession and how could it affect me? The Office for National Statistics publishes figures for the UK#39;s Gross Domestic Product. This is the value of all the goods and services the UK produces. The latest ONS figures show that the economy shrank 0. 3% between October and December 2023.&#xA;The Bank of England has since suggested that the downturn might already be over. UK economy grew by 0.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is a recession and how could it affect me?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/bcad18ba-e533-11ee-b776-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 16:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/bcad18ba-e533-11ee-b776-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What is a recession and how could it affect me? The Office for National Statistics publishes figures for the UK#39;s Gross Domestic Product. This is the value of all the goods and services the UK produces. The latest ONS figures show that the economy shrank 0. 3% between October and December 2023.&#xA;The Bank of England has since suggested that the downturn might already be over. UK economy grew by 0.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is a recession and how could it affect me?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f77793f4-e6f9-11ee-83d7-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 16:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f77793f4-e6f9-11ee-83d7-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What is a recession and how could it affect me? The Office for National Statistics publishes figures for the UK#39;s Gross Domestic Product. This is the value of all the goods and services the UK produces. The latest ONS figures show that the economy shrank 0. 3% between October and December 2023.&#xA;The Bank of England has since suggested that the downturn might already be over. UK economy grew by 0.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five tips when asking for a pay rise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1473d9ea-e5f6-11ee-b3f0-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 15:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1473d9ea-e5f6-11ee-b3f0-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Five tips when asking for a pay rise Last year saw waves of strikes, with tens of thousands of workers walking out. Many of these strikes have taken place in the public sector. Even if you do have a conversation with your manager there#39;s no guarantee that it will result in a pay rise. But there are ways to give yourself the best chance of success.&#xA;Jill Cotton, a career trends experts at jobs site Glassdoor, says scheduling a talk in advance will allow you and your boss time to prepare.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five tips when asking for a pay rise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/814fc35c-e534-11ee-b238-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 15:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/814fc35c-e534-11ee-b238-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Five tips when asking for a pay rise Last year saw waves of strikes, with tens of thousands of workers walking out. Many of these strikes have taken place in the public sector. Even if you do have a conversation with your manager there#39;s no guarantee that it will result in a pay rise. But there are ways to give yourself the best chance of success.&#xA;Jill Cotton, a career trends experts at jobs site Glassdoor, says scheduling a talk in advance will allow you and your boss time to prepare.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five tips when asking for a pay rise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/9cb19b44-e6fa-11ee-91f1-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 15:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/9cb19b44-e6fa-11ee-91f1-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Five tips when asking for a pay rise Last year saw waves of strikes, with tens of thousands of workers walking out. Many of these strikes have taken place in the public sector. Even if you do have a conversation with your manager there#39;s no guarantee that it will result in a pay rise. But there are ways to give yourself the best chance of success.&#xA;Jill Cotton, a career trends experts at jobs site Glassdoor, says scheduling a talk in advance will allow you and your boss time to prepare.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five tips when asking for a pay rise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a02fec3a-e2db-11ee-90a8-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 15:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a02fec3a-e2db-11ee-90a8-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Five tips when asking for a pay rise Last year saw waves of strikes, with tens of thousands of workers walking out. Many of these strikes have taken place in the public sector. Even if you do have a conversation with your manager there#39;s no guarantee that it will result in a pay rise. But there are ways to give yourself the best chance of success.&#xA;Jill Cotton, a career trends experts at jobs site Glassdoor, says scheduling a talk in advance will allow you and your boss time to prepare.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five tips when asking for a pay rise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b103e142-e132-11ee-8ecb-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 15:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b103e142-e132-11ee-8ecb-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Five tips when asking for a pay rise Last year saw waves of strikes, with tens of thousands of workers walking out. Many of these strikes have taken place in the public sector. Even if you do have a conversation with your manager there#39;s no guarantee that it will result in a pay rise. But there are ways to give yourself the best chance of success.&#xA;Jill Cotton, a career trends experts at jobs site Glassdoor, says scheduling a talk in advance will allow you and your boss time to prepare.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get a job: Six expert tips for finding work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/27d058b0-e132-11ee-b800-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 16:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/27d058b0-e132-11ee-b800-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How to get a job: Six expert tips for finding work Unemployment is close to its lowest rate since the 1970s. But there are about 8. 65 million people out of work. It may feel daunting to try and find a job at first so we spoke to some career experts to give you some tips.&#xA;There have been a lot of shifts in the workplace in recent years. Hybrid and flexible working means your job search can stretch a bit further, quite literally.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get a job: Six expert tips for finding work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/35efd884-e534-11ee-bb3a-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 16:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/35efd884-e534-11ee-bb3a-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How to get a job: Six expert tips for finding work Unemployment is close to its lowest rate since the 1970s. But there are about 8. 65 million people out of work. It may feel daunting to try and find a job at first so we spoke to some career experts to give you some tips.&#xA;There have been a lot of shifts in the workplace in recent years. Hybrid and flexible working means your job search can stretch a bit further, quite literally.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get a job: Six expert tips for finding work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/670fd992-e6fa-11ee-888c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 16:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/670fd992-e6fa-11ee-888c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How to get a job: Six expert tips for finding work Unemployment is close to its lowest rate since the 1970s. But there are about 8. 65 million people out of work. It may feel daunting to try and find a job at first so we spoke to some career experts to give you some tips.&#xA;There have been a lot of shifts in the workplace in recent years. Hybrid and flexible working means your job search can stretch a bit further, quite literally.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
