<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Automobile on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/automobile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Automobile on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:01:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/automobile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>European flying car technology sold to China</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/265ac948-ec40-11ee-ae96-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/265ac948-ec40-11ee-ae96-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>European flying car technology sold to China The AirCar flew for 35 minutes between two Slovakian airports in 2021. It took just over two minutes to transform from a car into an aircraft. The tech behind the flying car was originally developed and successfully test-flown in Europe, has been bought by a Chinese firm. Hebei Jianxin Flying Car Technology Company, headquartered in Cangzhou, has purchased exclusive rights to manufacture and use AirCar aircraft inside an undisclosed area.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>McDonald&#39;s resolves IT issue for customers in UK</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/40a0b5d6-e2ce-11ee-b9f7-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 12:44:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/40a0b5d6-e2ce-11ee-b9f7-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>McDonald&amp;rsquo;s resolves IT issue for customers in UK Customers in Japan, Australia, New Zealand, Germany and Austria were also unable to order food owing to a series of IT issues. The issue has now been resolved in the UK and Ireland, the company said in a statement. It is unclear whether the problem has been resolved elsewhere. Downdetector, a system used to monitor IT problems in businesses, noted a spike in issues with the McDonald#39;s UK app from around 05:00 GMT on Friday.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
