<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Entertainment on Five Minunte Reads</title>
    <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/categories/entertainment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Entertainment on Five Minunte Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 18:43:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://fiveminutesread.github.io/categories/entertainment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Constance Marten: I did nothing but show baby love</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/cfc5ced4-dcbd-11ee-b796-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 18:43:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/cfc5ced4-dcbd-11ee-b796-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Constance Marten: &amp;lsquo;I did nothing but show baby love&amp;rsquo; Constance Marten, 36, and partner Mark Gordon, 49, both deny the manslaughter by gross negligence of their daughter Victoria. Her body was found in a Lidl bag in a shed in Brighton on 1 March. Ms Marten and Mr Gordon had allegedly been living in a tent in wintry conditions. Ms Marten wept in the witness box as she gave evidence in her defence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netflix hits make Adam Sandler the best-paid actor</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/a4f6cdbc-dcc6-11ee-a62e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 11:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/a4f6cdbc-dcc6-11ee-a62e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Netflix hits make Adam Sandler the best-paid actor CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. Please share your best photos of the United States with CNN iReport.&#xA;Sandler&amp;rsquo;s success on Netflix contributed to his $73m (£57m) earnings, Forbes said. That put him above Barbie star Margot Robbie, who at 33 is the youngest person in the top 10 by a decade.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From slaps to snubs: 13 Oscar Moments</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/09be2734-dcc9-11ee-983d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/09be2734-dcc9-11ee-983d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>From slaps to snubs: 13 Oscar Moments CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firths wet shirt from Pride and Prejudice on sale</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/3c165042-daaa-11ee-8e6b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/3c165042-daaa-11ee-8e6b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Firth&amp;rsquo;s wet shirt from Pride and Prejudice on sale CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. Please share your best photos of the United States with CNN iReport.&#xA;The shirt was worn by Colin Firth in the 1995 adaptation of Pride and Prejudice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kate Middletons uncle joins Celebrity Big Brother</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/0d3a927c-dab1-11ee-b89a-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 23:08:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/0d3a927c-dab1-11ee-b89a-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Kate Middleton&amp;rsquo;s uncle joins Celebrity Big Brother Gary Goldsmith, uncle of Catherine, Princess of Wales, has entered the Celebrity Big Brother house. He said it is the one show he had previously said he would never do. X Factor judges Sharon Osbourne and Louis Walsh will also be in the house. They will be tasked with watching their fellow contestants and rating them.&#xA;The series started on Monday and is hosted by AJ Odudu and Will Best.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transparency tool launched by BBC Verify</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/d47edbfe-dab1-11ee-9d60-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 18:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/d47edbfe-dab1-11ee-9d60-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Transparency tool launched by BBC Verify CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I spent my 18th birthday wishing my missing mum would come home</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/f9d3655e-dab7-11ee-aa92-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 18:03:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/f9d3655e-dab7-11ee-aa92-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;I spent my 18th birthday wishing my missing mum would come home&amp;rsquo; Mother-of-three Khasha has been missing since October. She was last seen at the flat she shared with her partner in Edinburgh. Officers have searched a nearby canal and nearby woodland. Police say she was last in contact with her family in November.&#xA;For confidential support call the Samaritans in the UK on 08457 90 90 90, visit a local Samaritans branch or click here for details.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
