<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Entertainment on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/entertainment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Entertainment on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 12:41:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/entertainment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cockney Rebel singer Steve Harley dies at 73</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/315bb7f4-e460-11ee-b5f6-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 12:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/315bb7f4-e460-11ee-b5f6-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Cockney Rebel singer Steve Harley dies at 73 His best known song was Make Me Smile which went to number one in the charts in 1975. The musician had still been touring until recently, but cancelled dates to have treatment for cancer. Harley lived on the Essex-Suffolk border with his wife Dorothy, with whom he had two children. Harley was born in south London in 1951 and formed Cockney Rebel in the early 1970s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fans thrilled as Ed Sheeran sings in Punjabi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f6be9712-e462-11ee-83fa-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 10:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f6be9712-e462-11ee-83fa-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Fans thrilled as Ed Sheeran sings in Punjabi The Shape Of You singer invited Indian singer Diljit Dosanjh to perform with him on stage. Crowds went wild when the duo gave a rendition of DosanJh#39;s hit track Lover in Punjabi. One fan said it was #34;the crossover we never knew we needed&amp;rsquo; Diljit Dosanjh and Ed Sheeran have collaborated on a Punjabi song. The song, Hass Hass, was released last year in collaboration with Cheap Thrills singer Sia.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lenny Henry emotional ahead of his final Comic Relief</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/d832a2be-e2d4-11ee-9570-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/d832a2be-e2d4-11ee-9570-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Lenny Henry emotional ahead of his final Comic Relief Comedian co-founded the charity 39 years ago. Friday#39;s Red Nose Day broadcast will be his last as host. Sir Lenny Henry: &amp;ldquo;I think it needs new blood, and I#34;m definitely old blood&amp;rdquo; He says he is incredibly proud of what the charity has achieved. Sir Lenny will be joined by Maya Jama, David Tennant and Davina McCall.&#xA;A spoof movie adaptation of The Traitors will feature Suranne Jones.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meghan launches surprise new lifestyle brand</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/93b26cda-e2d6-11ee-bb42-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 19:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/93b26cda-e2d6-11ee-bb42-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Meghan launches surprise new lifestyle brand The Duchess of Sussex has launched a new Instagram account. The account is called American Riviera Orchard. There are few details about the new brand, which has a waiting list of 1,000. The Duchess has stepped back from official royal duties to focus on her own life.&#xA;trademark application filed for #34;American Riviera Orchard. The brand plans to sell home goods, such as decanters and kitchen linens.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The story of I Will Always Love You, 50 years on</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/0a22384a-e224-11ee-aaf1-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 11:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/0a22384a-e224-11ee-aaf1-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The story of I Will Always Love You, 50 years on Dolly Parton wrote Jolene and I Will Always Love You back to back in 1973. The first was a career-defining smash, synonymous with Parton alone. The second remains one of her lesser-known credits, despite soundtracking love and heartbreak for 50 years. Dolly Parton wrote I Will Always Love You on Tuesday.&#xA;One of the top-rated replies to the post was: #34;I never realised it was your song.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neil Young to rejoin Spotify after Joe Rogan row</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f7ccc196-e12a-11ee-914d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 09:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f7ccc196-e12a-11ee-914d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Neil Young to rejoin Spotify after Joe Rogan row Young told streaming giant to remove hits like Harvest Moon and Heart of Gold. The singer said his return did not reflect a reversal of his stance. Instead, the decision came after Rogan signed a $250m deal to make his podcast available on multiple platforms, rather than remaining a Spotify exclusive. Young said in January 2022 that Spotify represented 60% of his streaming revenue globally.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mel B on moving in with her mum after abusive marriage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/cab6b4ee-e127-11ee-abb1-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 05:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/cab6b4ee-e127-11ee-abb1-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Mel B on moving in with her mum after abusive marriage Melanie Brown left an abusive marriage after leaving the Spice Girls. She moved back to Leeds and moved into her mum#39;s bungalow. The singer, 48, says while she #34;is all about girl power, she was in a powerless situation after the abuse. Belafonte, a film producer, has repeatedly denied the claims against him made by the singer.&#xA;They reached a private settlement out of court in 2017, and their divorce was finalised a year later.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Half-sister&#39;s defamation case against Meghan Markle dismissed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/47456a70-e130-11ee-bfa9-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 05:15:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/47456a70-e130-11ee-bfa9-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Half-sister&amp;rsquo;s defamation case against Meghan Markle dismissed Samantha Markle was suing Meghan over comments she made in a Netflix documentary and an interview with Oprah Winfrey. Judge Charlene Edwards Honeywell found these comments were either opinions, substantially true, or did not plausibly defame Samantha. The case was dismissed with prejudice, meaning she will not be able to refile. The lawsuit also took issue with Meghan#39;s remarks on how close they were growing up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bridgerton star goes from screen to stage</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/fb4f6af2-e12b-11ee-a499-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 01:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/fb4f6af2-e12b-11ee-a499-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Bridgerton star goes from screen to stage Charithra Chandran stars as Edwina Sharma in Netflix hit Bridgerton. 27-year-old also appeared in spy thriller Alex Rider and How to Date Billy Walsh. Has a degree in Philosophy, Politics and Economics, but it wasn#39;t enough to pull her away. Her success was never guaranteed, and her family haven#39;t always been on board with her chosen profession, even though the signs were always there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hollywood stars lead the way at Olivier nominations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/84c6c95a-e074-11ee-ac35-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 12:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/84c6c95a-e074-11ee-ac35-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Hollywood stars lead the way at Olivier nominations Hollywood stars lead the nominations for this year&amp;rsquo;s Olivier Awards. Nicole Scherzinger, Sarah Snook and Sarah Jessica Parker all recognised. The Olivier Awards will take place in London on November 14. The nominations for the Olivier Awards are announced on Tuesday.&#xA;The Oliviers is seen as the most prestigious awards event in UK theatre. The hit musical Sunset Boulevard scooped 11 nods, including Scherzinger for best actress in a musical.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven of the best moments from the Oscars</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/575c2a0a-dfac-11ee-a5b3-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 04:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/575c2a0a-dfac-11ee-a5b3-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Seven of the best moments from the Oscars Ryan Gosling sang I&amp;rsquo;m Just Ken at the Oscars. The full-throated rendition of the hit was even better than we could have hoped for. Slash appeared to lend his talents for a guitar solo. The Oscars brought more than three hours of glamour and nudity.&#xA;The Kenergy was infectious - Gosling solicited energetic singalongs from the star-studded front row. There were even suggestions the choreography was a homage to Diamonds Are A Girl&amp;rsquo;s Best Friend.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top director makes Gaza statement in Oscars speech on night of protests</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/71197878-dfaf-11ee-8817-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 02:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/71197878-dfaf-11ee-8817-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Top director makes Gaza statement in Oscars speech on night of protests Protesters block traffic outside the Dolby Theatre in London. Around 1,000 people took part in the demonstration outside the venue. Celebrities, including Billie Eilish, also wore pins calling for a ceasefire. The Zone of Interest won the best international film award at the Oscars.&#xA;The German-language film focuses on the family of Auschwitz commandant Rudolf Höss. An estimated 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The outfits: Best actress Emma Stone and others show off classic styles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/eb426ee2-dfa6-11ee-b146-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 02:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/eb426ee2-dfa6-11ee-b146-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The outfits: Best actress Emma Stone and others show off classic styles Emma Stone was among the best-dressed in a custom Louis Vuitton pale mint peplum gown. Margot Robbie was controversially not nominated for her role in Barbie, but she was one of the fashion winners in a black sequined Versace gown. America Ferrera wore a shimmering pink gown in a tribute to Barbie. The singer won best song for her Barbie theme What Was I Made For?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Red Bull victorious but things anything but serene behind the scenes&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/135a6414-de7d-11ee-b8f3-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:14:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/135a6414-de7d-11ee-b8f3-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Red Bull victorious but things anything but serene behind the scenes&amp;rsquo; Red Bull driver Max Verstappen wins his 29th race in a row. The Dutchman has been in fine form since returning to Formula One in 2013. But he has been dogged by allegations of sexual misconduct. He has been accused of using a female masseuse as a &amp;lsquo;favourite&amp;rsquo; Red Bull has always been a secretive organisation that tightly controlled the flow of information to the outside world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winnie the Pooh slasher movie named worst film</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/06f9e7de-de47-11ee-9b37-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 11:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/06f9e7de-de47-11ee-9b37-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Winnie the Pooh slasher movie named worst film Winnie the Pooh: Blood and Honey wins five of the 10 categories. Sylvester Stallone &amp;rsquo;s Expend4bles also picked up two awards. The Razzies name and shame the year’s worst films. The organisers describe their awards as the &amp;ldquo;ugly cousin to the Oscars.&#xA;Rhys Frake-Waterfield, who won worst director, has announced a sequel. Pooh and Piglet, depicted in the film as blood-thirsty killers, also won worst on-screen couple.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barbie 2? &#39;We&#39;d love to,&#39; says Warner Bros boss</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/96fd87b6-de77-11ee-87ac-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 01:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/96fd87b6-de77-11ee-87ac-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Barbie 2? &amp;lsquo;We&amp;rsquo;d love to,&amp;rsquo; says Warner Bros boss The film took $1. 4bn (£1. 1bn) at the box office globally, making it the most successful movie of 2023. Warner Bros boss Pam Abdy said both parties were always talking about a follow-up.&#xA;Gerwig said she is open to the idea if she can find an undertow for the film. The Academy has worked to diversify its 10,000-strong membership in recent years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FF7 actress&#39;s nervous wait for fan reactions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/30d74bf0-de79-11ee-ba7b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 01:43:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/30d74bf0-de79-11ee-ba7b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>FF7 actress&amp;rsquo;s nervous wait for fan reactions Briana White plays Aerith Gainsborough in Final Fantasy 7 (FF7) Rebirth. The game is the second part of a trilogy that remakes the legendary, influential 1997 Japanese role-playing game (JRPG) Briana provides the English language voiceover for Aerith. Rebirth has been released last week and is packed with side activities and mini-games that can push the play time closer to 100 hours. Fans have been racing to get to the end of the game to see whether that departure from the original storyline does occur.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Oppenheimer story that won&#39;t win Oscars</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/cf15ce9c-de77-11ee-8c84-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 01:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/cf15ce9c-de77-11ee-8c84-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The Oppenheimer story that won&amp;rsquo;t win Oscars Tina Cordova lives in Albuquerque, about a two-hour drive from where the atomic bomb was developed. She is one of the &amp;ldquo;Downwinders,&amp;rdquo;&amp;quot; a term used to describe the communities who claim to have been affected by radiation from the Trinity Test. The test is the centrepiece of Christopher Nolan&amp;rsquo;s box office hit, Oppenheimer. It follows the physicist of the same name and his team of scientists and engineers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Brit up for three visual effects Oscars</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/0e710eb2-dee6-11ee-9826-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 01:20:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/0e710eb2-dee6-11ee-9826-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The Brit up for three visual effects Oscars It&amp;rsquo;s not every day you get nominated for an Oscar. The Oscar nominations were announced on Sunday. The ceremony will take place in Los Angeles on February 26. The Oscars will be held at the Dolby Theatre on February 28.&#xA;For more information on the Oscars, go to www. Oscars. com. Neil Corbould is recognised for his work on Mission Impossible: Dead Reckoning Part One, The Creator and Napoleon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TV star shaken after Jaguar brakes fail during drive</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/448510c0-dd88-11ee-a6b5-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 17:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/448510c0-dd88-11ee-a6b5-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>TV star shaken after Jaguar brakes fail during drive It is the second report of the brakes failing on this particular model while in motion. Earlier this week another I-Pace driver claimed to have found himself unable to brake on a motorway as the car accelerated. Jaguar Land Rover (JLR) said a full review is underway to determine the cause of this incident. Mr Phillips&amp;rsquo; experience happened on New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve 2023.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Day author David Nicholls: &#39;I&#39;m still in a daze&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/833b1e00-dd8c-11ee-94eb-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 11:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/833b1e00-dd8c-11ee-94eb-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>One Day author David Nicholls: &amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;m still in a daze&amp;rsquo; David Nicholls&amp;rsquo; debut novel Starter For Ten has been adapted by Netflix. The film is based on Nicholls &amp;rsquo;s novel One Day. Nicholls says he is still in a bit of a daze after One Day&amp;rsquo;s success. He says the reaction has been &amp;lsquo;really.&#xA;head-turning&amp;rsquo; Nicholls&amp;rsquo; bittersweet love story has sold six million copies since being published in 2009. The Netflix series, an instant hit with both viewers and critics, took things to another level.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constance Marten: I did nothing but show baby love</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/cfc5ced4-dcbd-11ee-b796-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 18:43:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/cfc5ced4-dcbd-11ee-b796-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Constance Marten: &amp;lsquo;I did nothing but show baby love&amp;rsquo; Constance Marten, 36, and partner Mark Gordon, 49, both deny the manslaughter by gross negligence of their daughter Victoria. Her body was found in a Lidl bag in a shed in Brighton on 1 March. Ms Marten and Mr Gordon had allegedly been living in a tent in wintry conditions. Ms Marten wept in the witness box as she gave evidence in her defence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kate Middletons uncle joins Celebrity Big Brother</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/0d3a927c-dab1-11ee-b89a-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 23:08:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/0d3a927c-dab1-11ee-b89a-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Kate Middleton&amp;rsquo;s uncle joins Celebrity Big Brother Gary Goldsmith, uncle of Catherine, Princess of Wales, has entered the Celebrity Big Brother house. He said it is the one show he had previously said he would never do. X Factor judges Sharon Osbourne and Louis Walsh will also be in the house. They will be tasked with watching their fellow contestants and rating them.&#xA;The series started on Monday and is hosted by AJ Odudu and Will Best.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I spent my 18th birthday wishing my missing mum would come home</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f9d3655e-dab7-11ee-aa92-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 18:03:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f9d3655e-dab7-11ee-aa92-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;I spent my 18th birthday wishing my missing mum would come home&amp;rsquo; Mother-of-three Khasha has been missing since October. She was last seen at the flat she shared with her partner in Edinburgh. Officers have searched a nearby canal and nearby woodland. Police say she was last in contact with her family in November.&#xA;For confidential support call the Samaritans in the UK on 08457 90 90 90, visit a local Samaritans branch or click here for details.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lily Gladstone: The actress who could make Oscars history</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/887554e4-dee5-11ee-b716-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:29:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/887554e4-dee5-11ee-b716-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Lily Gladstone: The actress who could make Oscars history The 37-year-old is the first Native American woman to ever be nominated for best actress at the Oscars. We will find out if she is also the first winner when the ceremony takes place in Los Angeles on 10 March. Gladstone is not a newcomer to acting - viewers may have seen her in TV series such as Billions and films including Certain Women.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
