<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science on Five Minunte Reads</title>
    <link>https://fiveminread.com/categories/science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science on Five Minunte Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 18:02:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://fiveminread.com/categories/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Oil and gas profits windfall tax extended until 2029</title>
      <link>https://fiveminread.com/post/950392ae-dbfa-11ee-b073-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 18:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminread.com/post/950392ae-dbfa-11ee-b073-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Oil and gas profits windfall tax extended until 2029 The 35% surcharge on profits due to high energy prices had been scheduled to end in March 2028. Scottish Conservative leader Douglas Ross said he would not support the legislation needed to pass the extension. The Energy Profits Levy (EPL) was introduced by Rishi Sunak when he was chancellor in May 2022. Energy Profits Levy extended to 2029, raising £1.&#xA;5bn for oil and gas firms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rahm criticises world rankings as LIV ends interest</title>
      <link>https://fiveminread.com/post/1753a45a-dbfc-11ee-bfc8-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 12:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminread.com/post/1753a45a-dbfc-11ee-bfc8-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Rahm criticises world rankings as LIV ends interest Masters champion Jon Rahm said the Official World Golf Ranking (OWGR) is not a good system. LIV Golf withdrew its application to join the OWGR in October. CEO Greg Norman told players it will not pursue its bid for world ranking points. Two-time major winner and world number three Rahm is among the players to have switched from the PGA Tour.&#xA;LIV Golf Hong Kong begins on Friday.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Medical leaders back rise in physician associates</title>
      <link>https://fiveminread.com/post/383bb538-daab-11ee-9500-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 02:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminread.com/post/383bb538-daab-11ee-9500-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Medical leaders back rise in physician associates NHS has 3,286 PAs, who assist healthcare teams and are not authorised to prescribe or request scans. British Medical Association (BMA) is concerned about a new law allowing the General Medical Council to regulate PAs. The doctors&amp;rsquo; union says it blurs the lines between doctors and PAs and could risk patient safety. Like PAs, AAs are healthcare professionals who work as part of a multidisciplinary team with supervision from a named senior doctor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Northern lights give spectacular surprise display across UK</title>
      <link>https://fiveminread.com/post/29388dba-dab3-11ee-bffd-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 08:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminread.com/post/29388dba-dab3-11ee-bffd-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Northern lights give spectacular surprise display across UK CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. Please share your best photos of the United States with CNN iReport.&#xA;Sudden spike in solar activity - which causes the lights - saw an aurora &amp;ldquo;red alert issued on Sunday evening.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
