<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 11:12:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Electricity upgrade plan includes miles of pylons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b9e1acdc-e5eb-11ee-a95c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 11:12:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b9e1acdc-e5eb-11ee-a95c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Electricity upgrade plan includes miles of pylons Some 4,000 miles of undersea cables and 1,000 power lines are needed. The investment would add between £20 to £30 a year to customer bills. The plans were written up by the National Grid, which runs the electricity network. The government said the ESO&amp;rsquo;s plans were preliminary and yet to pass a planning process.&#xA;The £58bn estimate is for work needed between 2030 and 2035.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Banksy confirms London tree mural is his own work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b4c166c4-e529-11ee-a516-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 12:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b4c166c4-e529-11ee-a516-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Banksy confirms London tree mural is his own work The tree mural appeared on Hornsey Road, in Finsbury Park, on Sunday morning. It shows green paint sprayed on a wall behind a cut-back tree to look like foliage, with a stencil of a person holding a pressure hose next to it. The elusive artist usually confirms his work on his website and social media, and on Monday he posted images of the artwork with no caption.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>M25 reopens eight hours ahead of schedule</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/7a944820-e530-11ee-b879-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 08:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/7a944820-e530-11ee-b879-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>M25 reopens eight hours ahead of schedule The five-mile stretch of the M25 was due to be closed until 06:00 on Monday. But it re-opened on Sunday, and some delays in both directions were reported. National Highways project lead Jonathan Wade said congestion wasn&amp;rsquo;t as dire as you might expect. Carriageway closures happened along and between junctions 10 and 11.&#xA;The works are part of a £317m upgrade to the motorway.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Women waiting 10 years for endometriosis diagnosis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2411c3e6-e536-11ee-a104-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 06:04:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2411c3e6-e536-11ee-a104-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Women waiting 10 years for endometriosis diagnosis It now takes almost a year more than before 2020 to be diagnosed. The wait in Wales is also the longest in the UK, according to Endometriosis UK. The Welsh government wants to cut the waiting list to a year by 2025. For confidential support call the Samaritans on 08457 90 90 90, visit a local Samaritans branch or see www.&#xA;samaritans. org. The disease causes tissue similar to the lining of the womb to build up in other organs, such as the ovaries or fallopian tubes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heat pumps too expensive, government warned</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/34a478c0-e52c-11ee-ad9f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:14:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/34a478c0-e52c-11ee-ad9f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Heat pumps too expensive, government warned Despite its target, only 55,000 heat pumps were sold in the UK in 2022. Sales must increase dramatically, said the UK#39;s spending watchdog. To meet UK climate change targets, the government wants to install 600,000 low-carbon heat pumps annually by 2028. Heating in UK homes produces 18% of the country#39;s greenhouse gas emissions.&#xA;Only 55,000 heat pumps were sold in the UK in 2022. National Audit Office (NAO) said ministers were optimistic to think that target could be reached by 2028.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boeing plane lands without panel in Oregon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/89ec50d4-e39a-11ee-a6fc-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 12:15:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/89ec50d4-e39a-11ee-a6fc-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Boeing plane lands without panel in Oregon A missing external panel on a Boeing plane was detected when it landed at an airport in the US state of Oregon on Friday. United Airlines says the missing panel was found when the plane landed at the airport in Oregon. The missing panel is believed to have been on the plane&amp;rsquo;s left wing. United flight 433 left San Francisco and landed in Medford, Oregon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sister&#39;s stem cells help woman fight leukaemia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b0e5e6f8-e3a6-11ee-8583-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 06:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b0e5e6f8-e3a6-11ee-8583-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Sister&amp;rsquo;s stem cells help woman fight leukaemia Lesley Calder was diagnosed with acute myeloid leukaemia in 2019. chemotherapy was unsuccessful and her only option was a stem cell transplant. Her three siblings came forward to be tested as stem cell donors. The chances of a sibling match are just 25% but Lesley was lucky.&#xA;Max was called on to donate his stem cells to a stranger last summer. Only 3% of the UK population is signed up to the stem cell donor register.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Macron went from dove to hawk on Russia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a77ace8e-e39d-11ee-8ef4-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 04:45:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a77ace8e-e39d-11ee-8ef4-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Why Macron went from dove to hawk on Russia What came over Emmanuel Macron to turn him from appeaser to warmonger in the matter of Russia and Ukraine? That is the question being asked in chancelleries across Europe, as the French president warms to his new role as the continent#39;s resister-in-chief to Vladimir Putin. How genuine is the new Macron line? Is his refusal to rule out sending troops to Ukraine just another of his surprises - testimony to his insatiable need to cut a diplomatic dash?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The &#39;insane&#39; plan to save the Arctic&#39;s sea-ice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/3be364f4-e39a-11ee-a07d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/3be364f4-e39a-11ee-a07d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;lsquo;insane&amp;rsquo; plan to save the Arctic&amp;rsquo;s sea-ice As sea-ice vanishes, the dark ocean surface can absorb more of the Sun#39;s energy, which accelerates warming. Parka-clad scientists watch saltwater pump out over the frozen ocean. Their goal? To slow global warming.&#xA;Back to Mail Online home. back to the page you came from. The ultimate goal of the Arctic experiment is to thicken enough sea-ice to slow or even reverse the melting already seen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alcaraz stung as bees swarm court at Indian Wells</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/75d9dcea-e2de-11ee-8121-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 06:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/75d9dcea-e2de-11ee-8121-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Alcaraz stung as bees swarm court at Indian Wells Umpire Mohamed Lahyani was forced to suspend play in the third game as the bees invaded the court in California. The match was delayed for one hour and 40 minutes before defending champion Alcaraz won 6-3 6-1. The Wimbledon champion said afterwards that it was the most unusual match he had ever played. The bees were particularly attracted to the spidercam - a TV camera which moves above the court on cables.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A ball of barnacles wins wildlife photo award</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/68684640-e2d0-11ee-814b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/68684640-e2d0-11ee-814b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>A ball of barnacles wins wildlife photo award The picture was chosen from more than 14,000 entries by both amateur and professional photographers. The photograph, which also won the Coast and Marine category, was taken by Ryan Stalker. The football was washed up in Dorset after making a huge ocean journey across the Atlantic. Photographers competed in different categories, here are the other winners.&#xA;This award is supported by the Royal Society for the Protection of Birds (RSPB) to encourage young people to get involved with nature.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World&#39;s largest trees are &#39;thriving in UK&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/43b9133c-e128-11ee-878d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 01:33:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/43b9133c-e128-11ee-878d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>World&amp;rsquo;s largest trees are &amp;rsquo;thriving in UK&#39; An estimated 500,000 trees are in the UK compared to 80,000 in California. In California they can reach 90m-high, but in UK the tallest is 54. 87m. But that#39;s because the introduced trees are still very young.&#xA;Giant redwoods were first brought to the UK by the Victorians. They were the ultimate botanical status symbol. Today, some form sweeping avenues while others stand in ones or twos.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Warning pet owners overpaying for medicine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2ab8964e-e076-11ee-bc38-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 10:52:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2ab8964e-e076-11ee-bc38-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Warning pet owners overpaying for medicine More than 80% of practice websites have no pricing information, watchdog says. It means owners may be overpaying for medicines or prescriptions. CMA has provisionally decided to launch a formal market investigation. If a formal investigation upholds its findings, it would give the CMA the power to compel companies to give it full set of information.&#xA;The vet industry is worth £2bn after pet ownership rose to two-thirds of UK households during the coronavirus pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vinyl records and air fryers added to inflation measure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/489a5fea-dfa8-11ee-b936-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 10:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/489a5fea-dfa8-11ee-b936-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Vinyl records and air fryers added to inflation measure Vinyl records have returned to the basket of goods used by the Office for National Statistics. Air fryers have also been added to the virtual basket in its annual review. But hand sanitiser, a must-have of the Covid years, has been taken out. Her album 1989 (Taylor&amp;rsquo;s Version) was the best-selling vinyl LP of last year.&#xA;UK sales of vinyl LPs hit their highest level since 1990, according to the BPI.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bodies of five skiers found in Swiss Alps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/3e159f50-dfb5-11ee-ac04-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 05:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/3e159f50-dfb5-11ee-ac04-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Bodies of five skiers found in Swiss Alps The group went missing near the 3,706m high Tete Blanche mountain. They had set off from Zermatt on a ski tour towards Arolla along the Swiss-Italian border. Five of the skiers were found at 21:20 local time (20:20 GMT) The group may have been overcome by the bad weather, rather than struck by an avalanche. The last signal from the group was recorded overnight.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Your pictures on the theme of &#39;speed&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f4754134-dee7-11ee-8ede-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 01:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f4754134-dee7-11ee-8ede-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Your pictures on the theme of &amp;lsquo;speed&amp;rsquo; We asked our readers to send in their best pictures on the theme of speed. Here is a selection of the photographs we received from around the world. The next theme is reflections and the deadline for entries is 19 March 2024. The pictures will be published later that week on the BBC News website.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New life springs from rescued Sycamore Gap tree</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6ea832ca-de45-11ee-91b2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 01:57:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6ea832ca-de45-11ee-91b2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>New life springs from rescued Sycamore Gap tree The Sycamore Gap tree was mysteriously cut down last year. Young twigs and seeds thrown to the ground were salvaged by the National Trust. BBC News saw the new shoots on a rare visit to the secret National Trust centre protecting the seedlings. Police are still investigating what happened in what they call a ‘deliberate act of vandalism’ High security greenhouse guards genetic copies of some of the UK&amp;rsquo;s most valuable plants and trees.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New life springs from rescued Sycamore Gap tree</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/fddcc51c-de74-11ee-a2b4-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 01:57:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/fddcc51c-de74-11ee-a2b4-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>New life springs from rescued Sycamore Gap tree The Sycamore Gap tree was mysteriously cut down last year. Young twigs and seeds thrown to the ground were salvaged by the National Trust. BBC News saw the new shoots on a rare visit to the secret National Trust centre protecting the seedlings. Police are still investigating what happened in what they call a ‘deliberate act of vandalism’ High security greenhouse guards genetic copies of some of the UK&amp;rsquo;s most valuable plants and trees.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MH370: The families haunted by one of aviation&#39;s greatest mysteries</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/664d10d6-dd8d-11ee-8f9e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 23:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/664d10d6-dd8d-11ee-8f9e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>MH370: The families haunted by one of aviation&amp;rsquo;s greatest mysteries Li Eryou&amp;rsquo;s son Yanlin was on board Malaysia Airlines flight MH370. The Boeing 777, carrying 227 passengers and 12 crew members, disappeared on 8 March 2014. Mr Li and his wife, Liu Shuangfeng - farmers from a village south of Beijing - have struggled to make sense of what happened. The biggest and most expensive search operation ever mounted lasted four years but failed to find any trace of the missing airliner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Budget leaves Labour seeking savings to fund pledges</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/9ce4b060-dcc3-11ee-9874-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 13:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/9ce4b060-dcc3-11ee-9874-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Budget leaves Labour seeking savings to fund pledges Labour now intends to pay for its NHS and school breakfast plans through future savings to public spending if it wins power. The party had planned to fund the flagship policies by replacing the UK&amp;rsquo;s current &amp;ldquo;non-dom&amp;rdquo;&amp;quot; tax regime. Labour had planned to raise an extra £2bn by replacing tax breaks for overseas workers. It had also set aside £1.&#xA;6bn to pay for more appointments in the NHS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Worlds earliest forest discovered near Butlins in Somerset</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a1dce8f4-dcc2-11ee-8bcf-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 12:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a1dce8f4-dcc2-11ee-8bcf-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>World&amp;rsquo;s earliest forest discovered near Butlin&amp;rsquo;s in Somerset Scientists have found what they believe to be the world&amp;rsquo;s earliest known fossilised forest in cliffs on the coast of South West England. Researchers from Cambridge and Cardiff Universities say they are the oldest fossilised trees ever found in Britain. The trees, known as calamophyton, resemble palm trees. Early trees helped shape landscapes and stabilised riverbanks and coastlines hundreds of millions of years ago.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What can I do if I cant pay my energy bill?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/e81dce40-dcc8-11ee-bf64-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 12:25:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/e81dce40-dcc8-11ee-bf64-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What can I do if I can&amp;rsquo;t pay my energy bill? Energy prices will fall in April, but many households will still struggle to pay their bills. Some will need to repay debt to suppliers and many will worry about future levels of financial support. For confidential support call the Samaritans in the UK on 08457 90 90 90, visit a local Samaritans branch or click here for details. From April, energy bills will fall by more than 12% for most people in England, Scotland and Wales.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Budget: Key points at a glance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1d629d06-dcc4-11ee-977f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 08:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1d629d06-dcc4-11ee-977f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Budget: Key points at a glance National Insurance, a payroll tax, cut by 2p in the pound for employees and the self-employed. Salary thresholds at which people start paying income tax and national insurance remain frozen. People will pay more tax as their incomes rise, a process called fiscal drag. New tax on vaping and an increase to the salary threshold for claiming child benefit.&#xA;National Insurance cut to £10,000, with £5,000 tax allowance for savers investing in UK-focused shares.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oil and gas profits windfall tax extended until 2029</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/950392ae-dbfa-11ee-b073-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 18:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/950392ae-dbfa-11ee-b073-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Oil and gas profits windfall tax extended until 2029 The 35% surcharge on profits due to high energy prices had been scheduled to end in March 2028. Scottish Conservative leader Douglas Ross said he would not support the legislation needed to pass the extension. The Energy Profits Levy (EPL) was introduced by Rishi Sunak when he was chancellor in May 2022. Energy Profits Levy extended to 2029, raising £1.&#xA;5bn for oil and gas firms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is happening to energy bills?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/37a0f000-dfb7-11ee-8ae5-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 15:29:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/37a0f000-dfb7-11ee-8ae5-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What is happening to energy bills? Ofgem sets the maximum price suppliers can charge households for each unit of gas and electricity they use. Gas prices will be capped at 6p per kilowatt hour (kWh), and electricity at 24p per kWh. The energy price cap is set every three months and covers 29 million households in England, Wales and Scotland. From April, an average household paying by direct debit for dual fuel (gas and electricity) will pay £1,690 a year, a drop of £238 from the previous cap.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is happening to energy bills?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/e5d880f0-e081-11ee-bc30-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 15:29:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/e5d880f0-e081-11ee-bc30-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What is happening to energy bills? Ofgem sets the maximum price suppliers can charge households for each unit of gas and electricity they use. Gas prices will be capped at 6p per kilowatt hour (kWh), and electricity at 24p per kWh. The energy price cap is set every three months and covers 29 million households in England, Wales and Scotland. From April, an average household paying by direct debit for dual fuel (gas and electricity) will pay £1,690 a year, a drop of £238 from the previous cap.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rahm criticises world rankings as LIV ends interest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1753a45a-dbfc-11ee-bfc8-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 12:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1753a45a-dbfc-11ee-bfc8-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Rahm criticises world rankings as LIV ends interest Masters champion Jon Rahm said the Official World Golf Ranking (OWGR) is not a good system. LIV Golf withdrew its application to join the OWGR in October. CEO Greg Norman told players it will not pursue its bid for world ranking points. Two-time major winner and world number three Rahm is among the players to have switched from the PGA Tour.&#xA;LIV Golf Hong Kong begins on Friday.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Medical leaders back rise in physician associates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/383bb538-daab-11ee-9500-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 02:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/383bb538-daab-11ee-9500-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Medical leaders back rise in physician associates NHS has 3,286 PAs, who assist healthcare teams and are not authorised to prescribe or request scans. British Medical Association (BMA) is concerned about a new law allowing the General Medical Council to regulate PAs. The doctors&amp;rsquo; union says it blurs the lines between doctors and PAs and could risk patient safety. Like PAs, AAs are healthcare professionals who work as part of a multidisciplinary team with supervision from a named senior doctor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get a job: Six expert tips for finding work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/27d058b0-e132-11ee-b800-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 16:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/27d058b0-e132-11ee-b800-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How to get a job: Six expert tips for finding work Unemployment is close to its lowest rate since the 1970s. But there are about 8. 65 million people out of work. It may feel daunting to try and find a job at first so we spoke to some career experts to give you some tips.&#xA;There have been a lot of shifts in the workplace in recent years. Hybrid and flexible working means your job search can stretch a bit further, quite literally.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to get a job: Six expert tips for finding work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/35efd884-e534-11ee-bb3a-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 16:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/35efd884-e534-11ee-bb3a-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How to get a job: Six expert tips for finding work Unemployment is close to its lowest rate since the 1970s. But there are about 8. 65 million people out of work. It may feel daunting to try and find a job at first so we spoke to some career experts to give you some tips.&#xA;There have been a lot of shifts in the workplace in recent years. Hybrid and flexible working means your job search can stretch a bit further, quite literally.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
