<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Russia on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/russia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Russia on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 14:28:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/russia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Did Russia ignore US &#39;extremist&#39; attacks warning?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/24b1cc1c-e935-11ee-8eb4-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 14:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/24b1cc1c-e935-11ee-8eb4-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Did Russia ignore US &amp;rsquo;extremist&amp;rsquo; attacks warning? Washington issued a warning to its own citizens on 7 March. It warned of reports that extremists had plans to target large gatherings. It specifically mentioned concerts and advised Americans in the city to avoid large gatherings over the coming 48 hours. It seems clear Washington had some kind of intelligence and that it related to Islamic State.&#xA;The US government also shared this information with Russian authorities in accordance with its long-standing #39;duty to warn policy, a US official said.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bullets, a crush and panic: Moscow concert that became a massacre</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/85c3d3c8-e92c-11ee-8e97-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 12:42:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/85c3d3c8-e92c-11ee-8e97-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Bullets, a crush and panic: Moscow concert that became a massacre Some 6,200 tickets had been sold for the concert, but security outside the entrance quickly melted away. The gunmen had just walked across the concourse outside the theatre, opening fire at random, killing and wounding members of the public as they walked in. WARNING: Some of the details of this story are graphic. Four suspects arrested, says Russia - follow events LIVE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Gaza war is testing the limits of US diplomacy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/be7d94ce-e93b-11ee-8987-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 03:19:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/be7d94ce-e93b-11ee-8987-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How Gaza war is testing the limits of US diplomacy US Secretary of State Antony Blinken met with Israeli protesters in Tel Aviv. He was seen gripping the hands of protesters calling for a deal to release the hostages held by Hamas. It was a strong message from America#39;s top diplomat to both the Israeli public and its prime minister. The US has been putting pressure on Israel to act on the crisis in Gaza.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Million in Ukraine lose power after Russian attack</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/64527788-e875-11ee-9921-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 14:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/64527788-e875-11ee-9921-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Million in Ukraine lose power after Russian attack There is no electricity in the second-largest city of Kharkiv. More than 53,000 households in Odesa are without power. At least five people have been reported killed and 14 wounded. Russia said it was revenge for recent Ukrainian attacks on Russian territory.&#xA;The DniproHES in Zaporizhzhia was hit eight times according to Ukrainian officials. Video footage appeared to show the dam on fire, but authorities say there is no threat of an imminent breach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UFC star squares faith with a career in the octagon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/143f1d5e-e87b-11ee-af5d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 11:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/143f1d5e-e87b-11ee-af5d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>UFC star squares faith with a career in the octagon Muhammad Mokaev is one of the biggest names in UFC right now. The 23-year-old is one step closer to a UFC flyweight title opportunity. He talks to BBC Asian Network about the importance of his faith during Ramadan, a month of spiritual reflection for Muslims. Mokaev arrived from Russia aged 12, shortly after his mum died.&#xA;He first lived in a refugee shelter in Liverpool, before moving to Wigan.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two arrested in Russia&#39;s first LGBTQ&#43; extremism case</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f78a61b6-e6f7-11ee-b0ed-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 18:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f78a61b6-e6f7-11ee-b0ed-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Two arrested in Russia&amp;rsquo;s first LGBTQ+ extremism case Two employees of an LGBTQ+ club in the Russian city of Orenburg arrested. Art director of the club, Alexander Klimov, and administrator Diana Kamilyanova will remain in custody until 18 May. It is the first criminal case of its kind since Russia#39;s Supreme Court outlawed the so-called international LGBT movement last November. Police raid gay club in Orenburg, Russia.&#xA;Items confiscated included a female stage costume, five female wigs, and fake female breasts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electricity upgrade plan includes miles of pylons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b9e1acdc-e5eb-11ee-a95c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 11:12:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b9e1acdc-e5eb-11ee-a95c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Electricity upgrade plan includes miles of pylons Some 4,000 miles of undersea cables and 1,000 power lines are needed. The investment would add between £20 to £30 a year to customer bills. The plans were written up by the National Grid, which runs the electricity network. The government said the ESO&amp;rsquo;s plans were preliminary and yet to pass a planning process.&#xA;The £58bn estimate is for work needed between 2030 and 2035.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Putin&#39;s fifth term as Russian leader was never in doubt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/900399c0-e52d-11ee-909f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 18:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/900399c0-e52d-11ee-909f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Why Putin&amp;rsquo;s fifth term as Russian leader was never in doubt Kremlin ensured Putin had no credible opponent so it was always certain he would secure a fifth term by a landslide. It was at a grand military awards ceremony last December that Vladimir Putin, 71, told the Russian public he would stand for the presidency again. He said: &amp;ldquo;Now is the time for making decisions. I will be running for the post of president of the Russian Federation&amp;rdquo; Kremlin rarely leaves its choreography to chance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia says it repelled multiple drone attacks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/379bb48e-e46a-11ee-985b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 10:36:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/379bb48e-e46a-11ee-985b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Russia says it repelled multiple drone attacks Russia&amp;rsquo;s defence ministry says its forces have destroyed dozens of drones. The biggest attack happened in the southern Russian region of Krasnodar. The attacks come as Russia holds a general election in which President Vladimir Putin is guaranteed to win. In Ukraine, officials reported an overnight barrage of Russian drones and missiles on the port city of Odesa.&#xA;Five drones were downed in different areas while flying towards the capital.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin: From Russia&#39;s KGB to a presidency defined by war</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1c0c896e-e465-11ee-8bba-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 10:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1c0c896e-e465-11ee-8bba-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Putin: From Russia&amp;rsquo;s KGB to a presidency defined by war Vladimir Putin has been in power since 2000, longer than any Kremlin leader since Soviet dictator Joseph Stalin. As he prepares for a fifth term as president, aged 71, there is little to stop him staying on, if he wants, until 2036. It was almost by accident that this little-known, former KGB man was hand-picked for the Kremlin. He often justifies his actions with an outlandish perception of history and a keen resentment of Nato.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shapps abandoned Odesa trip over security - MoD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/65e90934-e46c-11ee-b351-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 06:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/65e90934-e46c-11ee-b351-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Shapps abandoned Odesa trip over security - MoD The defence secretary had to scrap his visit to Odesa last week. UK intelligence reportedly warned Russia had become aware of his travel plans. Mr Shapps was due to travel to the city a day after a missile hit the city. Five people were killed in the strike, Ukrainian authorities said.&#xA;Mr Shapps was due to meet Ukrainian leader Volodymyr Zelensky in Kyiv.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Macron went from dove to hawk on Russia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a77ace8e-e39d-11ee-8ef4-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 04:45:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a77ace8e-e39d-11ee-8ef4-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Why Macron went from dove to hawk on Russia What came over Emmanuel Macron to turn him from appeaser to warmonger in the matter of Russia and Ukraine? That is the question being asked in chancelleries across Europe, as the French president warms to his new role as the continent#39;s resister-in-chief to Vladimir Putin. How genuine is the new Macron line? Is his refusal to rule out sending troops to Ukraine just another of his surprises - testimony to his insatiable need to cut a diplomatic dash?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secret classes to counter Russian brainwashing in occupied Ukraine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/df8761b8-e39b-11ee-9c47-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:10:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/df8761b8-e39b-11ee-9c47-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Secret classes to counter Russian brainwashing in occupied Ukraine Nataliia (not her real name) was forced from her home in Melitopol. She felt she would be more useful in territory still controlled by Ukraine. Nataliia didn#39;t just leave her home and relatives behind, she also surrendered her profession, giving up her job of 20 years as a teacher. Ukrainian children are educated in territories occupied by Russia.&#xA;They are taught that Ukraine isn#39;t a real country.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steve Rosenberg on Russia&#39;s stage-managed election</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f4c249fa-e222-11ee-94d2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 03:37:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f4c249fa-e222-11ee-94d2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Steve Rosenberg on Russia&amp;rsquo;s stage-managed election There is almost no sign of the presidential election coming up this weekend. The absence of election preparations mirrors the absence of drama surrounding a stage-managed event. The other thing you can#39;t help noticing in Borovsk is the street art. Much of it has been created by street artist Vladimir Ovchinnikov.&#xA;Vladimir uses his art to comment on the present, but to shine a light on Russia#39;s dark past - the repressions of the Stalin era.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How fast are prices rising in the UK?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/00d0df86-e534-11ee-bc51-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 09:59:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/00d0df86-e534-11ee-bc51-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How fast are prices rising in the UK? Prices in the UK are no longer rising as fast as wages, official figures show. However, inflation of 4% in January was still significantly above the Bank of England#39;s target. This means knock-on effects for interest rates could be significant. Core inflation was 5.&#xA;1% in January, according to the Bank of England. This excludes the price of energy, food, alcohol and tobacco.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How fast are prices rising in the UK?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1dd39b02-e5f5-11ee-84f2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 09:59:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1dd39b02-e5f5-11ee-84f2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How fast are prices rising in the UK? Prices in the UK are no longer rising as fast as wages, official figures show. However, inflation of 4% in January was still significantly above the Bank of England#39;s target. This means knock-on effects for interest rates could be significant. Core inflation was 5.&#xA;1% in January, according to the Bank of England. This excludes the price of energy, food, alcohol and tobacco.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How fast are prices rising in the UK?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/da30ae84-e2da-11ee-94d4-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 09:59:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/da30ae84-e2da-11ee-94d4-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How fast are prices rising in the UK? Prices in the UK are no longer rising as fast as wages, official figures show. However, inflation of 4% in January was still significantly above the Bank of England#39;s target. This means knock-on effects for interest rates could be significant. Core inflation was 5.&#xA;1% in January, according to the Bank of England. This excludes the price of energy, food, alcohol and tobacco.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navalny ally blames Putin&#39;s men for hammer attack</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/0cbf210c-e130-11ee-8dec-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 08:35:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/0cbf210c-e130-11ee-8dec-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Navalny ally blames Putin&amp;rsquo;s men for hammer attack Leonid Volkov said his arm was broken and his leg hit 15 times with a hammer. The alleged assailant is unknown, but Mr Volkov says it was politically motivated. Police have begun an investigation into the attack in Vilnius, Lithuania. Another Navalny team member posted pictures on social media showing Mr Volakov with a bloodied lower left leg.&#xA;Mr Volkov, 43, has lived outside Russia for some years for his own safety.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Occupied Ukraine forced to vote in Putin&#39;s election</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/8a6c0dda-e12c-11ee-b050-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 01:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/8a6c0dda-e12c-11ee-b050-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Occupied Ukraine forced to vote in Putin&amp;rsquo;s election Moscow has launched a wide-ranging campaign telling residents of occupied parts of Ukraine to vote in Russia#39;s presidential election. For the first time, the national vote is taking place over three days (15-17 March), but additional early voting has already begun in four Ukrainian regions: Zaporizhzhia, Kherson, Donetsk and Luhansk. Voting normally starts early in remote parts of Russia, but the procedure has been extended to the four partially occupied regions of Ukraine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine-based groups claim raids into Russia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/17bf968e-e074-11ee-998b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 12:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/17bf968e-e074-11ee-998b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Ukraine-based groups claim raids into Russia The Freedom of Russia Legion (FRL) and Siberian Battalion (SB) posted videos purportedly showing their fighters in Russia. The SVR and an exiled Russian politician claimed two villages were now in control of &amp;ldquo;liberation forces. Ukraine&amp;rsquo;s military denied any involvement in Tuesday&amp;rsquo;s cross-border raids. The Il-76 military-transport plane crashed shortly after take-off.&#xA;The ministry said an engine fire caused the crash. Russia said Ukraine had launched 25 drones on targets across Russia, but the attack was thwarted.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ukrainian sea drones hunting Russian warships</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/72fee956-e078-11ee-9823-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 06:16:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/72fee956-e078-11ee-9823-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The Ukrainian sea drones hunting Russian warships Drones have been used to target Russian ships in the past. But the latest attack was the first time they have been seen by the public. The attack was carried out by a group known as the Group-13. It is believed to be the first of its kind in the world.&#xA;The Magura V5, named after a Slavic goddess of war, looks like a small motorboat with a flat surface instead of passenger seats.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How fast are prices rising in the UK?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/90d3da0a-e081-11ee-9978-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 10:20:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/90d3da0a-e081-11ee-9978-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How fast are prices rising in the UK? Prices in the UK are no longer rising as fast as wages, official figures show. However, inflation of 4% in January was still significantly above the Bank of England&amp;rsquo;s target. This means knock-on effects for interest rates could be significant. Core inflation was 5.&#xA;1% in January, according to the Bank of England. This excludes the price of energy, food, alcohol and tobacco.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Papers:  Gove&#39;s extremism warning and Johnson in trip to Venezuela</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1eb786ba-dee7-11ee-a16e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 06:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1eb786ba-dee7-11ee-a16e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The Papers: Gove&amp;rsquo;s extremism warning and Johnson in trip to Venezuela The Sunday Times reports that Boris Johnson flew to Venezuela last month for what it describes as secret talks. There has been concern in western diplomatic circles that Nicolás Maduro might supply weapons or other military support to Russia. Michael Gove warns that some pro-Palestinian events have been organised by extremist organisations. The Mail on Sunday leads on a claim by Earl Spencer in his memoir that he was sexually abused as an 11-year-old by a female member of staff at his boarding school.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Johnson flew to Venezuela for unofficial talks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/13fd299c-dee1-11ee-a2b1-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 04:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/13fd299c-dee1-11ee-a2b1-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Johnson flew to Venezuela for unofficial talks Boris Johnson flew to Venezuela last month for a private meeting with the country&amp;rsquo;s President Nicolás Maduro. The talks were unofficial and not paid for by the UK government, the BBC has been told. It is not clear who initiated or paid for the visit. Mr Maduro has ruled Venezuela since 2013.&#xA;The UK has an embassy in the country but no ambassador, though it does have a charge d&amp;lsquo;affaires, Colin Dick.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Europe doing enough to help Ukraine?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/54394ce8-dee6-11ee-8c15-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/54394ce8-dee6-11ee-8c15-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Is Europe doing enough to help Ukraine? Yulia Navalnaya told MEPs: &amp;ldquo;If you really want to defeat Putin, you have to become an innovator&amp;rdquo; A $60bn (£47bn) package of US military support for Ukraine is held up in the House of Representatives. On the battlefield, Russian forces are beginning to make gains against their less well armed opponents. Two years on from Russia&amp;rsquo;s full-scale invasion of Ukraine, European capitals have largely maintained their political backing for Kyiv.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Europe doing enough to help Ukraine?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/bd90c2ea-dfb1-11ee-bb68-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/bd90c2ea-dfb1-11ee-bb68-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Is Europe doing enough to help Ukraine? Yulia Navalnaya told MEPs: &amp;ldquo;If you really want to defeat Putin, you have to become an innovator&amp;rdquo; A $60bn (£47bn) package of US military support for Ukraine is held up in the House of Representatives. On the battlefield, Russian forces are beginning to make gains against their less well armed opponents. Two years on from Russia&amp;rsquo;s full-scale invasion of Ukraine, European capitals have largely maintained their political backing for Kyiv.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What the world made of Biden&#39;s big speech</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/25a86b38-dd89-11ee-883c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 16:21:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/25a86b38-dd89-11ee-883c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What the world made of Biden&amp;rsquo;s big speech Biden started his State of the Union address by talking about Ukraine. He then went on to talk about the Israel-Hamas war and the China-U. S. trade deal.&#xA;He ended the speech with a reference to the &amp;lsquo;greatest generation&amp;rsquo; of Americans. Biden draws election battle lines in fiery speech. He calls on Congress to unblock the bill that would release the funding Kyiv needs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swedes cheer end of long wait to join Nato</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/7f5930e8-dd8b-11ee-81ad-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 14:22:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/7f5930e8-dd8b-11ee-81ad-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Swedes cheer end of long wait to join Nato Sweden officially joined Nato following a document handover in Washington. A decade ago a majority of residents were against joining the multinational military alliance. Many Swedes say there is palpable relief that the wait to secure membership in the military alliance is finally over. As Stockholm commuters rushed to work in temperatures of -1C, few were in the mood for a detailed post-mortem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why does International Women&#39;s Day matter?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/4d6fc5fc-dd8a-11ee-9475-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 01:24:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/4d6fc5fc-dd8a-11ee-9475-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Why does International Women&amp;rsquo;s Day matter? International Women&amp;rsquo;s Day (IWD) grew out of the labour movement. The seeds were planted in 1908, when 15,000 women marched through New York City demanding shorter working hours, better pay and the right to vote. The idea to make it an international event came from Clara Zetkin, a communist activist. The 8 March date was chosen after Russian women demanded bread and peace during a war-time strike in 1917.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israel back in Eurovision 2024 after lyric change</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/3623b0e0-dcc0-11ee-99bc-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 19:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/3623b0e0-dcc0-11ee-99bc-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Israel back in Eurovision 2024 after lyric change Eden Golan will represent the country at the contest in Sweden this May. Israel will be allowed to compete at the Eurovision Song Contest 2024 after changing the lyrics to its song, organisers have confirmed. The country will take part in the contest for the first time in 2024. Israel&amp;rsquo;s public broadcaster agreed to amend the song, now titled Hurricane.&#xA;Original song, October Rain, was thought to reference the Hamas attacks of 7 October and had been barred for breaking rules on political neutrality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweden formally joins Nato military alliance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/92668b1c-dcbf-11ee-a08c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 19:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/92668b1c-dcbf-11ee-a08c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Sweden formally joins Nato military alliance Swedish Prime Minister Ulf Kristersson said that unity and solidarity would be Sweden&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;guiding lights. The handover of documents took place at a ceremony two years after Sweden applied to join the military alliance following Russia&amp;rsquo;s full-scale invasion of Ukraine. Nato Secretary-General Jens Stoltenberg posted on X that Sweden brings with it &amp;ldquo;capable armed forces and a first-class defence industry. Nato will continue to stand for freedom and democracy for generations to come, US President Joe Biden says.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump told to pay six-figure costs of firm he sued</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/776b23f6-dcc7-11ee-925e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 16:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/776b23f6-dcc7-11ee-925e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Trump told to pay six-figure costs of firm he sued Mrs Justice Steyn threw out the case against Orbis Business Intelligence. She found that Mr Trump&amp;rsquo;s compensation claim was &amp;ldquo;bound to fail. Mr Steele, who previously ran the Secret Intelligence Service#38;s Russia desk, was the author of the so-called Steele dossier. The dossier, made up of more than a dozen memos, was produced by Orbis in 2016.&#xA;Mrs Justice Steyn said Orbis has estimated its costs to be more than £600,000.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Close to the frontline in Ukraine, the tide of war is coming in fast</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ea1ad318-dcc4-11ee-a745-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ea1ad318-dcc4-11ee-a745-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Close to the frontline in Ukraine, the tide of war is coming in fast In February, Russia captured the strategic town of Avdiivka. Since then, the invaders have advanced further west, and taken several villages. Over 1. 2 million people - or two thirds of the population - have left the Ukrainian-controlled Donetsk region since Russia&amp;rsquo;s full scale invasion two years ago.&#xA;People in cities like Pokrovsk, Kostyantynivka and Kramatorsk are now facing a fast-approaching front line, and even occupation.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
