<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Drug on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/drug/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Drug on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 12:32:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/drug/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Parents killed baby when he should have been protected, report says</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ad1ec152-ec39-11ee-83aa-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 12:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ad1ec152-ec39-11ee-83aa-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Parents killed baby when he should have been protected, report says Finley Boden was murdered by his parents 39 days after being placed back into their care. Review found numerous missed opportunities, which may have prevented his death. Local child safeguarding practice review details key findings and makes a number of recommendations for future improvements. Stephen Boden and Shannon Marsden were jailed for murdering Finley.&#xA;Boden and Marsden were known drug users and Boden had already served time in prison for violent and threatening behaviour.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Care worker migrant surge &#39;should&#39;ve been obvious&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2318f72a-ebad-11ee-8b5a-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 16:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2318f72a-ebad-11ee-8b5a-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Care worker migrant surge &amp;lsquo;should&amp;rsquo;ve been obvious&amp;rsquo; The Home Office has a limited understanding of the social care system. It &amp;ldquo;should have been obvious that lots of migrants would arrive for jobs in care, the former borders watchdog has said. The Home Office says it has a ‘limited understanding’ of social care. David Neal says the immigration system has invited large numbers of low-skilled care workers into the UK.&#xA;His findings are in a report published after he was sacked.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leaked emails reveal child gender service concerns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/42b086b0-ebae-11ee-b842-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 02:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/42b086b0-ebae-11ee-b842-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Leaked emails reveal child gender service concerns Hospital executives voiced worry about the cancellation of appointments, patients lacking information and poor communication with the new services. The controversial Gender Identity Development Service (Gids), which is run by the Tavistock and Portman NHS Foundation Trust, is due to close later this week. NHS England insisted patients would have &amp;ldquo;continuity of care. The sole NHS gender identity service for children in England and Wales will close in 2020.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19th Century law fires up anti-abortion push</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/91b957f8-ebab-11ee-855e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/91b957f8-ebab-11ee-855e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>19th Century law fires up anti-abortion push US anti-abortion activists, including allies of Donald Trump, have a strategy to ban abortion nationwide. It hinges on Mr Trump&amp;rsquo;s re-election in November and the use of a little-known 19th Century law. In June 2022, those appointees helped overturn Roe v Wade, rescinding the nationwide right to abortion. The American public has shown consistent support for abortion access, even in conservative states.&#xA;The movement&amp;rsquo;s ultimate goal - a federal abortion ban - has remained out of reach, a near-impossibility in a divided Congress.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man who stabbed victim in neck jailed for 28 years</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ff6d56d4-e884-11ee-be04-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 13:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ff6d56d4-e884-11ee-be04-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Man who stabbed victim in neck jailed for 28 years James Smith, 36, of Llanelli, stabbed Ashley Sarsero, 26, in the neck. Smith was handed a life sentence and told he would serve a minimum of 28 years in jail before being eligible for parole. He was jailed at Swansea Crown Court. Steven Morgan, also 36, was sentenced to four-and-a-half years for helping Smith flee the scene.&#xA;The jury in the three-week trial heard Smith and Morgan had been invited into Mr Sarsero#39;s home in the Maestir area of Felinfoel by his mother.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life sentence for man who murdered couple with fentanyl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/8d838856-e873-11ee-8f50-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 12:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/8d838856-e873-11ee-8f50-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Life sentence for man who murdered couple with fentanyl Stephen Baxter, 61, and his wife Carol, 64, were found dead at their home in West Mersea, Essex, in April 2023. Luke DWit, 34, used fake identities to manipulate the couple before he laced their medication with the drug, a trial at Chelmsford Crown Court heard. Describing the moment she found them dead, she said: #34;I have never known an emotional pain to physically hurt so much.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
