<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Drug on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/drug/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Drug on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 13:47:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/drug/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Man who stabbed victim in neck jailed for 28 years</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ff6d56d4-e884-11ee-be04-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 13:47:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ff6d56d4-e884-11ee-be04-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Man who stabbed victim in neck jailed for 28 years James Smith, 36, of Llanelli, stabbed Ashley Sarsero, 26, in the neck. Smith was handed a life sentence and told he would serve a minimum of 28 years in jail before being eligible for parole. He was jailed at Swansea Crown Court. Steven Morgan, also 36, was sentenced to four-and-a-half years for helping Smith flee the scene.&#xA;The jury in the three-week trial heard Smith and Morgan had been invited into Mr Sarsero#39;s home in the Maestir area of Felinfoel by his mother.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life sentence for man who murdered couple with fentanyl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/8d838856-e873-11ee-8f50-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 12:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/8d838856-e873-11ee-8f50-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Life sentence for man who murdered couple with fentanyl Stephen Baxter, 61, and his wife Carol, 64, were found dead at their home in West Mersea, Essex, in April 2023. Luke DWit, 34, used fake identities to manipulate the couple before he laced their medication with the drug, a trial at Chelmsford Crown Court heard. Describing the moment she found them dead, she said: #34;I have never known an emotional pain to physically hurt so much.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
