<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finance on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/finance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finance on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 12:33:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How do interest rates affect me?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/e7495566-e880-11ee-9cf3-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 12:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/e7495566-e880-11ee-9cf3-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How do interest rates affect me? Interest rates set by the Bank of England affect mortgage, credit card and savings rates for millions of people across the UK. The base rate, currently 5. 25%, is what it charges other lenders to borrow money. It has a target to keep UK inflation at 2%.&#xA;The Bank may decide to raise rates to encourage people to spend less. The idea is that this helps to bring inflation down by dampening demand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I am no longer best man to be Irish PM - Varadkar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1c46a8b8-e6fb-11ee-b750-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 19:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1c46a8b8-e6fb-11ee-b750-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>I am no longer best man to be Irish PM - Varadkar Leo Varadkar was Ireland#39;s youngest PM in 2017 when he became Fine Gael leader. He currently leads the coalition government in Dublin, along with Fianna Fáil and the Green Party. He described leading his country as #34;the most fulfilling time of my life. During his time as taoiseach, Mr Varadkar championed referendums to change the Irish constitution legalising same-sex marriage and abortion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I am no longer best man to be Irish PM - Varadkar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/3fb2b9fe-e6f1-11ee-84b8-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 19:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/3fb2b9fe-e6f1-11ee-84b8-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>I am no longer best man to be Irish PM - Varadkar Leo Varadkar was Ireland#39;s youngest PM in 2017 when he became Fine Gael leader. He currently leads the coalition government in Dublin, along with Fianna Fáil and the Green Party. He described leading his country as #34;the most fulfilling time of my life. During his time as taoiseach, Mr Varadkar championed referendums to change the Irish constitution legalising same-sex marriage and abortion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The councils fighting to stop themselves going bust</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b30f6350-e52c-11ee-b864-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 05:43:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b30f6350-e52c-11ee-b864-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The councils fighting to stop themselves going bust In England more and more councils are in danger of going bust. BBC Panorama has followed the struggles of one such authority and the people who rely on it. The London Borough of Havering is in a fight to stop itself going bust, as seen in the video below. BBC Panorama has followed Havering Council as it has struggled to balance its books.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Idris Elba &#39;dreams big&#39; with West African eco-city plan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1c268de8-e468-11ee-94af-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 01:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1c268de8-e468-11ee-94af-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Idris Elba &amp;lsquo;dreams big&amp;rsquo; with West African eco-city plan Hollywood actor Idris Elba has a big dream for Sierra Leone. He wants to regenerate a beautiful island off its coast and turn it into an eco-friendly city. The project also intends to bring wind-powered renewable electricity for the first time to the West African nation. Elba was brought into the project by his childhood friend Siaka Stevens, the grandson of a former Sierra Leonean president of the same name.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Battle between West Bank farmers divides Israel and US</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ce069efa-e2d2-11ee-86bf-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 06:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ce069efa-e2d2-11ee-86bf-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Battle between West Bank farmers divides Israel and US US announces sanctions against three more Israeli settlers and two farming outposts. New measures by Washington and London to stop violent displacement of Palestinians. Fares Samamreh is a Palestinian sheep farmer on the South Hebron Hills. His battle with his neighbour, an Israeli settler called Yinon Levy, has drawn both the US and the UK into the dispute.&#xA;Yinon Levy was one of a group of local Israeli settlers who would regularly come to harass his sheep with their dogs and weapons, he says.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What a $1 deal says about America&#39;s office market</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/52283b84-dee2-11ee-8558-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 01:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/52283b84-dee2-11ee-8558-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What a $1 deal says about America&amp;rsquo;s office market The famous Flatiron building has been vacant since 2019. Around the corner, there&amp;rsquo;s work under way on a new office fronting Madison Square Park. But its next door neighbour, 360 Park Avenue South, has been empty since 2021. The building&amp;rsquo;s owners said it would be turned into condos.&#xA;The 20-storey building, which sold for $300m (£233m) that year, recently drew headlines after one of the owners handed over its 29% stake to one of its partners.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biden faces high-stakes address to calm Democrat nerves</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a8d3471e-dcc4-11ee-b111-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 15:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a8d3471e-dcc4-11ee-b111-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Biden faces high-stakes address to calm Democrat nerves The State of the Union address will give him a rare opportunity to speak to a national audience of millions. The 81-year-old seeks to tackle concerns about his age, put a positive gloss on his first-term record and lay out the case for his re-election in November. Mr Biden&amp;rsquo;s approval ratings are some of the lowest recorded for a president seeking re-election. Americans across the political spectrum feel discomfort about giving him another four-years as the commander-in-chief.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does the Budget mean for you?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/e79c3754-dfb6-11ee-a1cc-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 13:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/e79c3754-dfb6-11ee-a1cc-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What does the Budget mean for you? Jeremy Hunt announced a cut in the rate of National Insurance (NI) paid by 27 million employees across the UK. For employees paid between £12,571 to £50,270 a year, the current NI rate is 10% on earnings (down from 12% before January) The chancellor said this would fall to 8% in April. Higher earners will take home an additional £754 a year, according to calculations by investment companies.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
