<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trump on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/trump/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Trump on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:15:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/trump/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>19th Century law fires up anti-abortion push</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/91b957f8-ebab-11ee-855e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/91b957f8-ebab-11ee-855e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>19th Century law fires up anti-abortion push US anti-abortion activists, including allies of Donald Trump, have a strategy to ban abortion nationwide. It hinges on Mr Trump&amp;rsquo;s re-election in November and the use of a little-known 19th Century law. In June 2022, those appointees helped overturn Roe v Wade, rescinding the nationwide right to abortion. The American public has shown consistent support for abortion access, even in conservative states.&#xA;The movement&amp;rsquo;s ultimate goal - a federal abortion ban - has remained out of reach, a near-impossibility in a divided Congress.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is TikTok really a danger to the West?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f15885cc-e5ec-11ee-b97b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f15885cc-e5ec-11ee-b97b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Is TikTok really a danger to the West? TikTok has been accused of harvesting huge amounts of data. The app collects details such as location, what specific device is being used and which other apps are on it. China has attacked a bill going through US Congress that could ultimately see TikTok banned in the States. TikTok is owned by Beijing-based tech giant ByteDance, making it unique as a non-American mainstream app.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
