<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Putin on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/putin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Putin on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 10:18:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/putin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What we know about the attack on a Moscow concert hall</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/08f41026-e9de-11ee-a8bb-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 10:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/08f41026-e9de-11ee-a8bb-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What we know about the attack on a Moscow concert hall More than 100 people were killed as gunmen stormed Crocus City Hall. The Islamic State group has said four of its members carried out the attack. Video showed at least four people shooting randomly before proceeding into the concert hall itself and opening fire there. A woman said she and other visitors rushed towards the stage as soon as they realised shots were being fired.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russian day of mourning, as Putin says concert attackers arrested</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/10fc7f06-e9d9-11ee-ad16-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 10:15:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/10fc7f06-e9d9-11ee-ad16-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Russian day of mourning, as Putin says concert attackers arrested More than 140 people were injured in the stampede. The stampede took place in front of a crowd of more than 1,000 people in the centre of Moscow. The event was organised by a group called the Russian National Council of People&amp;rsquo;s Militia. The group was set up to counter the growing threat posed by the Islamic State.&#xA;Russian President Vladimir Putin said all four gunmen who carried out the attack have been arrested.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did Russia ignore US &#39;extremist&#39; attacks warning?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/24b1cc1c-e935-11ee-8eb4-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 14:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/24b1cc1c-e935-11ee-8eb4-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Did Russia ignore US &amp;rsquo;extremist&amp;rsquo; attacks warning? Washington issued a warning to its own citizens on 7 March. It warned of reports that extremists had plans to target large gatherings. It specifically mentioned concerts and advised Americans in the city to avoid large gatherings over the coming 48 hours. It seems clear Washington had some kind of intelligence and that it related to Islamic State.&#xA;The US government also shared this information with Russian authorities in accordance with its long-standing #39;duty to warn policy, a US official said.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did Russia ignore US &#39;extremist&#39; attacks warning?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/803ec054-e9d9-11ee-b8e8-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 14:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/803ec054-e9d9-11ee-b8e8-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Did Russia ignore US &amp;rsquo;extremist&amp;rsquo; attacks warning? Washington issued a warning to its own citizens on 7 March. It warned of reports that extremists had plans to target large gatherings. It specifically mentioned concerts and advised Americans in the city to avoid large gatherings over the coming 48 hours. It seems clear Washington had some kind of intelligence and that it related to Islamic State.&#xA;The US government also shared this information with Russian authorities in accordance with its long-standing &amp;lsquo;duty to warn policy, a US official said.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Putin&#39;s fifth term as Russian leader was never in doubt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/900399c0-e52d-11ee-909f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 18:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/900399c0-e52d-11ee-909f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Why Putin&amp;rsquo;s fifth term as Russian leader was never in doubt Kremlin ensured Putin had no credible opponent so it was always certain he would secure a fifth term by a landslide. It was at a grand military awards ceremony last December that Vladimir Putin, 71, told the Russian public he would stand for the presidency again. He said: &amp;ldquo;Now is the time for making decisions. I will be running for the post of president of the Russian Federation&amp;rdquo; Kremlin rarely leaves its choreography to chance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia says it repelled multiple drone attacks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/379bb48e-e46a-11ee-985b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 10:36:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/379bb48e-e46a-11ee-985b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Russia says it repelled multiple drone attacks Russia&amp;rsquo;s defence ministry says its forces have destroyed dozens of drones. The biggest attack happened in the southern Russian region of Krasnodar. The attacks come as Russia holds a general election in which President Vladimir Putin is guaranteed to win. In Ukraine, officials reported an overnight barrage of Russian drones and missiles on the port city of Odesa.&#xA;Five drones were downed in different areas while flying towards the capital.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putin: From Russia&#39;s KGB to a presidency defined by war</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1c0c896e-e465-11ee-8bba-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 10:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1c0c896e-e465-11ee-8bba-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Putin: From Russia&amp;rsquo;s KGB to a presidency defined by war Vladimir Putin has been in power since 2000, longer than any Kremlin leader since Soviet dictator Joseph Stalin. As he prepares for a fifth term as president, aged 71, there is little to stop him staying on, if he wants, until 2036. It was almost by accident that this little-known, former KGB man was hand-picked for the Kremlin. He often justifies his actions with an outlandish perception of history and a keen resentment of Nato.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
