<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Israel on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/israel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Israel on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 06:43:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/israel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>US reports death of senior Hamas military leader</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/60ba2c82-e5e7-11ee-af17-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 06:43:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/60ba2c82-e5e7-11ee-af17-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>US reports death of senior Hamas military leader Mr Issa was considered one of Israel#39;s most-wanted men. He was killed in a strike on a tunnel complex under the Nuseirat refugee camp. The Palestinian group, which controls Gaza, has not officially commented on reports of his death. He would be Hamas&amp;rsquo; most senior leader to die since the war began.&#xA;Hamas political leader Saleh al-Arouri died in an explosion in Beirut.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;He will come back’ - Israeli hostage families cling to hope, and demand a deal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ae41d17e-e45e-11ee-81f0-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:51:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ae41d17e-e45e-11ee-81f0-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;He will come back’ - Israeli hostage families cling to hope, and demand a deal Rachel Goldberg-Polin now lives by a new calendar - not weeks, or months, but days of absence and anguish. She writes a number on a piece of tape and sticks it to her clothing. It#39;s the number of days since her son Hersh was taken hostage by Hamas. The last image of the 23-year-old is in a Hamas video.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid reaches shore in Gaza after first sea delivery</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/27bf0efc-e399-11ee-a3c2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 09:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/27bf0efc-e399-11ee-a3c2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Aid reaches shore in Gaza after first sea delivery The US charity behind the mission, World Central Kitchen, is carrying out the mission in co-operation with the United Arab Emirates. The shipment contained 200 tonnes of food desperately needed for Gaza, which the UN says is on the brink of famine. Aid agencies have accused Israel of impeding aid deliveries, a charge vehemently denied. The shipment arrived on board Spanish charity ship Open Arms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Was this the week Israel and Hezbollah drew closer to war?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f9eff074-e396-11ee-997a-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 08:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f9eff074-e396-11ee-997a-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Was this the week Israel and Hezbollah drew closer to war? The day after the Hamas assault, Lebanon#39;s most powerful armed group Hezbollah fired guided rockets and shells into Israel. Israel carried out more air strikes on the Bekaa valley, deep into Lebanon, taking the death toll in Lebanon since the start of the conflict to more than 240. Could Israel, traumatised and vulnerable, with a prime minister fighting for political survival, decide the threat from across its northern border in Lebanon needs to be neutralised?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza medics tell BBC that Israeli troops beat and humiliated them</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/fb3d476a-e071-11ee-9a4f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 06:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/fb3d476a-e071-11ee-9a4f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Gaza medics tell BBC that Israeli troops beat and humiliated them Ahmed Abu Sabha, a doctor at Nasser hospital, described being held for a week in detention. He said muzzled dogs were set upon him and his hand was broken by an Israeli soldier. Two other medics wanted to remain anonymous for fear of reprisals. They told the BBC they were humiliated, beaten, doused with cold water, and forced to kneel in uncomfortable positions for hours.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza aid ship yet to leave Cyprus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ad45368a-dfb3-11ee-9003-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 12:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ad45368a-dfb3-11ee-9003-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Gaza aid ship yet to leave Cyprus A charity leading the mission said it hoped the ship, Open Arms, would set sail soon. The sighting of the new moon marked the start of the Islamic holy month of Ramadan in Gaza. A ceasefire remains off the table as indirect negotiations between Israel and Hamas have largely stalled. UK Foreign Secretary Lord Cameron said the UK, US and EU were continuing to urge Israel to allow more trucks into Gaza.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven of the best moments from the Oscars</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/575c2a0a-dfac-11ee-a5b3-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 04:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/575c2a0a-dfac-11ee-a5b3-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Seven of the best moments from the Oscars Ryan Gosling sang I&amp;rsquo;m Just Ken at the Oscars. The full-throated rendition of the hit was even better than we could have hoped for. Slash appeared to lend his talents for a guitar solo. The Oscars brought more than three hours of glamour and nudity.&#xA;The Kenergy was infectious - Gosling solicited energetic singalongs from the star-studded front row. There were even suggestions the choreography was a homage to Diamonds Are A Girl&amp;rsquo;s Best Friend.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top director makes Gaza statement in Oscars speech on night of protests</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/71197878-dfaf-11ee-8817-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 02:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/71197878-dfaf-11ee-8817-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Top director makes Gaza statement in Oscars speech on night of protests Protesters block traffic outside the Dolby Theatre in London. Around 1,000 people took part in the demonstration outside the venue. Celebrities, including Billie Eilish, also wore pins calling for a ceasefire. The Zone of Interest won the best international film award at the Oscars.&#xA;The German-language film focuses on the family of Auschwitz commandant Rudolf Höss. An estimated 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US military ship heading to Gaza to build port</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/d3255bc0-dedf-11ee-8d49-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 11:44:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/d3255bc0-dedf-11ee-8d49-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>US military ship heading to Gaza to build port The support ship, General Frank S Besson, set sail from a military base in the state of Virginia on Saturday. President Joe Biden said the US would build the floating harbour to help get aid into Gaza by sea. The UN has warned that famine in the Gaza Strip is almost inevitable and children are starving to death. Pentagon has said it could take up to 60 days to build the pier with the help of 1,000 troops - none of whom would go ashore.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attack victims hit out at extremism in open letter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/aa9cae7a-deed-11ee-a10a-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 05:41:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/aa9cae7a-deed-11ee-a10a-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Attack victims hit out at extremism in open letter Survivors and relatives of those killed during attacks in London, Manchester and Brussels are among the signatories. They warn it is irresponsible for politicians to equate extremists with the vast majority of British Muslims who deplore such violence. It comes as the government prepares to set out a new definition of extremism. The 57 signatories to the letter include Magen Inon, whose parents were killed by Hamas during the 7 October attacks on Israel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t equate Muslims with extremists, attack victims say</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/687b9076-dee1-11ee-84c2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 05:41:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/687b9076-dee1-11ee-84c2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t equate Muslims with extremists, attack victims say Survivors and relatives of those killed during attacks in London, Manchester and Brussels are among the signatories. They warn it is irresponsible for politicians to equate extremists with the vast majority of British Muslims who deplore such violence. It comes as the government prepares to set out a new definition of extremism. The 57 signatories to the letter include Magen Inon, whose parents were killed by Hamas during the 7 October attacks on Israel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IDF completes road across Gaza, satellite images show</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/5e4d9820-dee0-11ee-9fc3-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/5e4d9820-dee0-11ee-9fc3-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>IDF completes road across Gaza, satellite images show Satellite images show a new road running across northern Gaza from east to west. Some experts fear it will be used as a barrier, preventing Palestinians from returning to their homes. Others say it is part of an Israeli plan to remain in Gaza beyond the end of current hostilities. The new IDF route is the only one which runs uninterrupted across Gaza.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza war fuels Jerusalem fears as Ramadan to begin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/da33bf36-dee6-11ee-bb4b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/da33bf36-dee6-11ee-bb4b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Gaza war fuels Jerusalem fears as Ramadan to begin Hamas has reiterated a call for Palestinians to step up visits to al-Aqsa Mosque. The third holiest shrine in Islam is a place of worship for local Muslims. It is also the holiest place in Judaism, known as Temple Mount. Ramadan is due to begin on 10 or 11 March depending on sighting of the new moon.&#xA;Israel says its spy chief met with his US counterpart as it continued efforts to try to release dozens of hostages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US, UK and French destroy dozens of Houthi drones</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/bcf1b0f8-de74-11ee-84cc-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 21:13:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/bcf1b0f8-de74-11ee-84cc-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>US, UK and French destroy dozens of Houthi drones US military said at least 28 uncrewed aerial vehicles (UAVs) were downed over the Red Sea. Houthis said they had targeted a commercial ship, Propel Fortune, and a number of US destroyers. No US or coalition military vehicles were damaged and there were no reports of damage from commercial ships. Houthis have been attacking ships in the Red Sea and Gulf of Aden.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thousands call for Gaza ceasefire in London march</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/dc8715fa-de76-11ee-83d5-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 18:05:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/dc8715fa-de76-11ee-83d5-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Thousands call for Gaza ceasefire in London march The demonstration was organised by the Palestine Solidarity Campaign. It made its way from Hyde Park Corner to the US Embassy in Nine Elms. It was the 10th pro-Palestinian march in central London since Israel started its campaign in Gaza following the 7 October attacks on Israel by Hamas. A further man was also arrested for assault but was later de-arrested.&#xA;The Met said there had been no significant public order disturbance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yousaf condemns &#39;outrageous smear&#39; over Gaza funding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/18c73b4e-de7c-11ee-9e13-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 17:31:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/18c73b4e-de7c-11ee-9e13-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Yousaf condemns &amp;lsquo;outrageous smear&amp;rsquo; over Gaza funding Humza Yousaf has been accused of having a conflict of interest. The Scottish government donated £250,000 to UNRWA in November 2023. His parents-in-law were among millions unable to leave the enclave. He said the story was an Islamophobic attack and an attempt to link him to terrorism.&#xA;He said: &amp;ldquo;Most of my political life, I&amp;rsquo;ve battled insinuations from sections of the media desperate to link me to terrorism despite campaigning my whole life against it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweden and Canada resume aid to UN Gaza agency</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/82dad926-de74-11ee-aa72-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 15:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/82dad926-de74-11ee-aa72-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Sweden and Canada resume aid to UN Gaza agency Sweden and Canada will resume aid payments to UNRWA, the UN agency for Palestinian refugees. They were among 16 countries that paused funds after the 7 October attack by Hamas. The UN is investigating the attack, and France&amp;rsquo;s foreign minister is leading a review. The government has allocated 400 million kronor for the year 2024.&#xA;UNRWA is the biggest UN agency operating in Gaza.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweden and Canada resume aid to UN Gaza agency</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/cce804f6-de44-11ee-a47b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 15:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/cce804f6-de44-11ee-a47b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Sweden and Canada resume aid to UN Gaza agency Sweden and Canada will resume aid payments to UNRWA, the UN agency for Palestinian refugees. They were among 16 countries that paused funds after the 7 October attack by Hamas. The UN is investigating the attack, and France&amp;rsquo;s foreign minister is leading a review. The government has allocated 400 million kronor for the year 2024.&#xA;UNRWA is the biggest UN agency operating in Gaza.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netanyahu is a survivor, but his problems are stacking up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/04fc0b06-de79-11ee-9649-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 23:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/04fc0b06-de79-11ee-9649-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Netanyahu is a survivor, but his problems are stacking up The piece in Haaretz followed a report that held the Israeli prime minister personally responsible for failures over a stampede that led to the death of 45 people in 2021. The newspaper, which is frequently critical of the prime minister, pointed out that Mr Netanyahu did not respond directly to the report. Commentators across the political divide saw a parallel between the Mount Meron disaster and the 7 October attacks by Hamas.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five killed in Gaza aid drop parachute failure - reports</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1633e822-dd88-11ee-aa19-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 19:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1633e822-dd88-11ee-aa19-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Five killed in Gaza aid drop parachute failure - reports An eyewitness and the Hamas-run health ministry in Gaza said the five were killed when at least one parachute failed to deploy. It is unclear which air drop was involved in the incident. US, Jordan, Egypt, France, the Netherlands and Belgium have been dropping aid into Gaza in recent days. Joint air drop of aid into Gaza with the Royal Jordanian Air Force happened at about 13:30 local time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>West Bank violence: &#39;My child&#39;s destiny was to get killed&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/c89a35f0-dd85-11ee-91ca-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 17:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/c89a35f0-dd85-11ee-91ca-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>West Bank violence: &amp;lsquo;My child&amp;rsquo;s destiny was to get killed&amp;rsquo; Samah and Amr were filming themselves on a spring day. They walk around the garden of the family home. In the background, their mother Salam is burning leaves and grass. The scene is emblematic of a close family that has lived in the same place for generations.&#xA;Now Samah is in mourning for her brother. Amr Najjar grew up in Burin, in the north of the occupied West Bank.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What the world made of Biden&#39;s big speech</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/25a86b38-dd89-11ee-883c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 16:21:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/25a86b38-dd89-11ee-883c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What the world made of Biden&amp;rsquo;s big speech Biden started his State of the Union address by talking about Ukraine. He then went on to talk about the Israel-Hamas war and the China-U. S. trade deal.&#xA;He ended the speech with a reference to the &amp;lsquo;greatest generation&amp;rsquo; of Americans. Biden draws election battle lines in fiery speech. He calls on Congress to unblock the bill that would release the funding Kyiv needs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israel back in Eurovision 2024 after lyric change</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/3623b0e0-dcc0-11ee-99bc-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 19:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/3623b0e0-dcc0-11ee-99bc-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Israel back in Eurovision 2024 after lyric change Eden Golan will represent the country at the contest in Sweden this May. Israel will be allowed to compete at the Eurovision Song Contest 2024 after changing the lyrics to its song, organisers have confirmed. The country will take part in the contest for the first time in 2024. Israel&amp;rsquo;s public broadcaster agreed to amend the song, now titled Hurricane.&#xA;Original song, October Rain, was thought to reference the Hamas attacks of 7 October and had been barred for breaking rules on political neutrality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US to set up temporary port on Gaza coast for aid delivery</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/488373ee-dcbe-11ee-b15f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 18:38:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/488373ee-dcbe-11ee-b15f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>US to set up temporary port on Gaza coast for aid delivery Port will be able to receive large ships carrying food, water medicine, and temporary shelters. Initial shipments will arrive via Cyprus, where Israeli security inspections will take place. UN warns that a quarter of the population is on the brink of famine. Mr Biden is due to make the announcement during his State of the Union address later.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mordaunt defends Donelan over £15,000 legal bill</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/3e481d04-dcc2-11ee-b70b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 17:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/3e481d04-dcc2-11ee-b70b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Mordaunt defends Donelan over £15,000 legal bill Science Secretary Michelle Donelan was told to pay £15,000 for falsely suggesting an academic backed Hamas. Penny Mordaunt said she was confident the payment had been justified. Prime Minister Rishi Sunak also defended the payout saying it was a long-standing convention that the government will fund disputes. He said if Labour were to get into power it would &amp;ldquo;never allow that sort of thing to happen… that would be history#34&amp;rdquo;;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biden faces high-stakes address to calm Democrat nerves</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a8d3471e-dcc4-11ee-b111-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 15:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a8d3471e-dcc4-11ee-b111-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Biden faces high-stakes address to calm Democrat nerves The State of the Union address will give him a rare opportunity to speak to a national audience of millions. The 81-year-old seeks to tackle concerns about his age, put a positive gloss on his first-term record and lay out the case for his re-election in November. Mr Biden&amp;rsquo;s approval ratings are some of the lowest recorded for a president seeking re-election. Americans across the political spectrum feel discomfort about giving him another four-years as the commander-in-chief.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
