<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hong Kong on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/hong-kong/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hong Kong on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 06:01:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/hong-kong/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Say one thing, do another? The government’s record net migration rise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/eea7467c-ea99-11ee-bb51-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 06:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/eea7467c-ea99-11ee-bb51-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Say one thing, do another? The government’s record net migration rise The 12 months to June 2022 saw the fastest population growth since the 1960s. Current projections from the Office for National Statistics put the UK on course for 74 million people by 2036 - six million more than there are today. The answer, according to the ONS, is largely immigration. Small boats are an important issue - on a human and national level.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are Hong Kong&#39;s days as a global business hub over?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/51b5df12-ea9f-11ee-b917-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:22:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/51b5df12-ea9f-11ee-b917-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Are Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s days as a global business hub over? Authorities say it will protect the city and ensure stability. Critics are alarmed it will silence all dissent with its closed-door trials. It comes at a time when Beijing&amp;rsquo;s iron grip and US-China tensions were already driving away foreign investors who now have an &amp;ldquo;anywhere but China&amp;rdquo;&amp;quot; policy. The emphasis on national security and the danger posed by &amp;ldquo;foreign forces&amp;rsquo; raises the stakes for foreign capital and businesses operating in the city.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
