<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rape on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/rape/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rape on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 15:11:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/rape/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What we know about Baltimore bridge collapse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/23e9aa22-eba9-11ee-8e16-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 15:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/23e9aa22-eba9-11ee-8e16-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What we know about Baltimore bridge collapse The Francis Scott Key Bridge was opened in 1977. It spanned the Patapsco River and Baltimore harbour. A container ship crashed into the bridge early on Tuesday morning. Between seven and 20 people are believed to be in the river.&#xA;Maryland Governor Wes Moore has declared a state of emergency. The bridge was the third longest of its type in the world. The collapse happened at around 01:30 local time (05:30 GMT) on Tuesday.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Having a certificate of loss proves my baby existed’</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2808b0b4-e9e0-11ee-828d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:46:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2808b0b4-e9e0-11ee-828d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>‘Having a certificate of loss proves my baby existed’ Emma Barnett wrote about the heartbreak of losing a baby this week. She said receiving a certificate to mark the miscarriage has helped her family. Here, other women share their thoughts and feelings about the government&amp;rsquo;s new scheme for bereaved parents to commemorate pregnancy losses. The morning baby loss certificates were launched I found myself pouring my details into the website to apply.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
