<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oscar on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/oscar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oscar on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 09:40:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/oscar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Olivia Colman: I&#39;d be paid more if I was Oliver</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/16dc5862-ea9a-11ee-af8e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 09:40:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/16dc5862-ea9a-11ee-af8e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Olivia Colman: I&amp;rsquo;d be paid more if I was Oliver Olivia Colman says she would be paid a lot more if she was a man. Says she knows of one pay disparity which was a 12,000% difference. The issue of equal pay in Hollywood burst into the open a decade ago. The latest top 10 list of the best-paid actors contains just two women.&#xA;Colman joined the Hollywood A-list in 2019 when she won the best actress Oscar for playing Queen Anne in The Favourite.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oscar-winning King&#39;s Speech screenwriter dies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/e2646ec6-e530-11ee-8b0c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 04:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/e2646ec6-e530-11ee-8b0c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Oscar-winning King&amp;rsquo;s Speech screenwriter dies Oscar-winning writer of The King&amp;rsquo;s Speech dies at the age of 86. The film was based on a true story of a man&amp;rsquo;s struggle to overcome a speech impediment. The actor who played the man in the film has not yet been named. He is survived by his wife and two children.&#xA;Seidler won his first Writers Guild award for the 1988 biopic Onassis: The Richest Man In The World starring Raul Julia as the Greek shipping magnate Aristotle Onassis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weekly quiz: Which exclusive Oscars club did Emma Stone join?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/60c3167a-e2d2-11ee-a93b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 18:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/60c3167a-e2d2-11ee-a93b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Weekly quiz: Which exclusive Oscars club did Emma Stone join? The weekly news quiz. How closely have you been paying attention to what#39;s been going on in the world over the past seven days? Some mobile users may experience difficulties. If you cannot see the quiz, try this link or have a go at something from the archives.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
