<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>India on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/india/</link>
    <description>Recent content in India on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 06:15:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/india/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My father&#39;s diary left me wondering whether he was a killer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/3b9bd72a-e939-11ee-8202-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 06:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/3b9bd72a-e939-11ee-8202-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>My father&amp;rsquo;s diary left me wondering whether he was a killer Saul Wordsworth&amp;rsquo;s father Christopher may have taken a terrible secret to his grave. He knew all about his quick temper and explosive outbursts of rage. But a set of his diaries inherited by Saul hinted at something altogether darker. The passage she highlighted referred to hiding a body until a search party had gone.&#xA;Growing up in Harpenden, Hertfordshire, Saul knew his father as a teller of tall tales.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First J-Pop, then K-Pop - could I-Pop be next?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/38ce4002-e937-11ee-b0d3-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/38ce4002-e937-11ee-b0d3-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>First J-Pop, then K-Pop - could I-Pop be next? Ri, Zo, Sim, and Suchi are said to be India;s first mainstream girl group in more than 20 years. W.i.S.H. is an acronym of World inka Stage Hai, or the world is their stage. W.i.S.H. want to change that and get to the top by spreading a positive message of sisterhood and female empowerment. She describes their debut single, Lazeez, as a song that #34;celebrates the modern woman and encourages self-love.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The GP who became Ireland&#39;s youngest taoiseach</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/9166bda0-e6f5-11ee-9f55-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 14:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/9166bda0-e6f5-11ee-9f55-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The GP who became Ireland&amp;rsquo;s youngest taoiseach Leo Varadkar is stepping down as Fine Gael leader and Irish prime minister. He is the son of an Irish-born nurse and a Indian-born doctor. He was just 38 years old when he began his first term as taoiseach in 2017. At the time, he was widely seen as embodying the liberalisation of Ireland.&#xA;The future Irish leader was born on 18 January 1979 in Dublin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raducanu&#39;s lower back injury &#39;nothing serious&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/18a07d7c-e5f9-11ee-a46b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 11:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/18a07d7c-e5f9-11ee-a46b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Raducanu&amp;rsquo;s lower back injury &amp;rsquo;nothing serious&#39; The 21-year-old was due to face China#39;s Wang Xiyu in the first round on Tuesday. Raducanu was beaten in straight sets by world number two Aryna Sabalenka in the third round at Indian Wells last week. It is not known whether the injury will impact her selection for Great Britain&amp;rsquo;s King Cup squad. Raducanu had recorded back-to-back victories for the first time since winning three in a row at Indian Wells 12 months ago.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is TikTok really a danger to the West?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f15885cc-e5ec-11ee-b97b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f15885cc-e5ec-11ee-b97b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Is TikTok really a danger to the West? TikTok has been accused of harvesting huge amounts of data. The app collects details such as location, what specific device is being used and which other apps are on it. China has attacked a bill going through US Congress that could ultimately see TikTok banned in the States. TikTok is owned by Beijing-based tech giant ByteDance, making it unique as a non-American mainstream app.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fans thrilled as Ed Sheeran sings in Punjabi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f6be9712-e462-11ee-83fa-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 10:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f6be9712-e462-11ee-83fa-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Fans thrilled as Ed Sheeran sings in Punjabi The Shape Of You singer invited Indian singer Diljit Dosanjh to perform with him on stage. Crowds went wild when the duo gave a rendition of DosanJh#39;s hit track Lover in Punjabi. One fan said it was #34;the crossover we never knew we needed&amp;rsquo; Diljit Dosanjh and Ed Sheeran have collaborated on a Punjabi song. The song, Hass Hass, was released last year in collaboration with Cheap Thrills singer Sia.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alcaraz stung as bees swarm court at Indian Wells</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/75d9dcea-e2de-11ee-8121-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 06:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/75d9dcea-e2de-11ee-8121-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Alcaraz stung as bees swarm court at Indian Wells Umpire Mohamed Lahyani was forced to suspend play in the third game as the bees invaded the court in California. The match was delayed for one hour and 40 minutes before defending champion Alcaraz won 6-3 6-1. The Wimbledon champion said afterwards that it was the most unusual match he had ever played. The bees were particularly attracted to the spidercam - a TV camera which moves above the court on cables.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neil Young to rejoin Spotify after Joe Rogan row</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f7ccc196-e12a-11ee-914d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 09:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f7ccc196-e12a-11ee-914d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Neil Young to rejoin Spotify after Joe Rogan row Young told streaming giant to remove hits like Harvest Moon and Heart of Gold. The singer said his return did not reflect a reversal of his stance. Instead, the decision came after Rogan signed a $250m deal to make his podcast available on multiple platforms, rather than remaining a Spotify exclusive. Young said in January 2022 that Spotify represented 60% of his streaming revenue globally.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The cruel Yale benefactor who traded in Indian slaves</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f4581f54-e12c-11ee-92a1-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f4581f54-e12c-11ee-92a1-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The cruel Yale benefactor who traded in Indian slaves Yale served as the all-powerful governor-president of the British East India Company in Madras in southern India. It was a gift of about £1,162 ($1,486) that earned him the honour of having the university named after him. Last month, Yale issued a formal apology for the links its early leaders and benefactors had with slavery. Yale apologises for its role in the Indian Ocean slave trade.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why firms are bringing their manufacturing back home</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/56b66b1a-e12d-11ee-b95d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/56b66b1a-e12d-11ee-b95d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Why firms are bringing their manufacturing back home Reshoring is when a company decides to stop getting its manufacturing done overseas, such as in China, and instead returns the work to its home country. Chris Ball and Ian Whateley are the bosses of Shropshire-based Advanced Chemical Etching (Ace) Ace makes precision metal components for customers in the aerospace, automotive, electronics and telecoms sectors. More than half of UK manufacturers are now reshoring, according to a study.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raducanu loses to Sabalenka at Indian Wells</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6fa3662a-e086-11ee-819d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 07:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6fa3662a-e086-11ee-819d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Raducanu loses to Sabalenka at Indian Wells Britain&amp;rsquo;s Emma Raducanu beaten 6-3 7-5 by Aryna Sabalenka. The 21-year-old was a wildcard at the tournament following an injury-disrupted 2023. Raducanu reached the fourth round in California last year. Raducanu beat Dayana Yastremska in straight sets.&#xA;It was the first time the English player had recorded back-to-back wins since successfully coming through three in a row at Indian Wells 12 months ago. Raducanu made her return to the tour in January following an eight-month absence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Djokovic knocked out by lucky loser at Indian Wells</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6294431a-e085-11ee-a73f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 07:10:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6294431a-e085-11ee-a73f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Djokovic knocked out by lucky loser at Indian Wells World number one Novak Djokovic beaten by Luca Nardi at Indian Wells. Italian Nardi, ranked 123 in the world, had originally been knocked out in qualifying but reached the main draw after another player&amp;rsquo;s withdrawal. He hit 34 winners in a 6-4 3-6 6-3 win over the 24-time Grand Slam champion, converting match point with an ace. Nardi was beaten by Belgium&amp;rsquo;s David Goffin in the final round of qualifying.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How China&#39;s boarding schools are silencing Tibet’s language</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ce8fab76-dee7-11ee-b085-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:54:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ce8fab76-dee7-11ee-b085-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How China&amp;rsquo;s boarding schools are silencing Tibet’s language Tibetan educational sociologist Gyal Lo can speak Mandarin Chinese fluently. He would prefer not to use the language of people he identifies as colonial oppressors. Beijing says these reforms give Tibetan children the best possible preparation for their adult lives. But he believes Beijing&amp;rsquo;s real aim is to undermine the Tibetan identity.&#xA;Chinese government has closed village schools and expanded use of boarding schools.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raducanu moves on to round three at Indian Wells</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/44a0dfc2-de77-11ee-992d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 22:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/44a0dfc2-de77-11ee-992d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Raducanu moves on to round three at Indian Wells Raducanu raced into a 4-0 lead in just 18 minutes during the first set. Yastremska stepped to the back of the court between games, holding her stomach and then retiring from the contest. Raducanu will face Peyton Stearns or Aryna Sabalenka in round three. Cameron Norrie beats Lorenzo Sonego to reach round three.&#xA;Wild card Raducanu broke Yastremska&amp;rsquo;s serve in the opening game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raducanu moves on to round three at Indian Wells</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/aedf9508-de7d-11ee-8ae3-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 22:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/aedf9508-de7d-11ee-8ae3-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Raducanu moves on to round three at Indian Wells Raducanu raced into a 4-0 lead in just 18 minutes during the first set. Yastremska stepped to the back of the court between games, holding her stomach and then retiring from the contest. Raducanu will face Peyton Stearns or Aryna Sabalenka in round three. Cameron Norrie beats Lorenzo Sonego to reach round three.&#xA;Wild card Raducanu broke Yastremska&amp;rsquo;s serve in the opening game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MH370: The families haunted by one of aviation&#39;s greatest mysteries</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/664d10d6-dd8d-11ee-8f9e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 23:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/664d10d6-dd8d-11ee-8f9e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>MH370: The families haunted by one of aviation&amp;rsquo;s greatest mysteries Li Eryou&amp;rsquo;s son Yanlin was on board Malaysia Airlines flight MH370. The Boeing 777, carrying 227 passengers and 12 crew members, disappeared on 8 March 2014. Mr Li and his wife, Liu Shuangfeng - farmers from a village south of Beijing - have struggled to make sense of what happened. The biggest and most expensive search operation ever mounted lasted four years but failed to find any trace of the missing airliner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Hugh right about Oscar films being &#39;frankly too long&#39;?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/d71595b0-dee4-11ee-82c6-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/d71595b0-dee4-11ee-82c6-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Is Hugh right about Oscar films being &amp;lsquo;frankly too long&amp;rsquo;? Hugh Grant openly questions length of this year&amp;rsquo;s awards season contenders. Christopher Nolan&amp;rsquo;s three-hour epic Oppenheimer is expected to sweep the Oscars. Three of the five other Bafta nominees clock in at over two hours each. The Holdovers, Maestro, and Anatomy of a Fall are also Oscar contenders.&#xA;Killers of the Flower Moon is the longest of this year&amp;rsquo;s best picture contenders.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the new vaping tax and when will it start?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6b7734d0-dcc8-11ee-9aea-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 15:25:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6b7734d0-dcc8-11ee-9aea-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What is the new vaping tax and when will it start? Vaping is nowhere near as harmful as smoking cigarettes. But health experts agree that anyone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t smoke should not start. The government has said it will introduce a new tax on vaping products. It has already announced plans to ban disposable vapes, to help cut the number of children vaping.&#xA;Vaping products duty will start in October 2026. The duty will be in place until the end of the current fiscal year in October 2015.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five tips when asking for a pay rise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1473d9ea-e5f6-11ee-b3f0-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 15:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1473d9ea-e5f6-11ee-b3f0-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Five tips when asking for a pay rise Last year saw waves of strikes, with tens of thousands of workers walking out. Many of these strikes have taken place in the public sector. Even if you do have a conversation with your manager there#39;s no guarantee that it will result in a pay rise. But there are ways to give yourself the best chance of success.&#xA;Jill Cotton, a career trends experts at jobs site Glassdoor, says scheduling a talk in advance will allow you and your boss time to prepare.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five tips when asking for a pay rise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6bea6782-e080-11ee-8757-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 15:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6bea6782-e080-11ee-8757-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Five tips when asking for a pay rise Last year saw waves of strikes, with tens of thousands of workers walking out. Many of these strikes have taken place in the public sector. Even if you do have a conversation with your manager there&amp;rsquo;s no guarantee that it will result in a pay rise. But there are ways to give yourself the best chance of success.&#xA;Jill Cotton, a career trends experts at jobs site Glassdoor, says scheduling a talk in advance will allow you and your boss time to prepare.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five tips when asking for a pay rise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/814fc35c-e534-11ee-b238-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 15:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/814fc35c-e534-11ee-b238-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Five tips when asking for a pay rise Last year saw waves of strikes, with tens of thousands of workers walking out. Many of these strikes have taken place in the public sector. Even if you do have a conversation with your manager there#39;s no guarantee that it will result in a pay rise. But there are ways to give yourself the best chance of success.&#xA;Jill Cotton, a career trends experts at jobs site Glassdoor, says scheduling a talk in advance will allow you and your boss time to prepare.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five tips when asking for a pay rise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/9cb19b44-e6fa-11ee-91f1-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 15:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/9cb19b44-e6fa-11ee-91f1-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Five tips when asking for a pay rise Last year saw waves of strikes, with tens of thousands of workers walking out. Many of these strikes have taken place in the public sector. Even if you do have a conversation with your manager there#39;s no guarantee that it will result in a pay rise. But there are ways to give yourself the best chance of success.&#xA;Jill Cotton, a career trends experts at jobs site Glassdoor, says scheduling a talk in advance will allow you and your boss time to prepare.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five tips when asking for a pay rise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a02fec3a-e2db-11ee-90a8-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 15:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a02fec3a-e2db-11ee-90a8-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Five tips when asking for a pay rise Last year saw waves of strikes, with tens of thousands of workers walking out. Many of these strikes have taken place in the public sector. Even if you do have a conversation with your manager there#39;s no guarantee that it will result in a pay rise. But there are ways to give yourself the best chance of success.&#xA;Jill Cotton, a career trends experts at jobs site Glassdoor, says scheduling a talk in advance will allow you and your boss time to prepare.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five tips when asking for a pay rise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b103e142-e132-11ee-8ecb-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 15:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b103e142-e132-11ee-8ecb-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Five tips when asking for a pay rise Last year saw waves of strikes, with tens of thousands of workers walking out. Many of these strikes have taken place in the public sector. Even if you do have a conversation with your manager there#39;s no guarantee that it will result in a pay rise. But there are ways to give yourself the best chance of success.&#xA;Jill Cotton, a career trends experts at jobs site Glassdoor, says scheduling a talk in advance will allow you and your boss time to prepare.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lily Gladstone: The actress who could make Oscars history</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/887554e4-dee5-11ee-b716-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:29:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/887554e4-dee5-11ee-b716-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Lily Gladstone: The actress who could make Oscars history The 37-year-old is the first Native American woman to ever be nominated for best actress at the Oscars. We will find out if she is also the first winner when the ceremony takes place in Los Angeles on 10 March. Gladstone is not a newcomer to acting - viewers may have seen her in TV series such as Billions and films including Certain Women.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
