<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cancer on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/cancer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cancer on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:59:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/cancer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gillian Anderson: Why I changed my mind on playing Emily Maitlis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/41effdac-e5e9-11ee-8388-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:59:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/41effdac-e5e9-11ee-8388-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Gillian Anderson: Why I changed my mind on playing Emily Maitlis The X-Files and Sex Education actress had reservations about taking the part. She initially turned down the role of the interviewer in the new film Scoop. Anderson is speaking alongside her co-star Billie Piper in the Langham Hotel, about 100m from where Newsnight is made in the corporation’s New Broadcasting House. The Emmy and Golden Globe-winning actress explains that the pair bumped into each other at a Cancer Research fundraiser at Bafta#39;s headquarters last year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terminally ill apartment owner wants day in court</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/205236f6-e535-11ee-b153-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 06:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/205236f6-e535-11ee-b153-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Terminally ill apartment owner wants day in court Denise Patrick, 68, fears she will not live to see a new case for compensation go to trial. That would require legislative change. Owners of the apartments were told to evacuate the building in 2019. Their bid for compensation was struck out by a High Court judge.&#xA;Denise Patrick said she is begging politicians to enable her to have her day in court - but if she is not alive to see that day, she asked that her interview given to BBC Good Morning Ulster be played to the court.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cockney Rebel singer Steve Harley dies at 73</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/315bb7f4-e460-11ee-b5f6-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 12:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/315bb7f4-e460-11ee-b5f6-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Cockney Rebel singer Steve Harley dies at 73 His best known song was Make Me Smile which went to number one in the charts in 1975. The musician had still been touring until recently, but cancelled dates to have treatment for cancer. Harley lived on the Essex-Suffolk border with his wife Dorothy, with whom he had two children. Harley was born in south London in 1951 and formed Cockney Rebel in the early 1970s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sister&#39;s stem cells help woman fight leukaemia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b0e5e6f8-e3a6-11ee-8583-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 06:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b0e5e6f8-e3a6-11ee-8583-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Sister&amp;rsquo;s stem cells help woman fight leukaemia Lesley Calder was diagnosed with acute myeloid leukaemia in 2019. chemotherapy was unsuccessful and her only option was a stem cell transplant. Her three siblings came forward to be tested as stem cell donors. The chances of a sibling match are just 25% but Lesley was lucky.&#xA;Max was called on to donate his stem cells to a stranger last summer. Only 3% of the UK population is signed up to the stem cell donor register.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Journey Through Cancer: Insights from Prof Mererid Evans and Rhod Gilbert</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/56fce03a-de7c-11ee-a7f1-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 23:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/56fce03a-de7c-11ee-a7f1-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Understanding Cancer Treatment: Insights from Prof Mererid Evans and Rhod Gilbert&amp;rsquo;s Journey Both patients and medical professionals frequently express agreement that cancer treatment is harsh. Renowned oncologist Prof. Mererid Evans of Cardiff&amp;rsquo;s Velindre Cancer Centre discusses the difficulties and developments in cancer treatment via her work and the experiences of her well-known patient, Welsh comedian Rhod Gilbert.&#xA;A Journey Through the Treatment of Cancer Rhod Gilbert&amp;rsquo;s experience with tonsil, throat, tongue, and neck cancer raised awareness of the difficult realities of cancer treatment.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
