<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cancer on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/cancer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cancer on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 07:45:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/cancer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>NI sees 20% rise in 18-49 cancer diagnoses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6d30635a-eaa6-11ee-aa18-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 07:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6d30635a-eaa6-11ee-aa18-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>NI sees 20% rise in 18-49 cancer diagnoses Figures show that, by 2019, 1,076 people aged 18-49 were diagnosed with some form of cancer. Prof Helen Coleman, who was involved in the research, said it was worrying. The research looked at early onset cancers, which means cancers diagnosed in adults under the age of 50. Cancers commonly seen in older people are now being diagnosed in younger adults.&#xA;The rise has also been seen in other western countries such as across the UK, America and Australia.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>William and Kate &#39;enormously touched&#39; by public support</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f87186f8-e9d7-11ee-a529-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 10:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f87186f8-e9d7-11ee-a529-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>William and Kate &amp;rsquo;enormously touched&amp;rsquo; by public support Catherine revealed in a video message on Friday that she had begun treatment. The Prince and Princess of Wales are &amp;rsquo;enormously touched&amp;rsquo; by the kind messages. They are &amp;lsquo;grateful&amp;rsquo; that the public have understood their request for privacy, Kensington Palace said. Catherine received her diagnosis after tests carried out following abdominal surgery.&#xA;A spokesperson for Kensington Palace said: &amp;ldquo;The Prince and Princess are both enormously touched by the kind messages from people here in the UK, across the Commonwealth and around the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Campaigning dad of Damilola Taylor dies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a9168f8e-e92f-11ee-9bbe-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 15:31:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a9168f8e-e92f-11ee-9bbe-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Campaigning dad of Damilola Taylor dies The former Nigerian civil servant dedicated years to improving the lives of disadvantaged children in the wake of his son&amp;rsquo;s death. He set up the Damilola Taylor Trust to campaign against knife crime. Mr Taylor died on Saturday aged 75 with prostate cancer. He was 10 when he was stabbed in the leg and left to die in a south London stairwell in 2000.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Outpouring of support for Kate after cancer news</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/7cbeb2ee-e93a-11ee-8e3c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 14:43:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/7cbeb2ee-e93a-11ee-8e3c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Outpouring of support for Kate after cancer news Princess of Wales reveals she is being treated for cancer. She has been receiving chemotherapy since late February. Cancer charities have praised her openness, while world leaders, friends and celebrities have wished her well. The news has also led to calls for her and her family to be given privacy.&#xA;Catherine said she and Prince William had taken time to sensitively share the state of her health with their children.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harry and Meghan reach out to Kate after cancer news</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/9da0ab50-e92d-11ee-91e4-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 13:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/9da0ab50-e92d-11ee-91e4-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Harry and Meghan reach out to Kate after cancer news The Duke and Duchess of Sussex have reached out to the Prince and Princess of Wales, the BBC understands. The contact is understood to have been made privately. Prince Harry and Meghan said they wished health and healing for Catherine. The princess is confident that she will make a full recovery.&#xA;Catherine had abdominal surgery in January, but it was not known then there was any cancer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kate cancer diagnosis rewrites story of past weeks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/d081fb74-e9e0-11ee-a720-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/d081fb74-e9e0-11ee-a720-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Kate cancer diagnosis rewrites story of past weeks She&amp;rsquo;s been their dash of glamour in a greying royal world. The palace will fervently hope that the shift towards a greater openness about her health will be the point at which the speculation about her stops. The outburst of rumour-mongering has been a bruising time for Catherine and Prince William. Catherine and Prince William are now not expected to appear with the Royal Family on Easter Sunday.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kate cancer diagnosis rewrites story of past weeks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/d6ac3aa0-e92c-11ee-9385-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:39:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/d6ac3aa0-e92c-11ee-9385-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Kate cancer diagnosis rewrites story of past weeks She#39;s been their dash of glamour in a greying royal world. The palace will fervently hope that the shift towards a greater openness about her health will be the point at which the speculation about her stops. The outburst of rumour-mongering has been a bruising time for Catherine and Prince William. Catherine and Prince William are now not expected to appear with the Royal Family on Easter Sunday.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is preventative chemotherapy?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/333f5aa0-e936-11ee-8a4f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 19:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/333f5aa0-e936-11ee-8a4f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What is preventative chemotherapy? Catherine, Princess of Wales, says she is having treatment for cancer. It was discovered following major abdominal surgery in January. She started preventative chemotherapy in late February. Kensington Palace has not said what type of cancer she has.&#xA;The princess has a right to medical privacy as we all do, a spokesperson said. After the surgery in January, which Kensington Palace says was successful, doctors performed tests which revealed cancer had been present.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gillian Anderson: Why I changed my mind on playing Emily Maitlis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/41effdac-e5e9-11ee-8388-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:59:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/41effdac-e5e9-11ee-8388-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Gillian Anderson: Why I changed my mind on playing Emily Maitlis The X-Files and Sex Education actress had reservations about taking the part. She initially turned down the role of the interviewer in the new film Scoop. Anderson is speaking alongside her co-star Billie Piper in the Langham Hotel, about 100m from where Newsnight is made in the corporation’s New Broadcasting House. The Emmy and Golden Globe-winning actress explains that the pair bumped into each other at a Cancer Research fundraiser at Bafta#39;s headquarters last year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terminally ill apartment owner wants day in court</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/205236f6-e535-11ee-b153-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 06:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/205236f6-e535-11ee-b153-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Terminally ill apartment owner wants day in court Denise Patrick, 68, fears she will not live to see a new case for compensation go to trial. That would require legislative change. Owners of the apartments were told to evacuate the building in 2019. Their bid for compensation was struck out by a High Court judge.&#xA;Denise Patrick said she is begging politicians to enable her to have her day in court - but if she is not alive to see that day, she asked that her interview given to BBC Good Morning Ulster be played to the court.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cockney Rebel singer Steve Harley dies at 73</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/315bb7f4-e460-11ee-b5f6-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 12:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/315bb7f4-e460-11ee-b5f6-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Cockney Rebel singer Steve Harley dies at 73 His best known song was Make Me Smile which went to number one in the charts in 1975. The musician had still been touring until recently, but cancelled dates to have treatment for cancer. Harley lived on the Essex-Suffolk border with his wife Dorothy, with whom he had two children. Harley was born in south London in 1951 and formed Cockney Rebel in the early 1970s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sister&#39;s stem cells help woman fight leukaemia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b0e5e6f8-e3a6-11ee-8583-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 06:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b0e5e6f8-e3a6-11ee-8583-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Sister&amp;rsquo;s stem cells help woman fight leukaemia Lesley Calder was diagnosed with acute myeloid leukaemia in 2019. chemotherapy was unsuccessful and her only option was a stem cell transplant. Her three siblings came forward to be tested as stem cell donors. The chances of a sibling match are just 25% but Lesley was lucky.&#xA;Max was called on to donate his stem cells to a stranger last summer. Only 3% of the UK population is signed up to the stem cell donor register.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Journey Through Cancer: Insights from Prof Mererid Evans and Rhod Gilbert</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/56fce03a-de7c-11ee-a7f1-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 23:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/56fce03a-de7c-11ee-a7f1-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Understanding Cancer Treatment: Insights from Prof Mererid Evans and Rhod Gilbert&amp;rsquo;s Journey Both patients and medical professionals frequently express agreement that cancer treatment is harsh. Renowned oncologist Prof. Mererid Evans of Cardiff&amp;rsquo;s Velindre Cancer Centre discusses the difficulties and developments in cancer treatment via her work and the experiences of her well-known patient, Welsh comedian Rhod Gilbert.&#xA;A Journey Through the Treatment of Cancer Rhod Gilbert&amp;rsquo;s experience with tonsil, throat, tongue, and neck cancer raised awareness of the difficult realities of cancer treatment.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
