<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Murder on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/murder/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Murder on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 06:15:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/murder/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My father&#39;s diary left me wondering whether he was a killer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/3b9bd72a-e939-11ee-8202-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 06:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/3b9bd72a-e939-11ee-8202-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>My father&amp;rsquo;s diary left me wondering whether he was a killer Saul Wordsworth&amp;rsquo;s father Christopher may have taken a terrible secret to his grave. He knew all about his quick temper and explosive outbursts of rage. But a set of his diaries inherited by Saul hinted at something altogether darker. The passage she highlighted referred to hiding a body until a search party had gone.&#xA;Growing up in Harpenden, Hertfordshire, Saul knew his father as a teller of tall tales.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>South Africa&#39;s deadly love affair with guns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b20ae44c-e938-11ee-89d2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b20ae44c-e938-11ee-89d2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>South Africa&amp;rsquo;s deadly love affair with guns Penson Menson has been carrying a gun wherever he goes in South Africa. He says he has had to use his gun multiple times to protect himself. Menson: &amp;ldquo;I never know when I will be attacked by someone who wants to kill me&amp;rdquo; He says the police and government have failed to do enough to protect the public. South African law states that most people with a gun licence can carry a firearm if it is concealed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man killed in Kilkeel house named locally</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2e085288-e884-11ee-993d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 16:37:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2e085288-e884-11ee-993d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Man killed in Kilkeel house named locally Bobbie McKee, 69, was found dead in a house in Kilkeel on Thursday. A woman, also in her 60s, sustained serious head injuries in the incident. A 25-year-old man arrested on suspicion of murder and attempted murder remains in custody. DUP assembly member for South Down Diane Forsythe described a #34;lovely family#34;&amp;quot; at the centre of the incident.&#xA;However, at this time, we are not treating this as a firearms-related report.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Funeral held for teenage stabbing victim</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/831731a0-e883-11ee-86e2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 15:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/831731a0-e883-11ee-86e2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Funeral held for teenage stabbing victim Mason Rist, 15, died after being attacked by a number of people on 27 January. His best friend, Max Dixon, also died in the incident. Family and friends gathered at South Bristol Methodist Church on Thursday. Reverend Sally Spencer said the family were being &amp;lsquo;really brave and courageous&amp;rsquo; The service was held in memory of the young man who was killed in a car crash last month.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life sentence for man who murdered couple with fentanyl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/8d838856-e873-11ee-8f50-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 12:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/8d838856-e873-11ee-8f50-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Life sentence for man who murdered couple with fentanyl Stephen Baxter, 61, and his wife Carol, 64, were found dead at their home in West Mersea, Essex, in April 2023. Luke DWit, 34, used fake identities to manipulate the couple before he laced their medication with the drug, a trial at Chelmsford Crown Court heard. Describing the moment she found them dead, she said: #34;I have never known an emotional pain to physically hurt so much.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
