<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Korea on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/korea/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Korea on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 17:47:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/korea/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>North Korea censors Alan Titchmarsh&#39;s trousers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1723422c-eba8-11ee-aa05-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 17:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1723422c-eba8-11ee-aa05-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>North Korea censors Alan Titchmarsh&amp;rsquo;s trousers Central TV aired a 2010 edition of Alan Titchmarsh&amp;rsquo;s Garden Secrets for its morning audience. Jeans are seen as a symbol of western imperialism in the secretive state and as such are banned. Mr Titch marsh said the news has given him &amp;lsquo;a bit of street cred&amp;rsquo; North Korea has banned denim trousers since the 1990s. Leader Kim Jong-il declared denim trousers to be a symbol of Western imperialism.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What we know about Baltimore bridge collapse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/23e9aa22-eba9-11ee-8e16-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 15:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/23e9aa22-eba9-11ee-8e16-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What we know about Baltimore bridge collapse The Francis Scott Key Bridge was opened in 1977. It spanned the Patapsco River and Baltimore harbour. A container ship crashed into the bridge early on Tuesday morning. Between seven and 20 people are believed to be in the river.&#xA;Maryland Governor Wes Moore has declared a state of emergency. The bridge was the third longest of its type in the world. The collapse happened at around 01:30 local time (05:30 GMT) on Tuesday.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jealous K-pop fans try to dictate their idols&#39; private lives</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/221a79a4-e9da-11ee-ad6b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:07:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/221a79a4-e9da-11ee-ad6b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Jealous K-pop fans try to dictate their idols&amp;rsquo; private lives K-pop star Karina posted a handwritten apology on Instagram earlier in March. The apology came after she acknowledged that she was in a relationship with actor Lee Jae-wook. It opens a window into the world of K-pop&amp;rsquo;s super fans. They stream their favourite stars&amp;rsquo; music round the clock to boost chart rankings.&#xA;When news of Karina&amp;rsquo;s relationship broke, some fans drove a truck to her management agency.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Squid Game actor found guilty of sexual misconduct</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/e67dfb24-e2d0-11ee-8ceb-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 09:47:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/e67dfb24-e2d0-11ee-8ceb-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Squid Game actor found guilty of sexual misconduct The 79-year-old was charged in 2022 with sexually assaulting a woman twice. The assaults took place five years earlier when O was staying in a rural area for a theatre performance in 2017. O has said he will appeal against the verdict and has seven days to do so. O had denied the claims which, according to Suwon District Court, took place on a walking path and in front of the victim#39;s residence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The hidden village just metres from North Korea</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/81d9178a-e127-11ee-9990-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 23:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/81d9178a-e127-11ee-9990-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The hidden village just metres from North Korea Gyung-ho lives in the only South Korean village in the Demilitarised Zone. The strip of no-man#39;s land separating North and South Korea is one of the most militarised places on earth. It was created in 1953, after the Korean War, to keep the two armies apart. Freedom Village and Peace Village sit within Korea#39;s Demilitarised Zone.&#xA;They were supposed to signal that the DMZ was temporary and one day soon Korea would be reunified.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
