<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uk on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uk on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 12:53:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Holidaymakers caught out by 10-year-passport rule</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/317250c2-ec3a-11ee-a406-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 12:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/317250c2-ec3a-11ee-a406-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Holidaymakers caught out by 10-year-passport rule UK travellers used to be able to carry up to nine months from an old passport over to a new one. But post-Brexit, EU countries will not accept passports issued more than 10 years ago. 32 million people had applied for passports that if granted would be over 10 years old. Since the UK left the EU, travellers heading to all countries within the zone must have a passport which was issued less than 10 years before their departure date.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bankers jailed for interest rate rigging lose appeal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/835bf43c-ec3b-11ee-b250-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 12:46:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/835bf43c-ec3b-11ee-b250-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Bankers jailed for interest rate rigging lose appeal Tom Hayes and Carlo Palombo were among 37 City traders prosecuted for manipulating rate benchmarks, Libor and Euribor. Both men spent time in prison before being released in 2021. Their case went before the Appeal Court after a judge in the US overturned similar convictions there. The traders say they will now apply to take their cases to the Supreme Court.&#xA;This was also dismissed by the High Court in London.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Banksy tree mural covered in plastic and boards</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/3b339d3a-ec3c-11ee-9072-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 12:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/3b339d3a-ec3c-11ee-9072-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Banksy tree mural covered in plastic and boards The artwork in Finsbury Park features swathes of green paint on a residential building behind a nearby tree. The mural was claimed by the street artist on social media but just days later was strewn with white paint. Islington council said the plastic and boards had been put up by the building&amp;rsquo;s owner, not the council. Güley Polat travelled to see the mural from Germany.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VisitScotland to close all information centres</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b609b488-ec3f-11ee-8464-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 12:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b609b488-ec3f-11ee-8464-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>VisitScotland to close all information centres VisitScotland will close its 25 information centres over the next two years. The iCentres will operate as usual until the end of September. The move follows the closure of 39 tourist offices between 2017 and 2019. There will be no compulsory redundancies as a result of the shift to a digital first strategy.&#xA;The iCentres currently operate during office hours and offer booklets and leaflets promoting specific locations, landmarks and attractions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Veteran MP cleared of flouting Covid-19 rules</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/575a6c0c-ec3a-11ee-9367-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 11:54:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/575a6c0c-ec3a-11ee-9367-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Veteran MP cleared of flouting Covid-19 rules Sir Bernard Jenkin was alleged to have attended an event on the Parliamentary estate in December 2020. A report confirmed a WhatsApp invite to birthday drinks had been sent by his then-wife Baroness Jenkin. But it concluded the event was socially-distanced with &amp;ldquo;business and social elements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comic swaps hot dog for cucumber over Tube ad rule</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/57d9b556-ec40-11ee-8c5d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 11:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/57d9b556-ec40-11ee-8c5d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Comic swaps hot dog for cucumber over Tube ad rule TfL does not allow foods high in fat, sugar and salt to be advertised on its network. It was brought in by City Hall to help tackle child obesity rates. The ban spans the Underground and Overground, as well as buses and bus shelters. A spokesperson for TfL said: ‘We are happy to work with people to ensure adverts follow our policy’ Follow BBC London on Facebook, Twitter and Instagram.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Funeral inquiry firm faces wind up order over debt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/72d40f98-ec43-11ee-b636-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 11:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/72d40f98-ec43-11ee-b636-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Funeral inquiry firm faces wind up order over debt Hull City Council said its petition against Legacy Independent Funeral Directors would be considered at a court hearing on 9 April 2024. The firm owed the authority £51,508. 46 for unpaid charges including cremation fees. Two people are on bail after a police investigation into the company began on 6 March.&#xA;Legacy allegedly racked up nearly £55,000 in debt, of which £2,000 is said to be owed to East Riding of Yorkshire Council for unpaid burial fees.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is sewage released into rivers and the sea?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/e1d4ea70-ec3e-11ee-bee2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 11:06:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/e1d4ea70-ec3e-11ee-bee2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Why is sewage released into rivers and the sea? Sewage spills into England&amp;rsquo;s rivers and seas by water companies more than doubled in 2023. There were 3.6 million hours of spills, compared to 1.75 million hours in 2022.&#xA;Water UK, the industry body for sewerage companies, said record levels were due to heavy rain and increased data collection.Most of the UK has a combined sewerage system, meaning rainwater and wastewater are carried in the same pipes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supply chain fears after crash</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a6a5a5e0-ec3c-11ee-96e8-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 10:59:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a6a5a5e0-ec3c-11ee-96e8-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Supply chain fears after crash The ship, named the Dali, hit a support column of the Francis Scott Key Bridge in the early hours of Tuesday morning. The bridge spanned the entrance to the Port of Baltimore, the busiest port in the US for car exports. More than 750,000 cars and vehicles passed through Baltimore in the last year. Baltimore is the busiest US port for car shipments.&#xA;It is also the largest US port by volume for handling farm and construction machinery.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Father of three among victims on the bridge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6c6d4fd6-ec3c-11ee-bb54-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 10:38:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6c6d4fd6-ec3c-11ee-bb54-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Father of three among victims on the bridge The US Coast Guard said late on Tuesday that it had concluded the men had died and intended to suspend its massive search and rescue effort. All are believed to be members of a crew working on the bridge and are citizens of Latin American countries. Local media has reported that the six workers were citizens of Mexico, Guatemala, Honduras and El Salvador.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Record sewage spills into England&#39;s rivers and seas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/571621b8-ec3b-11ee-9ffb-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 10:31:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/571621b8-ec3b-11ee-9ffb-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Record sewage spills into England&amp;rsquo;s rivers and seas Sewage spills into England&amp;rsquo;s rivers and seas by water companies more than doubled last year. According to the Environment Agency there were 3. 6 million hours of spills compared to 1. 75 million hours in 2022.&#xA;Water UK, the industry body for sewerage companies, said the record levels were due to heavy rain. These spills are not illegal but environmentalists say they should only happen in exceptional weather.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MPs warn of &#39;fleecehold&#39; on new housing estates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/d1e3f100-ec3a-11ee-a8c6-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 10:21:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/d1e3f100-ec3a-11ee-a8c6-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>MPs warn of &amp;lsquo;fleecehold&amp;rsquo; on new housing estates 46 Tories, including two former housing ministers, call for ban on such arrangements. Leasehold Bill is working its way through Parliament and will be debated in the Lords on Wednesday. Up to four million people are now thought to be living on such estates. Mr Gove has labelled leaseholds &amp;ldquo;an outdated feudal system.&#xA;Ms Kendrick said a nominal ground rent had historically been the norm.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public satisfaction with NHS at lowest ever level</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/d07204be-ec3b-11ee-bb42-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 07:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/d07204be-ec3b-11ee-bb42-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Public satisfaction with NHS at lowest ever level Just 24% said they were satisfied with the NHS in 2023, with waiting times and staff shortages the biggest concerns. That is five percentage points down on last year and a drop from the 2010 high of 70% satisfaction. More than 3,000 people were polled by the National Centre for Social Research across England, Wales and Scotland. Of the core services, the public was least satisfied with Aamp;E and dentistry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sharleen Spiteri finds magic in Muscle Shoals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/4a6a3ab8-ec3f-11ee-8777-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 01:59:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/4a6a3ab8-ec3f-11ee-8777-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Sharleen Spiteri finds magic in Muscle Shoals Muscle Shoals was an unlikely staging post for rock and Ramp;B royalty in the 1960s and 70s. The Swampers were a crack team of studio musicians whose rich, funky Southern grooves infused classics like Aretha Franklin&amp;rsquo;s Respect. Local radio station WLAY was unusual for playing music by both white and black artists. The colour-blind approach was duplicated in the local recording studios.&#xA;Muscle Shoals sound was a product of geography, says former curator of Alabama&amp;rsquo;s Music Hall of Fame, George Lair.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Church limited Clapham attacker&#39;s attendance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2de41b4c-eba5-11ee-8487-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 18:36:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2de41b4c-eba5-11ee-8487-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Church limited Clapham attacker&amp;rsquo;s attendance Abdul Shokoor Ezedi, 35, arrived in the UK in 2016 from Afghanistan. He was granted asylum after two applications and an appeal. A key factor was his June 2018 baptism at Grange Road Baptist Church in Jarrow. He won asylum in 2020 after proving his conversion to Christianity.&#xA;The letter was sent to the First Tier Tribunal, which handles asylum applications. It was sent eight months after the case was referred to the tribunal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>North Korea censors Alan Titchmarsh&#39;s trousers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1723422c-eba8-11ee-aa05-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 17:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1723422c-eba8-11ee-aa05-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>North Korea censors Alan Titchmarsh&amp;rsquo;s trousers Central TV aired a 2010 edition of Alan Titchmarsh&amp;rsquo;s Garden Secrets for its morning audience. Jeans are seen as a symbol of western imperialism in the secretive state and as such are banned. Mr Titch marsh said the news has given him &amp;lsquo;a bit of street cred&amp;rsquo; North Korea has banned denim trousers since the 1990s. Leader Kim Jong-il declared denim trousers to be a symbol of Western imperialism.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Springsteen first US musician to land Ivors honour</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/84f37efc-ebad-11ee-ae76-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 17:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/84f37efc-ebad-11ee-ae76-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Springsteen first US musician to land Ivors honour The star will be the first US musician to be given the prize. The prize recognises writing that has enriched the cultural fabric of the UK. Only 24 other people have ever received the fellowship, including Sir Elton John, Sir Paul McCartney and Kate Bush. Last year, the prize went to Sting, who used the opportunity to warn of the dangers that AI posed to songwriters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Care worker migrant surge &#39;should&#39;ve been obvious&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2318f72a-ebad-11ee-8b5a-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 16:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2318f72a-ebad-11ee-8b5a-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Care worker migrant surge &amp;lsquo;should&amp;rsquo;ve been obvious&amp;rsquo; The Home Office has a limited understanding of the social care system. It &amp;ldquo;should have been obvious that lots of migrants would arrive for jobs in care, the former borders watchdog has said. The Home Office says it has a ‘limited understanding’ of social care. David Neal says the immigration system has invited large numbers of low-skilled care workers into the UK.&#xA;His findings are in a report published after he was sacked.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assange judges seek no death penalty pledge from US</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/d41bbf10-eba5-11ee-bafb-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 16:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/d41bbf10-eba5-11ee-bafb-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Assange judges seek no death penalty pledge from US US authorities say Mr Assange endangered lives by publishing thousands of classified documents. His lawyers have argued that the case is a form of &amp;ldquo;state retaliation. The court adjourned its final decision on Mr Assange&amp;rsquo;s extradition by three weeks to give the US government time to comply with its order. Wikileaks published confidential US documents in 2010 and 2011.&#xA;Mr Assange was widely condemned for failing to redact the names of intelligence operatives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK approach to China is &#39;robust&#39;, Sunak says</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/c2f7f2e6-ebad-11ee-bd07-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 15:37:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/c2f7f2e6-ebad-11ee-bd07-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>UK approach to China is &amp;lsquo;robust&amp;rsquo;, Sunak says Prime Minister Rishi Sunak defended the government&amp;rsquo;s approach to China. Comes after some MPs criticised the response to cyber-attacks against the Electoral Commission and UK politicians. The government has blamed the attacks on Beijing-linked hackers. Downing Street has played down suggestions the government is preparing to do this.&#xA;Prime Minister says EU countries have gone further in protecting themselves. He says China represents the greatest state-based threat to our economic security.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do I know if my smart meter is broken?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/5e53f3b8-ec42-11ee-8bcf-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 15:17:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/5e53f3b8-ec42-11ee-8bcf-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How do I know if my smart meter is broken? Faulty meters can mean customers rely on estimated bills. Almost four million smart meters in Great Britain were not working at the end of 2023, according to government data. Smart meters measure how much gas and electricity you use. Some customers are paying too much and struggling to get money back.&#xA;Smart meters usually come with an in-home display, which can help you track how much energy you&amp;rsquo;re using.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do I know if my smart meter is broken?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f13ea034-ebab-11ee-a756-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 15:17:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f13ea034-ebab-11ee-a756-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How do I know if my smart meter is broken? Faulty meters can mean customers rely on estimated bills. Almost four million smart meters in Great Britain were not working at the end of 2023, according to government data. Smart meters measure how much gas and electricity you use. Some customers are paying too much and struggling to get money back.&#xA;Smart meters usually come with an in-home display, which can help you track how much energy you&amp;rsquo;re using.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ferguson boss sacked as more ferry delays &#39;likely&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/098e3b90-ebb1-11ee-b2d3-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 14:46:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/098e3b90-ebb1-11ee-b2d3-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Ferguson boss sacked as more ferry delays &amp;rsquo;likely&#39; Chief executive David Tydeman&amp;rsquo;s contract was terminated by Ferguson Marine. The board attempt to ensure the company&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;long-term future. The company is building two delayed and over-budget CalMac ferries. The first of the two ferries is due to be completed by the end of the year.&#xA;Mr Tydeman joined the Port Glasgow shipyard in 2022. The exact reasons for his departure have not been revealed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Border Force response to Hamas attack victims probed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f3dcb824-ebad-11ee-aec4-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 14:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f3dcb824-ebad-11ee-aec4-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Border Force response to Hamas attack victims probed The Jewish Representative Council for Greater Manchester said two Israeli nationals had faced aggressive questioning by UK Border Force officials at Manchester Airport. The Home Office has launched a review. About 1,200 people were killed when Hamas militia stormed across Gaza&amp;rsquo;s border into Israel on 7 October in coordinated attacks. Manchester Airport said it was in touch with the Home Office.&#xA;Mr Cleverly replied on the social media platform: &amp;ldquo;We do not tolerate antisemitism or any form of discrimination.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Papa Johns pizza to shut nearly a tenth of UK sites</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/4f779a10-ebad-11ee-9c6e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 13:37:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/4f779a10-ebad-11ee-9c6e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Papa Johns pizza to shut nearly a tenth of UK sites Papa Johns says 43 of its restaurants are &amp;rsquo;no longer financially viable&amp;rsquo; The chain has 450 restaurants plus others in service stations and holiday parks. It has not said how many jobs will be hit by the closures. Revolution Bars has said it could sell all or part of its outlets. The closures are all in England and extend from Harrogate, North Yorkshire to St Helens, Merseyside, Billericay, Essex and Eastbourne, East Sussex.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who is Julian Assange and why is he facing extradition?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/5a69d3b4-ebaa-11ee-987b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 11:50:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/5a69d3b4-ebaa-11ee-987b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Who is Julian Assange and why is he facing extradition? Julian Assange will find out on 20 May whether he will be extradited to the US. The UK courts had agreed to send him to be tried for disclosing military secrets. But he asked the High Court for permission to appeal against that decision. Mr Assange gained a reputation for computer programming as a teenager.&#xA;WikiLeaks published documents that suggested the US military had killed hundreds of civilians in unreported incidents during the war in Afghanistan.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can my landlord put up my rent, keep my deposit or evict me?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b8165262-ebaf-11ee-89d9-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 12:07:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b8165262-ebaf-11ee-89d9-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Can my landlord put up my rent, keep my deposit or evict me? The average cost of renting in the UK rose by 9% in the year to February. It is the highest annual increase since records began in 2015. Most tenants in England and Wales have an assured shorthold tenancy. About one in five households have a guaranteed tenancy in England.&#xA;Renting rules are different in England, Scotland, Wales and Northern Ireland.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyber-attack on voter data to be linked to China</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/44d44742-ea9b-11ee-911e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 10:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/44d44742-ea9b-11ee-911e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Cyber-attack on voter data to be linked to China The attacks on the Electoral Commission took place in August 2021 but were only revealed last year. Several MPs and peers who have been critical of Beijing are thought to have also been targeted in cyber-attacks. Deputy Prime Minister Oliver Dowden will address Parliament on Monday about the threat. It is now thought that Mr Dowden will suggest those behind the attack had links to Beijing, as well as laying out how the UK will respond to what it deems a wider threat.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;It&#39;s on another level, completely alien in darts&#39; - the rapid rise of Luke Littler</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/3b8497fa-eaa0-11ee-9e7d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 10:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/3b8497fa-eaa0-11ee-9e7d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;It&amp;rsquo;s on another level, completely alien in darts&amp;rsquo; - the rapid rise of Luke Littler Luke Littler is the youngest ever PDC World Championship finalist. The 17-year-old has earned more than £350,000 in prize money in the past three months. His manager is Martin Foulds, whose ZXF Sports Management firm also looks after other top players including World Matchplay champion Nathan Aspinall. Darts star says travelling can take its toll on players.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NI sees 20% rise in 18-49 cancer diagnoses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6d30635a-eaa6-11ee-aa18-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 07:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6d30635a-eaa6-11ee-aa18-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>NI sees 20% rise in 18-49 cancer diagnoses Figures show that, by 2019, 1,076 people aged 18-49 were diagnosed with some form of cancer. Prof Helen Coleman, who was involved in the research, said it was worrying. The research looked at early onset cancers, which means cancers diagnosed in adults under the age of 50. Cancers commonly seen in older people are now being diagnosed in younger adults.&#xA;The rise has also been seen in other western countries such as across the UK, America and Australia.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Murder arrest at Heathrow after man hit by car</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/952dfe2a-eaa2-11ee-9248-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 21:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/952dfe2a-eaa2-11ee-9248-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Murder arrest at Heathrow after man hit by car Man, 35, found injured at the scene near the junction with Arragon Road. A 33-year-old man was arrested at the airport on suspicion of assisting an offender. Police are appealing for witnesses to the incident in Barking Road, east London, to come forward. Police do not believe there to be any risk to the wider community.&#xA;Officers will remain in the area over the coming days to provide reassurance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Triple lock for pensions stays if we win election, says Hunt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/797475ea-e9d7-11ee-8213-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 11:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/797475ea-e9d7-11ee-8213-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Triple lock for pensions stays if we win election, says Hunt Jeremy Hunt confirms the policy pledge on the BBC&amp;rsquo;s Sunday with Laura Kuenssberg. It means the increase in the state pension is the highest of average earnings, inflation or 2. 5%. Mr Hunt said he was confident the promise would be paid for by his plans to grow the economy.&#xA;The state pension is a payment made every four weeks by the government to people who have reached the qualifying age.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>William and Kate &#39;enormously touched&#39; by public support</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f87186f8-e9d7-11ee-a529-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 10:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f87186f8-e9d7-11ee-a529-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>William and Kate &amp;rsquo;enormously touched&amp;rsquo; by public support Catherine revealed in a video message on Friday that she had begun treatment. The Prince and Princess of Wales are &amp;rsquo;enormously touched&amp;rsquo; by the kind messages. They are &amp;lsquo;grateful&amp;rsquo; that the public have understood their request for privacy, Kensington Palace said. Catherine received her diagnosis after tests carried out following abdominal surgery.&#xA;A spokesperson for Kensington Palace said: &amp;ldquo;The Prince and Princess are both enormously touched by the kind messages from people here in the UK, across the Commonwealth and around the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sainz wins in Australia after Verstappen retires</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/80588798-e9e6-11ee-a174-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 08:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/80588798-e9e6-11ee-a174-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Sainz wins in Australia after Verstappen retires Carlos Sainz leads Charles Leclerc to a Ferrari one-two in the Australian Grand Prix. Max Verstappen retires with a brake failure after just four laps. The race ended under a virtual safety car after a crash for George Russell. The Mercedes driver lost control at Turn Six on the final lap.&#xA;Alonso and Russell were called to the stewards, who penalised the Spaniard 20 seconds, dropping him to eighth place.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hygiene poverty is a sign of crisis, says charity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6b9b6f5a-e9e1-11ee-b81f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 07:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6b9b6f5a-e9e1-11ee-b81f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Hygiene poverty is a sign of crisis, says charity The Hygiene Bank helps people who cannot afford basic essential toiletries. A new survey found that more than three million people in the UK are thought to be experiencing hygiene poverty. Volunteers at one of the charity&amp;rsquo;s schemes, in Bromley, south-east London, said a school washed pupils&amp;rsquo; clothes. The charity receives donations from the community, which are sorted by volunteers.&#xA;34;It often the first sign that a family is falling into crisis when they can&amp;rsquo;t afford these basic essentials,’ she said.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Outpouring of support for Kate after cancer news</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/7cbeb2ee-e93a-11ee-8e3c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 14:43:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/7cbeb2ee-e93a-11ee-8e3c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Outpouring of support for Kate after cancer news Princess of Wales reveals she is being treated for cancer. She has been receiving chemotherapy since late February. Cancer charities have praised her openness, while world leaders, friends and celebrities have wished her well. The news has also led to calls for her and her family to be given privacy.&#xA;Catherine said she and Prince William had taken time to sensitively share the state of her health with their children.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harry and Meghan reach out to Kate after cancer news</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/9da0ab50-e92d-11ee-91e4-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 13:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/9da0ab50-e92d-11ee-91e4-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Harry and Meghan reach out to Kate after cancer news The Duke and Duchess of Sussex have reached out to the Prince and Princess of Wales, the BBC understands. The contact is understood to have been made privately. Prince Harry and Meghan said they wished health and healing for Catherine. The princess is confident that she will make a full recovery.&#xA;Catherine had abdominal surgery in January, but it was not known then there was any cancer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>London landmarks join Earth Hour lights switch-off</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6626ea82-e93b-11ee-847b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 07:36:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6626ea82-e93b-11ee-847b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>London landmarks join Earth Hour lights switch-off The annual Earth Hour, spearheaded by the World Wide Fund for Nature (WWF), is observed around the world. Previous years have seen Big Ben, the Eiffel Tower, and the Sydney Opera House turn out the lights. WWF suggests individuals use the 60 minutes, between 20:30 and 21:30, to do something positive for the planet. Lit-up landmarks that will go dark for the hour include the Barbican Arts Centre, the Old Bailey, Tower Bridge, and the OXO Tower.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First UK-funded field hospital opens in Gaza</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1dbf0070-e93d-11ee-835e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 05:27:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1dbf0070-e93d-11ee-835e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>First UK-funded field hospital opens in Gaza The facility is based near Rafah, where 1. 5 million Palestinians are crammed in, having fled other parts of Gaza. It has been set up by the aid organisation UK-Med, which deploys many NHS staff to international emergencies. It will eventually cover the size of two football fields, but getting started hasn&amp;rsquo;t been easy.&#xA;UK-Med is already running mobile clinics that go out into the community in Gaza.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Oasis&#39; first tour venues, 30 years on</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/5549aa36-e938-11ee-9fbf-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 02:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/5549aa36-e938-11ee-9fbf-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Revisiting Oasis&amp;rsquo; first tour venues, 30 years on Exactly 30 years ago, a little-known band called Oasis set out on their first headline tour. Mark Davyd was asked to book a gig by a rising Scottish band called Whiteout at his venue in Kent in March 1994. He wasn#39;t keen when he found out that an unfamiliar Mancunian group would also be on the bill. He wanted to put on a local support act instead - but the agent stressed it was a joint headlined tour.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is preventative chemotherapy?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/333f5aa0-e936-11ee-8a4f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 19:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/333f5aa0-e936-11ee-8a4f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What is preventative chemotherapy? Catherine, Princess of Wales, says she is having treatment for cancer. It was discovered following major abdominal surgery in January. She started preventative chemotherapy in late February. Kensington Palace has not said what type of cancer she has.&#xA;The princess has a right to medical privacy as we all do, a spokesperson said. After the surgery in January, which Kensington Palace says was successful, doctors performed tests which revealed cancer had been present.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FA defends new England kit over flag design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/176deb02-e873-11ee-9c81-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 16:21:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/176deb02-e873-11ee-9c81-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>FA defends new England kit over flag design The FA has defended the St George#39;s Cross design on its new England kit. The body said it understood what the flag #34;means to our fans. It added the fresh 2024 home kit was meant as a tribute to the 1966 World Cup winning team. Prime Minister Rishi Sunak said he preferred the original and the national flag was a source of pride and identity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FA defends new England kit over flag design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/44d98486-e885-11ee-8bab-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 16:21:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/44d98486-e885-11ee-8bab-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>FA defends new England kit over flag design The FA has defended the St George#39;s Cross design on its new England kit. The body said it understood what the flag #34;means to our fans. Nike said its design was to celebrate the 1966 World Cup team. Both the prime minister and Labour leader criticised the design.&#xA;Prime Minister Rishi Sunak said he preferred the original and the national flag was a source of pride and identity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nationwide payments back to normal after delays</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/acfe1486-e87c-11ee-953f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 16:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/acfe1486-e87c-11ee-953f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Nationwide payments back to normal after delays Customers of UK;s biggest building society reported a range of problems, including transferring money and buying a train ticket. Nationwide says the IT issue has now been resolved but payment backlogs took a few hours to clear. Firm is currently trying to buy Virgin Money in a £2. 9bn deal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life sentence for man who murdered couple with fentanyl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/8d838856-e873-11ee-8f50-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 12:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/8d838856-e873-11ee-8f50-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Life sentence for man who murdered couple with fentanyl Stephen Baxter, 61, and his wife Carol, 64, were found dead at their home in West Mersea, Essex, in April 2023. Luke DWit, 34, used fake identities to manipulate the couple before he laced their medication with the drug, a trial at Chelmsford Crown Court heard. Describing the moment she found them dead, she said: #34;I have never known an emotional pain to physically hurt so much.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wetherspoon profits jump as Covid recovery continues</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/fa766094-e875-11ee-b0e5-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 12:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/fa766094-e875-11ee-b0e5-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Wetherspoon profits jump as Covid recovery continues Pre-tax profits leapt from £4. 6m to £36m in the first six months of the financial year. The biggest sellers for the chain, which has 814 pubs, were coffee and Pepsi. Shares in the company dropped 6% as a result.&#xA;Wetherspoon has cut its number of pubs from 955 a few years ago, since when sales per pub have increased by about 50%. But profits growth was in comparison with a low base, says Derren Nathan, head of equity research at Hargreaves Lansdown.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UFC star squares faith with a career in the octagon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/143f1d5e-e87b-11ee-af5d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 11:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/143f1d5e-e87b-11ee-af5d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>UFC star squares faith with a career in the octagon Muhammad Mokaev is one of the biggest names in UFC right now. The 23-year-old is one step closer to a UFC flyweight title opportunity. He talks to BBC Asian Network about the importance of his faith during Ramadan, a month of spiritual reflection for Muslims. Mokaev arrived from Russia aged 12, shortly after his mum died.&#xA;He first lived in a refugee shelter in Liverpool, before moving to Wigan.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MacIntyre taunts American hosts with Ryder Cup score</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a2e0ddc6-e886-11ee-866f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 09:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a2e0ddc6-e886-11ee-866f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>MacIntyre taunts American hosts with Ryder Cup score MacIntyre took advantage of a quirk of the tournament that allows players to choose wording for their caddie#39;s bib. The Scot opted for #39:EUR 16. 5-11. 5 USA and posted it on Twitter.&#xA;MacIntyre, 27, was unbeaten with two and a half points at the Marco Simone Country Club as Luke Donald#39;s side won back the Ryder Cup. He did not pair up with English caddie Mike Burrows until a month later.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘I want to help people fly – and keep them safe’</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/e6ebbf80-e87d-11ee-847b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/e6ebbf80-e87d-11ee-847b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>‘I want to help people fly – and keep them safe’ Pooja Umashankar has returned from Sri Lanka to study aircraft maintenance engineering at the University of South Wales. For years, airlines and engineering firms have struggled to hire maintenance engineers. There is now a global shortage numbering in the tens of thousands, and aviation is expected to balloon in coming decades. Around 700,000 engineers will have to enter the profession between now and 2040.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do interest rates affect me?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/25676a5e-ebb0-11ee-b4fb-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 12:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/25676a5e-ebb0-11ee-b4fb-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How do interest rates affect me? Interest rates set by the Bank of England affect mortgage, credit card and savings rates for millions of people across the UK. The base rate, currently 5. 25%, is what it charges other lenders to borrow money. It has a target to keep UK inflation at 2%.&#xA;The Bank may decide to raise rates to encourage people to spend less. The idea is that this helps to bring inflation down by dampening demand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do interest rates affect me?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/e7495566-e880-11ee-9cf3-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 12:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/e7495566-e880-11ee-9cf3-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How do interest rates affect me? Interest rates set by the Bank of England affect mortgage, credit card and savings rates for millions of people across the UK. The base rate, currently 5. 25%, is what it charges other lenders to borrow money. It has a target to keep UK inflation at 2%.&#xA;The Bank may decide to raise rates to encourage people to spend less. The idea is that this helps to bring inflation down by dampening demand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All you need to know about April train strikes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1e009d84-e882-11ee-9d43-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 14:23:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1e009d84-e882-11ee-9d43-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>All you need to know about April train strikes Train drivers at 16 train firms will take part in rolling one-day walk outs between 5 and 8 April. London Underground drivers will strike on Monday 8 April and Saturday 4 May. Aslef members will also refuse to work on rest days from Thursday 4 to Saturday 6 April and from Monday 8 to Tuesday 9 April. Rail passengers with advance tickets can be refunded fee-free if the train they are booked on is cancelled, delayed or rescheduled due to strikes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who gets 15 hours of free childcare and when do I apply?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2a722096-e883-11ee-93c8-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 14:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2a722096-e883-11ee-93c8-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Who gets 15 hours of free childcare and when do I apply? Working parents in England can apply for 15 hours of free weekly childcare for their two-year-olds. The government hopes that extending free childcare to this age group from April 2024 - and to all under-5s in 2025 - will get more parents back to work. Extra help with childcare costs is being rolled out in stages. The help you can get depends on the age of your child, and whether you are working, or receiving certain benefits.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who gets 15 hours of free childcare and when do I apply?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2e23693e-ec43-11ee-90ec-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 14:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2e23693e-ec43-11ee-90ec-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Who gets 15 hours of free childcare and when do I apply? Working parents in England can apply for 15 hours of free weekly childcare for their two-year-olds. The government hopes that extending free childcare to this age group from April 2024 - and to all under-5s in 2025 - will get more parents back to work. Extra help with childcare costs is being rolled out in stages. The help you can get depends on the age of your child, and whether you are working, or receiving certain benefits.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How are the child benefit rules changing?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/edc09b34-ebaf-11ee-865b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 14:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/edc09b34-ebaf-11ee-865b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How are the child benefit rules changing? The government says the changes will help more than half a million families. Only one person can claim child benefit for a child. There is no limit to how many children you can claim for. Child benefit is usually paid into a nominated bank account every four weeks.&#xA;You can find out how much child benefit you may be entitled to by using the government calculator.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What can I do if I can&#39;t pay my energy bill?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/498978b0-ebaf-11ee-9fdb-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 12:25:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/498978b0-ebaf-11ee-9fdb-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What can I do if I can&amp;rsquo;t pay my energy bill? Energy prices will fall in April, but many households will still struggle to pay their bills. Some will need to repay debt to suppliers and many will worry about future levels of financial support. For confidential support call the Samaritans in the UK on 08457 90 90 90, visit a local Samaritans branch or click here for details. From April, energy bills will fall by more than 12% for most people in England, Scotland and Wales.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What can I do if I can&#39;t pay my energy bill?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a36f8854-ec42-11ee-84a9-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 12:25:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a36f8854-ec42-11ee-84a9-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What can I do if I can&amp;rsquo;t pay my energy bill? Energy prices will fall in April, but many households will still struggle to pay their bills. Some will need to repay debt to suppliers and many will worry about future levels of financial support. For confidential support call the Samaritans in the UK on 08457 90 90 90, visit a local Samaritans branch or click here for details. From April, energy bills will fall by more than 12% for most people in England, Scotland and Wales.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which debts and bills should I pay first?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/9accd360-e881-11ee-94b2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 09:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/9accd360-e881-11ee-94b2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Which debts and bills should I pay first? 11 million adults in the UK struggle to pay their bills in January. This is a rise of 3. 1 million compared with 2022. Citizens Advice says you should work out how much you owe and who to pay.&#xA;There are what are known as priority debts and bills. If you do not pay them, you could lose your home or face court proceedings.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
