<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uk on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Uk on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 11:29:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Triple lock for pensions stays if we win election, says Hunt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/797475ea-e9d7-11ee-8213-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 11:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/797475ea-e9d7-11ee-8213-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Triple lock for pensions stays if we win election, says Hunt Jeremy Hunt confirms the policy pledge on the BBC&amp;rsquo;s Sunday with Laura Kuenssberg. It means the increase in the state pension is the highest of average earnings, inflation or 2. 5%. Mr Hunt said he was confident the promise would be paid for by his plans to grow the economy.&#xA;The state pension is a payment made every four weeks by the government to people who have reached the qualifying age.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>William and Kate &#39;enormously touched&#39; by public support</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f87186f8-e9d7-11ee-a529-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 10:55:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f87186f8-e9d7-11ee-a529-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>William and Kate &amp;rsquo;enormously touched&amp;rsquo; by public support Catherine revealed in a video message on Friday that she had begun treatment. The Prince and Princess of Wales are &amp;rsquo;enormously touched&amp;rsquo; by the kind messages. They are &amp;lsquo;grateful&amp;rsquo; that the public have understood their request for privacy, Kensington Palace said. Catherine received her diagnosis after tests carried out following abdominal surgery.&#xA;A spokesperson for Kensington Palace said: &amp;ldquo;The Prince and Princess are both enormously touched by the kind messages from people here in the UK, across the Commonwealth and around the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sainz wins in Australia after Verstappen retires</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/80588798-e9e6-11ee-a174-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 08:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/80588798-e9e6-11ee-a174-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Sainz wins in Australia after Verstappen retires Carlos Sainz leads Charles Leclerc to a Ferrari one-two in the Australian Grand Prix. Max Verstappen retires with a brake failure after just four laps. The race ended under a virtual safety car after a crash for George Russell. The Mercedes driver lost control at Turn Six on the final lap.&#xA;Alonso and Russell were called to the stewards, who penalised the Spaniard 20 seconds, dropping him to eighth place.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hygiene poverty is a sign of crisis, says charity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6b9b6f5a-e9e1-11ee-b81f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 07:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6b9b6f5a-e9e1-11ee-b81f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Hygiene poverty is a sign of crisis, says charity The Hygiene Bank helps people who cannot afford basic essential toiletries. A new survey found that more than three million people in the UK are thought to be experiencing hygiene poverty. Volunteers at one of the charity&amp;rsquo;s schemes, in Bromley, south-east London, said a school washed pupils&amp;rsquo; clothes. The charity receives donations from the community, which are sorted by volunteers.&#xA;34;It often the first sign that a family is falling into crisis when they can&amp;rsquo;t afford these basic essentials,’ she said.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Outpouring of support for Kate after cancer news</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/7cbeb2ee-e93a-11ee-8e3c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 14:43:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/7cbeb2ee-e93a-11ee-8e3c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Outpouring of support for Kate after cancer news Princess of Wales reveals she is being treated for cancer. She has been receiving chemotherapy since late February. Cancer charities have praised her openness, while world leaders, friends and celebrities have wished her well. The news has also led to calls for her and her family to be given privacy.&#xA;Catherine said she and Prince William had taken time to sensitively share the state of her health with their children.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harry and Meghan reach out to Kate after cancer news</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/9da0ab50-e92d-11ee-91e4-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 13:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/9da0ab50-e92d-11ee-91e4-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Harry and Meghan reach out to Kate after cancer news The Duke and Duchess of Sussex have reached out to the Prince and Princess of Wales, the BBC understands. The contact is understood to have been made privately. Prince Harry and Meghan said they wished health and healing for Catherine. The princess is confident that she will make a full recovery.&#xA;Catherine had abdominal surgery in January, but it was not known then there was any cancer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>London landmarks join Earth Hour lights switch-off</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6626ea82-e93b-11ee-847b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 07:36:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6626ea82-e93b-11ee-847b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>London landmarks join Earth Hour lights switch-off The annual Earth Hour, spearheaded by the World Wide Fund for Nature (WWF), is observed around the world. Previous years have seen Big Ben, the Eiffel Tower, and the Sydney Opera House turn out the lights. WWF suggests individuals use the 60 minutes, between 20:30 and 21:30, to do something positive for the planet. Lit-up landmarks that will go dark for the hour include the Barbican Arts Centre, the Old Bailey, Tower Bridge, and the OXO Tower.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First UK-funded field hospital opens in Gaza</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1dbf0070-e93d-11ee-835e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 05:27:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1dbf0070-e93d-11ee-835e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>First UK-funded field hospital opens in Gaza The facility is based near Rafah, where 1. 5 million Palestinians are crammed in, having fled other parts of Gaza. It has been set up by the aid organisation UK-Med, which deploys many NHS staff to international emergencies. It will eventually cover the size of two football fields, but getting started hasn&amp;rsquo;t been easy.&#xA;UK-Med is already running mobile clinics that go out into the community in Gaza.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Oasis&#39; first tour venues, 30 years on</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/5549aa36-e938-11ee-9fbf-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 02:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/5549aa36-e938-11ee-9fbf-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Revisiting Oasis&amp;rsquo; first tour venues, 30 years on Exactly 30 years ago, a little-known band called Oasis set out on their first headline tour. Mark Davyd was asked to book a gig by a rising Scottish band called Whiteout at his venue in Kent in March 1994. He wasn#39;t keen when he found out that an unfamiliar Mancunian group would also be on the bill. He wanted to put on a local support act instead - but the agent stressed it was a joint headlined tour.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is preventative chemotherapy?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/333f5aa0-e936-11ee-8a4f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 19:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/333f5aa0-e936-11ee-8a4f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What is preventative chemotherapy? Catherine, Princess of Wales, says she is having treatment for cancer. It was discovered following major abdominal surgery in January. She started preventative chemotherapy in late February. Kensington Palace has not said what type of cancer she has.&#xA;The princess has a right to medical privacy as we all do, a spokesperson said. After the surgery in January, which Kensington Palace says was successful, doctors performed tests which revealed cancer had been present.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FA defends new England kit over flag design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/176deb02-e873-11ee-9c81-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 16:21:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/176deb02-e873-11ee-9c81-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>FA defends new England kit over flag design The FA has defended the St George#39;s Cross design on its new England kit. The body said it understood what the flag #34;means to our fans. It added the fresh 2024 home kit was meant as a tribute to the 1966 World Cup winning team. Prime Minister Rishi Sunak said he preferred the original and the national flag was a source of pride and identity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FA defends new England kit over flag design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/44d98486-e885-11ee-8bab-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 16:21:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/44d98486-e885-11ee-8bab-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>FA defends new England kit over flag design The FA has defended the St George#39;s Cross design on its new England kit. The body said it understood what the flag #34;means to our fans. Nike said its design was to celebrate the 1966 World Cup team. Both the prime minister and Labour leader criticised the design.&#xA;Prime Minister Rishi Sunak said he preferred the original and the national flag was a source of pride and identity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nationwide payments back to normal after delays</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/acfe1486-e87c-11ee-953f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 16:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/acfe1486-e87c-11ee-953f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Nationwide payments back to normal after delays Customers of UK;s biggest building society reported a range of problems, including transferring money and buying a train ticket. Nationwide says the IT issue has now been resolved but payment backlogs took a few hours to clear. Firm is currently trying to buy Virgin Money in a £2. 9bn deal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life sentence for man who murdered couple with fentanyl</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/8d838856-e873-11ee-8f50-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 12:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/8d838856-e873-11ee-8f50-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Life sentence for man who murdered couple with fentanyl Stephen Baxter, 61, and his wife Carol, 64, were found dead at their home in West Mersea, Essex, in April 2023. Luke DWit, 34, used fake identities to manipulate the couple before he laced their medication with the drug, a trial at Chelmsford Crown Court heard. Describing the moment she found them dead, she said: #34;I have never known an emotional pain to physically hurt so much.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wetherspoon profits jump as Covid recovery continues</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/fa766094-e875-11ee-b0e5-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 12:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/fa766094-e875-11ee-b0e5-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Wetherspoon profits jump as Covid recovery continues Pre-tax profits leapt from £4. 6m to £36m in the first six months of the financial year. The biggest sellers for the chain, which has 814 pubs, were coffee and Pepsi. Shares in the company dropped 6% as a result.&#xA;Wetherspoon has cut its number of pubs from 955 a few years ago, since when sales per pub have increased by about 50%. But profits growth was in comparison with a low base, says Derren Nathan, head of equity research at Hargreaves Lansdown.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UFC star squares faith with a career in the octagon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/143f1d5e-e87b-11ee-af5d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 11:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/143f1d5e-e87b-11ee-af5d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>UFC star squares faith with a career in the octagon Muhammad Mokaev is one of the biggest names in UFC right now. The 23-year-old is one step closer to a UFC flyweight title opportunity. He talks to BBC Asian Network about the importance of his faith during Ramadan, a month of spiritual reflection for Muslims. Mokaev arrived from Russia aged 12, shortly after his mum died.&#xA;He first lived in a refugee shelter in Liverpool, before moving to Wigan.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MacIntyre taunts American hosts with Ryder Cup score</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a2e0ddc6-e886-11ee-866f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 09:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a2e0ddc6-e886-11ee-866f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>MacIntyre taunts American hosts with Ryder Cup score MacIntyre took advantage of a quirk of the tournament that allows players to choose wording for their caddie#39;s bib. The Scot opted for #39:EUR 16. 5-11. 5 USA and posted it on Twitter.&#xA;MacIntyre, 27, was unbeaten with two and a half points at the Marco Simone Country Club as Luke Donald#39;s side won back the Ryder Cup. He did not pair up with English caddie Mike Burrows until a month later.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘I want to help people fly – and keep them safe’</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/e6ebbf80-e87d-11ee-847b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/e6ebbf80-e87d-11ee-847b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>‘I want to help people fly – and keep them safe’ Pooja Umashankar has returned from Sri Lanka to study aircraft maintenance engineering at the University of South Wales. For years, airlines and engineering firms have struggled to hire maintenance engineers. There is now a global shortage numbering in the tens of thousands, and aviation is expected to balloon in coming decades. Around 700,000 engineers will have to enter the profession between now and 2040.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How do interest rates affect me?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/e7495566-e880-11ee-9cf3-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 12:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/e7495566-e880-11ee-9cf3-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How do interest rates affect me? Interest rates set by the Bank of England affect mortgage, credit card and savings rates for millions of people across the UK. The base rate, currently 5. 25%, is what it charges other lenders to borrow money. It has a target to keep UK inflation at 2%.&#xA;The Bank may decide to raise rates to encourage people to spend less. The idea is that this helps to bring inflation down by dampening demand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All you need to know about April train strikes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1e009d84-e882-11ee-9d43-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 14:23:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1e009d84-e882-11ee-9d43-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>All you need to know about April train strikes Train drivers at 16 train firms will take part in rolling one-day walk outs between 5 and 8 April. London Underground drivers will strike on Monday 8 April and Saturday 4 May. Aslef members will also refuse to work on rest days from Thursday 4 to Saturday 6 April and from Monday 8 to Tuesday 9 April. Rail passengers with advance tickets can be refunded fee-free if the train they are booked on is cancelled, delayed or rescheduled due to strikes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who gets 15 hours of free childcare and when do I apply?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2a722096-e883-11ee-93c8-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 14:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2a722096-e883-11ee-93c8-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Who gets 15 hours of free childcare and when do I apply? Working parents in England can apply for 15 hours of free weekly childcare for their two-year-olds. The government hopes that extending free childcare to this age group from April 2024 - and to all under-5s in 2025 - will get more parents back to work. Extra help with childcare costs is being rolled out in stages. The help you can get depends on the age of your child, and whether you are working, or receiving certain benefits.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which debts and bills should I pay first?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/9accd360-e881-11ee-94b2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 09:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/9accd360-e881-11ee-94b2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Which debts and bills should I pay first? 11 million adults in the UK struggle to pay their bills in January. This is a rise of 3. 1 million compared with 2022. Citizens Advice says you should work out how much you owe and who to pay.&#xA;There are what are known as priority debts and bills. If you do not pay them, you could lose your home or face court proceedings.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
