<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oscars on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/oscars/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oscars on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 04:17:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/oscars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Seven of the best moments from the Oscars</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/575c2a0a-dfac-11ee-a5b3-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 04:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/575c2a0a-dfac-11ee-a5b3-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Seven of the best moments from the Oscars Ryan Gosling sang I&amp;rsquo;m Just Ken at the Oscars. The full-throated rendition of the hit was even better than we could have hoped for. Slash appeared to lend his talents for a guitar solo. The Oscars brought more than three hours of glamour and nudity.&#xA;The Kenergy was infectious - Gosling solicited energetic singalongs from the star-studded front row. There were even suggestions the choreography was a homage to Diamonds Are A Girl&amp;rsquo;s Best Friend.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top director makes Gaza statement in Oscars speech on night of protests</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/71197878-dfaf-11ee-8817-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 02:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/71197878-dfaf-11ee-8817-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Top director makes Gaza statement in Oscars speech on night of protests Protesters block traffic outside the Dolby Theatre in London. Around 1,000 people took part in the demonstration outside the venue. Celebrities, including Billie Eilish, also wore pins calling for a ceasefire. The Zone of Interest won the best international film award at the Oscars.&#xA;The German-language film focuses on the family of Auschwitz commandant Rudolf Höss. An estimated 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The outfits: Best actress Emma Stone and others show off classic styles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/eb426ee2-dfa6-11ee-b146-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 02:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/eb426ee2-dfa6-11ee-b146-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The outfits: Best actress Emma Stone and others show off classic styles Emma Stone was among the best-dressed in a custom Louis Vuitton pale mint peplum gown. Margot Robbie was controversially not nominated for her role in Barbie, but she was one of the fashion winners in a black sequined Versace gown. America Ferrera wore a shimmering pink gown in a tribute to Barbie. The singer won best song for her Barbie theme What Was I Made For?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winnie the Pooh slasher movie named worst film</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/06f9e7de-de47-11ee-9b37-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 11:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/06f9e7de-de47-11ee-9b37-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Winnie the Pooh slasher movie named worst film Winnie the Pooh: Blood and Honey wins five of the 10 categories. Sylvester Stallone &amp;rsquo;s Expend4bles also picked up two awards. The Razzies name and shame the year’s worst films. The organisers describe their awards as the &amp;ldquo;ugly cousin to the Oscars.&#xA;Rhys Frake-Waterfield, who won worst director, has announced a sequel. Pooh and Piglet, depicted in the film as blood-thirsty killers, also won worst on-screen couple.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winnie the Pooh slasher movie named worst film</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6eb41d70-de76-11ee-b676-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 11:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6eb41d70-de76-11ee-b676-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Winnie the Pooh slasher movie named worst film Winnie the Pooh: Blood and Honey wins five of the 10 categories. Sylvester Stallone &amp;rsquo;s Expend4bles also picked up two awards. The Razzies name and shame the year’s worst films. The organisers describe their awards as the &amp;ldquo;ugly cousin to the Oscars.&#xA;Rhys Frake-Waterfield, who won worst director, has announced a sequel. Pooh and Piglet, depicted in the film as blood-thirsty killers, also won worst on-screen couple.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Oppenheimer story that won&#39;t win Oscars</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/cf15ce9c-de77-11ee-8c84-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 01:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/cf15ce9c-de77-11ee-8c84-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The Oppenheimer story that won&amp;rsquo;t win Oscars Tina Cordova lives in Albuquerque, about a two-hour drive from where the atomic bomb was developed. She is one of the &amp;ldquo;Downwinders,&amp;rdquo;&amp;quot; a term used to describe the communities who claim to have been affected by radiation from the Trinity Test. The test is the centrepiece of Christopher Nolan&amp;rsquo;s box office hit, Oppenheimer. It follows the physicist of the same name and his team of scientists and engineers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Brit up for three visual effects Oscars</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/0e710eb2-dee6-11ee-9826-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 01:20:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/0e710eb2-dee6-11ee-9826-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The Brit up for three visual effects Oscars It&amp;rsquo;s not every day you get nominated for an Oscar. The Oscar nominations were announced on Sunday. The ceremony will take place in Los Angeles on February 26. The Oscars will be held at the Dolby Theatre on February 28.&#xA;For more information on the Oscars, go to www. Oscars. com. Neil Corbould is recognised for his work on Mission Impossible: Dead Reckoning Part One, The Creator and Napoleon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Hugh right about Oscar films being &#39;frankly too long&#39;?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/d71595b0-dee4-11ee-82c6-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/d71595b0-dee4-11ee-82c6-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Is Hugh right about Oscar films being &amp;lsquo;frankly too long&amp;rsquo;? Hugh Grant openly questions length of this year&amp;rsquo;s awards season contenders. Christopher Nolan&amp;rsquo;s three-hour epic Oppenheimer is expected to sweep the Oscars. Three of the five other Bafta nominees clock in at over two hours each. The Holdovers, Maestro, and Anatomy of a Fall are also Oscar contenders.&#xA;Killers of the Flower Moon is the longest of this year&amp;rsquo;s best picture contenders.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lily Gladstone: The actress who could make Oscars history</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/887554e4-dee5-11ee-b716-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:29:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/887554e4-dee5-11ee-b716-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Lily Gladstone: The actress who could make Oscars history The 37-year-old is the first Native American woman to ever be nominated for best actress at the Oscars. We will find out if she is also the first winner when the ceremony takes place in Los Angeles on 10 March. Gladstone is not a newcomer to acting - viewers may have seen her in TV series such as Billions and films including Certain Women.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
