<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BBC on Five Minunte Reads</title>
    <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/tags/bbc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in BBC on Five Minunte Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 19:57:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://fiveminutesread.github.io/tags/bbc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Teenager stabbed to death in city park</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/316e99b4-dcc7-11ee-99af-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 19:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/316e99b4-dcc7-11ee-99af-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Teenager stabbed to death in city park Incident happened at Wolverhampton&amp;rsquo;s West Park at about 16:30 GMT. Paramedics arrived at the scene first and called the police. The youngster was found in a critical condition and declared dead a short time later. Officers said inquiries were at an early stage and were working to identify the victim.&#xA;One local man said he had been left shocked by the news. He said: &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s scary to think it happened right on my doorstep.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nunez hits double as Liverpool cruise to victory</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/85238480-dccb-11ee-a977-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 19:42:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/85238480-dccb-11ee-a977-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Nunez hits double as Liverpool cruise to victory CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Israel back in Eurovision 2024 after lyric change</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/3623b0e0-dcc0-11ee-99bc-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 19:21:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/3623b0e0-dcc0-11ee-99bc-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Israel back in Eurovision 2024 after lyric change Eden Golan will represent the country at the contest in Sweden this May. Israel will be allowed to compete at the Eurovision Song Contest 2024 after changing the lyrics to its song, organisers have confirmed. The country will take part in the contest for the first time in 2024. Israel&amp;rsquo;s public broadcaster agreed to amend the song, now titled Hurricane.&#xA;Original song, October Rain, was thought to reference the Hamas attacks of 7 October and had been barred for breaking rules on political neutrality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweden formally joins Nato military alliance</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/92668b1c-dcbf-11ee-a08c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 19:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/92668b1c-dcbf-11ee-a08c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Sweden formally joins Nato military alliance Swedish Prime Minister Ulf Kristersson said that unity and solidarity would be Sweden&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;guiding lights. The handover of documents took place at a ceremony two years after Sweden applied to join the military alliance following Russia&amp;rsquo;s full-scale invasion of Ukraine. Nato Secretary-General Jens Stoltenberg posted on X that Sweden brings with it &amp;ldquo;capable armed forces and a first-class defence industry. Nato will continue to stand for freedom and democracy for generations to come, US President Joe Biden says.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constance Marten: I did nothing but show baby love</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/cfc5ced4-dcbd-11ee-b796-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 18:43:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/cfc5ced4-dcbd-11ee-b796-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Constance Marten: &amp;lsquo;I did nothing but show baby love&amp;rsquo; Constance Marten, 36, and partner Mark Gordon, 49, both deny the manslaughter by gross negligence of their daughter Victoria. Her body was found in a Lidl bag in a shed in Brighton on 1 March. Ms Marten and Mr Gordon had allegedly been living in a tent in wintry conditions. Ms Marten wept in the witness box as she gave evidence in her defence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public inquiry into Emma Caldwell police failings</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/9d7d1fc4-dcc0-11ee-877d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 18:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/9d7d1fc4-dcc0-11ee-877d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Public inquiry into Emma Caldwell police failings Iain Packer, 51, was jailed for life after being found guilty of strangling the 27-year-old in 2005. He was interviewed a month after her body was found but it took 19 years to bring him to justice. Family said they now hoped to create a legacy for her and other victims of sexual violence. Senior officers refused to treat Packer as a suspect.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US to set up temporary port on Gaza coast for aid delivery</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/488373ee-dcbe-11ee-b15f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 18:38:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/488373ee-dcbe-11ee-b15f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>US to set up temporary port on Gaza coast for aid delivery Port will be able to receive large ships carrying food, water medicine, and temporary shelters. Initial shipments will arrive via Cyprus, where Israeli security inspections will take place. UN warns that a quarter of the population is on the brink of famine. Mr Biden is due to make the announcement during his State of the Union address later.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welsh ministers didnt know Covid rules - inquiry</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/80352182-dcca-11ee-b439-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 18:22:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/80352182-dcca-11ee-b439-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Welsh ministers didn&amp;rsquo;t know Covid rules - inquiry Simon Hart said members of First Minister Mark Drakeford&amp;rsquo;s own cabinet were expressing a &amp;ldquo;surprising amount of confusion. He suggested that the motivation for differing rules was to be different just for the sake of it. The comments come on the eighth day of the UK inquiry#38;s Welsh module. Welsh ministers didn&amp;rsquo;t know own Covid rules, inquiry told.&#xA;Health expert astonished at lack of Covid urgency in early 2020.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Labour and Tories accused of silence over cuts</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/9a24902a-dcbe-11ee-be72-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 18:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/9a24902a-dcbe-11ee-be72-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Labour and Tories accused of silence over cuts Tough decisions would need to be made following the next election, the Institute for Fiscal Studies said. Labour says it will have to make future savings to public spending to fund some of its policies if it wins power. The state of the economy is under intense focus in the run-up to a general election that must be called before next January. Prime Minister Rishi Sunak refused to be drawn on the date of the general election.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Labour and Tories accused of silence over cuts</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/e01b2eea-dcc3-11ee-8569-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 18:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/e01b2eea-dcc3-11ee-8569-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Labour and Tories accused of silence over cuts Tough decisions would need to be made following the next election, the Institute for Fiscal Studies said. Labour says it will have to make future savings to public spending to fund some of its policies if it wins power. The state of the economy is under intense focus in the run-up to a general election that must be called before next January. Prime Minister Rishi Sunak refused to be drawn on the date of the general election.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Horner says time to draw a line under controversy</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/12b9e62a-dcbf-11ee-93d0-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 18:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/12b9e62a-dcbf-11ee-93d0-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Horner says &amp;rsquo;time to draw a line under&amp;rsquo; controversy Red Bull has suspended the woman who accused Horner of inappropriate behaviour, which he has denied. Red Bull said it could not comment on the reasons for the woman&amp;rsquo;s suspension. Honda has called for more details about the matter. Horner said: &amp;ldquo;The time now is to draw a line under it.&#xA;Horner emphasised that Red Bull&amp;rsquo;s board dismissed the complaint last week.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Horner says time to draw a line under controversy</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/4c349baa-dccb-11ee-a624-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 18:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/4c349baa-dccb-11ee-a624-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Horner says &amp;rsquo;time to draw a line under&amp;rsquo; controversy Red Bull team boss Christian Horner says it is time to draw a line under the controversy over accusations about his behaviour towards a female employee. The woman accused Horner of inappropriate behaviour, which he has denied. Red Bull said it could not comment on the reasons for the woman&amp;rsquo;s suspension. Horner emphasised that Red Bull&amp;rsquo;s board dismissed the complaint last week.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mordaunt defends Donelan over £15,000 legal bill</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/3e481d04-dcc2-11ee-b70b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 17:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/3e481d04-dcc2-11ee-b70b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Mordaunt defends Donelan over £15,000 legal bill Science Secretary Michelle Donelan was told to pay £15,000 for falsely suggesting an academic backed Hamas. Penny Mordaunt said she was confident the payment had been justified. Prime Minister Rishi Sunak also defended the payout saying it was a long-standing convention that the government will fund disputes. He said if Labour were to get into power it would &amp;ldquo;never allow that sort of thing to happen… that would be history#34&amp;rdquo;;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Images show N Korea sealing its border with China</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/533036e6-dcc4-11ee-b3da-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 16:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/533036e6-dcc4-11ee-b3da-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Images show N Korea sealing its border with China North Korea has used the Covid-19 pandemic to seal up its northern border with China, new images show. Human Rights Watch (HRW) describes a situation which has seen repression. The border was only reopened a few months ago, largely to improve trade with China. UN member states should immediately address North Korea&amp;rsquo;s humanitarian crisis, HRW says.&#xA;Satellite images show 482km (299 miles) of new fencing in the areas investigated.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spider-Man battles Baldurs Gate in Bafta Games Awards</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/4b1a0d0e-dcc1-11ee-bb08-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 16:49:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/4b1a0d0e-dcc1-11ee-bb08-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Spider-Man battles Baldur&amp;rsquo;s Gate in Bafta Games Awards CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. Please share your best photos of the United States with CNN iReport.&#xA;Baldur&amp;rsquo;s Gate 3 leads the way with 10 nominations. Spider-Man 2 and Alan Wake 2 also in the running for Best Game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YouTuber Paul to fight ex-champion Tyson</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/da990408-dcc1-11ee-8062-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 16:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/da990408-dcc1-11ee-8062-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>YouTuber Paul to fight ex-champion Tyson It is unclear if it will be an official fight or an exhibition bout. It will be staged in Texas and broadcast live on streaming platform Netflix. Paul, 27, beat Ryan Bourland in his 10th professional fight last Saturday. Tyson&amp;rsquo;s professional career ended in 2005 and he will turn 58 three weeks before facing Paul.&#xA;Tyson was the first heavyweight boxer to simultaneously hold the WBA, WBC and IBF titles in 1987.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump told to pay six-figure costs of firm he sued</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/776b23f6-dcc7-11ee-925e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 16:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/776b23f6-dcc7-11ee-925e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Trump told to pay six-figure costs of firm he sued Mrs Justice Steyn threw out the case against Orbis Business Intelligence. She found that Mr Trump&amp;rsquo;s compensation claim was &amp;ldquo;bound to fail. Mr Steele, who previously ran the Secret Intelligence Service#38;s Russia desk, was the author of the so-called Steele dossier. The dossier, made up of more than a dozen memos, was produced by Orbis in 2016.&#xA;Mrs Justice Steyn said Orbis has estimated its costs to be more than £600,000.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boy, 11, died trying social media craze - family</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/9b0754e2-dcc7-11ee-8c61-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 16:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/9b0754e2-dcc7-11ee-8c61-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Boy, 11, died trying social media craze - family Tommie-lee Gracie Billington died at a house in Lancaster on Saturday. His grandmother Tina Burns said he had been at a sleepover. She said he was taking part in a social media craze that involves sniffing or inhaling toxic fumes. The 11-year-old&amp;rsquo;s family say they are devastated by his death.&#xA;Police said the boy&amp;rsquo;s death was being treated as unexplained. They said whether he had inhaled aerosols was one line of inquiry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Millions affected by German air and rail strikes</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/63ab241c-dcc5-11ee-9a39-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 15:57:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/63ab241c-dcc5-11ee-9a39-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Millions affected by German air and rail strikes Two-day strike by Lufthansa ground staff has coincided with a 35-hour strike by train drivers. Only 20% of long-distance trains were running and Frankfurt airport cancelled all departures. The strikes are the latest in a wave of industrial action to hit Germany. Germany has faced months of strikes as union members and service operators wrestle over pay rises and working hours.&#xA;Flights have also been greatly reduced, with German airline Lufthansa saying earlier this week that about 1,000 flights per day would be cancelled, affecting about 200,000 air passengers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biden faces high-stakes address to calm Democrat nerves</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/a8d3471e-dcc4-11ee-b111-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 15:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/a8d3471e-dcc4-11ee-b111-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Biden faces high-stakes address to calm Democrat nerves The State of the Union address will give him a rare opportunity to speak to a national audience of millions. The 81-year-old seeks to tackle concerns about his age, put a positive gloss on his first-term record and lay out the case for his re-election in November. Mr Biden&amp;rsquo;s approval ratings are some of the lowest recorded for a president seeking re-election. Americans across the political spectrum feel discomfort about giving him another four-years as the commander-in-chief.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teens guilty of killing boy, 16, with zombie knife</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/a511b230-dcc1-11ee-834f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 15:12:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/a511b230-dcc1-11ee-834f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Teens guilty of killing boy, 16, with zombie knife Mikey Roynon was stabbed in the back of the neck during a row. One of the 16-year-olds was found guilty of murder, the other two were found guilty. Mikey&amp;rsquo;s family broke down in tears and hugged each other as verdicts were delivered earlier. Around 50 people were at the party when Mikey, from Kingswood, near Bristol, was stabbed and collapsed.&#xA;He died a short time later.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyena shocks Kenyan after sneaking into his shop</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/d4f5a9d8-dcc7-11ee-acb4-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 15:11:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/d4f5a9d8-dcc7-11ee-acb4-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Hyena shocks Kenyan after sneaking into his shop Fredrick Omungu found the animal in his shop in the Rift Valley city of Nakuru. Neighbours came and identified the animal as a hyena, which under certain conditions can attack humans. It is unclear how the animal ended up in his stall in a populated area. The hyena is suspected to have strayed from the Lake Nakuru National Park.&#xA;Kenya Wildlife Service has been criticised for not doing enough to stop the animals.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More than 100 pupils abducted by Nigeria gunmen</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/0cb49bdc-dcc7-11ee-a1f9-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 15:08:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/0cb49bdc-dcc7-11ee-a1f9-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>More than 100 pupils abducted by Nigeria gunmen CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. Please share your best photos of the United States with CNN iReport.&#xA;Pupils between the ages of eight and 15 were taken away, witnesses say. Kidnap gangs, known as bandits, have seized hundreds of people in recent years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man who filmed his dogs killing wild animals jailed</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/0e4b71fc-dcca-11ee-9ed3-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 14:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/0e4b71fc-dcca-11ee-9ed3-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Man who filmed his dogs killing wild animals jailed Daniel Taylor made videos of his dogs ravaging deer, badgers, foxes and pigeons he had hunted. Skulls, tails, antlers and decomposing heads were found at his property during a search by police. The 32-year-old, from Nottinghamshire, was sentenced to two years and eight months in prison. A police warrant at Taylor&amp;rsquo;s address found a hoard of 15 deer skulls, 14 fox tails, two deer heads, two sets of antlers, and a bag of wire snares.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Rangers stun Benfica in Europa League last 16?</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/9df936cc-dcca-11ee-88f0-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 14:15:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/9df936cc-dcca-11ee-88f0-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Can Rangers stun Benfica in Europa League last 16? CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How are the child benefit rules changing?</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/156563f0-dcc3-11ee-a0b2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 14:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/156563f0-dcc3-11ee-a0b2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How are the child benefit rules changing? The government says the changes will help more than half a million families. Only one person can claim child benefit for a child. There is no limit to how many children you can claim for. Child benefit is usually paid into a nominated bank account every four weeks.&#xA;You can find out how much child benefit you may be entitled to by using the government calculator.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pampered pooches descend on NEC for Crufts</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/19f2ef80-dcc5-11ee-9184-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 13:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/19f2ef80-dcc5-11ee-9184-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Pampered pooches descend on NEC for Crufts Crufts in its current form began in 1891, making it older than the modern Olympics. The show on the outskirts of Birmingham attracts more than 18,000 competitors. The annual competition sees dogs taking part in a wide variety of challenges and presentations in a bid to take home the trophy. This year&amp;rsquo;s Crufts will come to an end after Best in Show and the presentation on Sunday.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Budget leaves Labour seeking savings to fund pledges</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/9ce4b060-dcc3-11ee-9874-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 13:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/9ce4b060-dcc3-11ee-9874-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Budget leaves Labour seeking savings to fund pledges Labour now intends to pay for its NHS and school breakfast plans through future savings to public spending if it wins power. The party had planned to fund the flagship policies by replacing the UK&amp;rsquo;s current &amp;ldquo;non-dom&amp;rdquo;&amp;quot; tax regime. Labour had planned to raise an extra £2bn by replacing tax breaks for overseas workers. It had also set aside £1.&#xA;6bn to pay for more appointments in the NHS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stakeknife report to call for UK and IRA apology</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/36758d3e-dcca-11ee-be0f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 13:03:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/36758d3e-dcca-11ee-be0f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Stakeknife report &amp;rsquo;to call for UK and IRA apology&#39; Report into activities of Stakeknife will call for government and IRA apologies. Freddie Scappaticci will not be named in the report. Report will also call for review into policy of neither confirming, nor denying sensitive information. It is understood that Operation Kenova inquiry will be published next month.&#xA;Operation Kenova ran for seven years and cost £40m, will deliver its interim findings on Friday.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Worlds earliest forest discovered near Butlins in Somerset</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/a1dce8f4-dcc2-11ee-8bcf-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 12:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/a1dce8f4-dcc2-11ee-8bcf-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>World&amp;rsquo;s earliest forest discovered near Butlin&amp;rsquo;s in Somerset Scientists have found what they believe to be the world&amp;rsquo;s earliest known fossilised forest in cliffs on the coast of South West England. Researchers from Cambridge and Cardiff Universities say they are the oldest fossilised trees ever found in Britain. The trees, known as calamophyton, resemble palm trees. Early trees helped shape landscapes and stabilised riverbanks and coastlines hundreds of millions of years ago.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What can I do if I cant pay my energy bill?</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/e81dce40-dcc8-11ee-bf64-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 12:25:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/e81dce40-dcc8-11ee-bf64-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What can I do if I can&amp;rsquo;t pay my energy bill? Energy prices will fall in April, but many households will still struggle to pay their bills. Some will need to repay debt to suppliers and many will worry about future levels of financial support. For confidential support call the Samaritans in the UK on 08457 90 90 90, visit a local Samaritans branch or click here for details. From April, energy bills will fall by more than 12% for most people in England, Scotland and Wales.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BBC Scotland presenter dies after short illness</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/d0eb0136-dcc6-11ee-b22d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 12:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/d0eb0136-dcc6-11ee-b22d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>BBC Scotland presenter dies after short illness Presenter Nick Sheridan has died at the age of 32. He had presented programmes including Reporting Scotland, Drivetime, the Nine and Seven Days since joining the corporation in 2018. First Minister Humza Yousaf paid tribute to Sheridan as he started his weekly question session in the Scottish Parliament. He had previously spent two years presenting RTE News2day, the young person&amp;rsquo;s news programme for Ireland.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I earn £70,000 and can now get child benefit payments</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/6651a706-dcc3-11ee-8a06-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 12:10:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/6651a706-dcc3-11ee-8a06-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;I earn £70,000 and can now get child benefit payments&amp;rsquo; Dad-of-two David Stuart has not been able to get child benefit payments for several years. On a salary of £70,000, he was deemed too high an earner. But in Wednesday&amp;rsquo;s Budget, the chancellor raised the income level at which people have to start paying back part of the benefit from £50,000 to £60,000. Claiming 50% child benefit for two children in 2024-25 would total £1,106.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Rock or Jaws? BBC Six Nations team tackle the Oscars</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/c4c7bb9c-dccb-11ee-bfc0-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 11:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/c4c7bb9c-dccb-11ee-bfc0-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The Rock or Jaws? BBC Six Nations team tackle the Oscars CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netflix hits make Adam Sandler the best-paid actor</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/a4f6cdbc-dcc6-11ee-a62e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 11:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/a4f6cdbc-dcc6-11ee-a62e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Netflix hits make Adam Sandler the best-paid actor CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. Please share your best photos of the United States with CNN iReport.&#xA;Sandler&amp;rsquo;s success on Netflix contributed to his $73m (£57m) earnings, Forbes said. That put him above Barbie star Margot Robbie, who at 33 is the youngest person in the top 10 by a decade.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much will the 2p National Insurance cut save me?</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/32fc0270-dcc8-11ee-8f49-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 10:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/32fc0270-dcc8-11ee-8f49-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How much will the 2p National Insurance cut save me? The government is cutting National Insurance (NI) by another 2p from April. It is not changing income-tax rates but previous changes to the way tax is calculated mean the amount people pay overall is rising. Chancellor Jeremy Hunt announced the starting rate for NI will change from 10% to 8% for 27 million workers from 6 April 2024. NI rates apply across the UK.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Budget: Key points at a glance</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/1d629d06-dcc4-11ee-977f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 08:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/1d629d06-dcc4-11ee-977f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Budget: Key points at a glance National Insurance, a payroll tax, cut by 2p in the pound for employees and the self-employed. Salary thresholds at which people start paying income tax and national insurance remain frozen. People will pay more tax as their incomes rise, a process called fiscal drag. New tax on vaping and an increase to the salary threshold for claiming child benefit.&#xA;National Insurance cut to £10,000, with £5,000 tax allowance for savers investing in UK-focused shares.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jacqueline Wilson reads for zoo animals on World Book Day</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/74f5d432-dcc6-11ee-8786-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 05:59:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/74f5d432-dcc6-11ee-8786-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Jacqueline Wilson reads for zoo animals on World Book Day Dame Jacqueline Wilson has been reading to animals at an East Sussex zoo. The event is to mark World Book Day on Wednesday. The zoo is in the town of Chichester, East Sussex. The book day event is being organised by the East Sussex Book Association.&#xA;Former children&amp;rsquo;s laureate read extracts from her best-selling book The Story of Tracey Beaker to the animals at Drusillas Zoo Park, near Alfriston.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Close to the frontline in Ukraine, the tide of war is coming in fast</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/ea1ad318-dcc4-11ee-a745-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/ea1ad318-dcc4-11ee-a745-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Close to the frontline in Ukraine, the tide of war is coming in fast In February, Russia captured the strategic town of Avdiivka. Since then, the invaders have advanced further west, and taken several villages. Over 1. 2 million people - or two thirds of the population - have left the Ukrainian-controlled Donetsk region since Russia&amp;rsquo;s full scale invasion two years ago.&#xA;People in cities like Pokrovsk, Kostyantynivka and Kramatorsk are now facing a fast-approaching front line, and even occupation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The worlds largest robots are setting sail</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/d2309930-dcc5-11ee-9a0c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/d2309930-dcc5-11ee-9a0c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The world&amp;rsquo;s largest robots are setting sail Ocean Infinity is building a fleet of 23 vessels that will survey the seabed for offshore wind farm operators and check underwater infrastructure for the oil and gas industry. The new vessel, the Armada, has cameras, microphones, radars, GPS and all manner of satellite communications. But for a ship that&amp;rsquo;s 78m in length there are only 16 people on board. A traditional ship carrying out the same kind of work would need a crew of 40 or 50.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything you need to know about the budget… and probably more</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/3c851fba-dcc9-11ee-b56f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 19:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/3c851fba-dcc9-11ee-b56f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Everything you need to know about the budget… and probably more CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MS faces ban for touching women on night out</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/c8b89356-dbfa-11ee-890b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 18:28:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/c8b89356-dbfa-11ee-890b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>MS faces ban for touching women on night out Rhys ab Owen has been banned from the Senedd for six weeks. He was found to have inappropriately touched and swore at two women. The 42-day ban will need to be passed by the Senate next week. It will mean that he will be stripped of his salary.&#xA;It is the biggest sanction against a Member of the Senedd that has ever been implemented.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dharshini David: An election giveaway but taxes will still rise</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/6df9ba2a-dbec-11ee-bcc8-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 18:23:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/6df9ba2a-dbec-11ee-bcc8-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Dharshini David: An election giveaway but taxes will still rise Chancellor Jeremy Hunt was on his feet for one hour and five minutes. His Budget contained a relatively modest amount of treats. Many are still going to see their tax bills rise. But £11bn will be going on that National Insurance cut - a tax giveaway that will be a relief to workers.&#xA;Almost half will come from changing the treatment of &amp;ldquo;non-doms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haiti gangs threaten civil war as unrest spreads</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/efe8b488-dbf0-11ee-af41-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 18:21:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/efe8b488-dbf0-11ee-af41-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Haiti gangs threaten &amp;lsquo;civil war&amp;rsquo; as unrest spreads Jimmy Chérizier made the threat as members of his gang tried to seize the capital&amp;rsquo;s airport to stop Ariel Henry from returning from abroad. The gang leader is behind the violence blighting the Haitian capital. He warned there will be a civil war if the prime minister, Ariel Henry, does not step down. UN High Commissioner for Human Rights Volker Türk says situation is &amp;lsquo;beyond untenable&amp;rsquo; Aid groups say about 15,000 people, among them many young children, have been displaced from their homes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I earn £22,000. The Budget will leave me £188 better off</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/aecca11e-dbee-11ee-91bb-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 18:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/aecca11e-dbee-11ee-91bb-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;I earn £22,000. The Budget will leave me £188 better off&amp;rsquo; Joe Makin, 23, earns £22,000 a year working in admin and says almost two-thirds of his take-home pay is eaten up by rent and bills. The 2p National Insurance (NI) cut announced by the chancellor means he will keep a further £188 of his salary a year. He says he had low expectations ahead of the Budget, so found it a smidgen more positive than he thought it would be.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parents on up to £80,000 eligible for child benefit</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/1209a150-dbf9-11ee-a8ed-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 18:14:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/1209a150-dbf9-11ee-a8ed-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Parents on up to £80,000 eligible for child benefit Benefit will not be taken away entirely until an individual earns £80,000. Changes are set to help 170,000 families with children under 16. But the system has been criticised for being unfair to households with one high-earning parent. Under child benefit, parents receive £24 a week for one child and £15.&#xA;90 for each additional child. Under the current system, if one partner earns more than £50,000, child benefit starts being gradually withdrawn.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watch as James gives Chelsea lead over Man City in Womens League Cup semi-final</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/07683720-dccb-11ee-a840-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 18:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/07683720-dccb-11ee-a840-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Watch as James gives Chelsea lead over Man City in Women&amp;rsquo;s League Cup semi-final CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oil and gas profits windfall tax extended until 2029</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/950392ae-dbfa-11ee-b073-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 18:02:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/950392ae-dbfa-11ee-b073-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Oil and gas profits windfall tax extended until 2029 The 35% surcharge on profits due to high energy prices had been scheduled to end in March 2028. Scottish Conservative leader Douglas Ross said he would not support the legislation needed to pass the extension. The Energy Profits Levy (EPL) was introduced by Rishi Sunak when he was chancellor in May 2022. Energy Profits Levy extended to 2029, raising £1.&#xA;5bn for oil and gas firms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two killed in Houthi missile attack on ship - US officials</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/272ecc26-dbf0-11ee-93d1-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 17:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/272ecc26-dbf0-11ee-93d1-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Two killed in Houthi missile attack on ship - US officials CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. Please share your best photos of the United States with CNN iReport.&#xA;The Barbados-flagged True Confidence had been abandoned and was drifting with a fire on board.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emma Caldwell killer Iain Packer to appeal against conviction </title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/4b8c7882-dbf7-11ee-8697-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 17:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/4b8c7882-dbf7-11ee-8697-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Emma Caldwell killer Iain Packer to appeal against conviction Iain Packer was given a life sentence and ordered to serve a minimum of 36 years in prison. He was found guilty last week of 33 charges against a total of 22 women, including Emma&amp;rsquo;s murder and 11 rapes. The Scottish Courts and Tribunals Service confirmed to BBC Scotland that Packer has indicated a &amp;ldquo;intimation of intention to appeal. Officers initially arrested four Turkish men in connection with the murder.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cameron meets Israel minister after Gaza aid warning</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/ae580af4-dbf1-11ee-a9e7-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 17:41:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/ae580af4-dbf1-11ee-a9e7-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Cameron meets Israel minister after Gaza aid warning Lord Cameron told Mr Gantz, a retired general and member of Israel&amp;rsquo;s war cabinet, that &amp;ldquo;we are still not seeing improvements on the ground. The two met in central London on Wednesday afternoon. The foreign secretary stressed that Israel had a legal responsibility to ensure the availability of aid. Lord Cameron said the UK was pushing for more aid to get into Gaza.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the tax take the highest for 70 years?</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/7e13f532-dbed-11ee-ae3d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 17:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/7e13f532-dbed-11ee-ae3d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Is the tax take the highest for 70 years? The UK economy grew faster than Germany over the past year, but not France or Italy. Mr Hunt is right to say that for the whole period that the Conservatives have been in power, the UK has grown faster than all three of them. But if we look at GDP per person, which excludes the effect of the growing population, Germany has actually performed better than the UK during that period.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man killed in A5 crash was Caolan Devlin</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/52aa0938-dbfa-11ee-8676-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 17:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/52aa0938-dbfa-11ee-8676-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Man killed in A5 crash was Caolan Devlin The 30-year-old was driving a BMW and was pronounced dead at the scene. The collision happened on the Curr Road, between Omagh and Ballygawley. Mr Devlin was the only occupant of the car which collided with a lorry. The Northern Ireland Ambulance Service received a 999 call at 19:18 GMT.&#xA;Police said the lorry driver was not hurt. Sinn Féin MP Órfhlaith Begley described Mr Devlin&amp;rsquo;s death as an &amp;ldquo;absolute tragedy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Explosions hit Odesa as Zelensky meets Greek PM</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/56ed63b4-dbf0-11ee-8c39-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 17:12:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/56ed63b4-dbf0-11ee-8c39-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Explosions hit Odesa as Zelensky meets Greek PM Ukraine&amp;rsquo;s navy says five people were killed. The BBC has been told no-one from either delegation was hurt. Russia said it targeted a maritime drone facility in a commercial port area of the city during an attack on Wednesday. President Zelensky accused Russia of not caring who they target.&#xA;Russia&amp;rsquo;s defence ministry said it had attacked a hangar housing drones. The BBC could not independently verify this claim.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chelseas Kerr has clubs full support - Hayes</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/8cbc5d50-dbfb-11ee-a9cd-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 17:07:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/8cbc5d50-dbfb-11ee-a9cd-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Chelsea&amp;rsquo;s Kerr has club&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;full support&amp;rsquo; - Hayes CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key takeaways from Super Tuesday results</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/b9644cde-dbf4-11ee-9fdd-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 16:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/b9644cde-dbf4-11ee-9fdd-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Key takeaways from Super Tuesday results Voters in 15 states and American Samoa chose their preferred party candidates for president. Donald Trump posted a dominant performance, with wins in states across the country. Joe Biden and Hillary Clinton are expected to face off in a rematch in November. Here are some of the key takeaways from Super Tuesday.&#xA;The former president will walk away with a near-insurmountable lead in convention delegates, even if he will have to wait until next week to mathematically lock the Republican nomination.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much will the 2p National Insurance cut save me?</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/60b7e75e-dbf8-11ee-9468-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 16:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/60b7e75e-dbf8-11ee-9468-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How much will the 2p National Insurance cut save me? The starting rate for NI will change from 10% to 8%, for 27 million workers, from April 2024. Chancellor Jeremy Hunt says this is worth £450 a year to an employee on an average salary of £35,000. He is also cutting NI for two million self-employed workers. Their rate will fall from 8% to 6%.&#xA;NI on income and profits above £50,270 remains at 2%.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europa League: West Ham visit Freiburg after Liverpool thrash Sparta</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/d5d8dfe8-dcca-11ee-99da-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 15:40:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/d5d8dfe8-dcca-11ee-99da-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Europa League: West Ham visit Freiburg after Liverpool thrash Sparta CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mother charged with murder of 10-year-old girl</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/57dafbd4-dbef-11ee-9909-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 15:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/57dafbd4-dbef-11ee-9909-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Mother charged with murder of 10-year-old girl Shay Kang was discovered fatally injured at the house in Rowley Regis. Jaskirat Kaur, also known as Jasmine Kang, has been charged with murder. The 33-year-old appeared at Wolverhampton Magistrates&amp;rsquo; Court on Wednesday. Shay attended nearby Brickhouse Primary School where staff described her as bright and fun-loving.&#xA;Ms Kaur spoke only to confirm her name and date of birth and was remanded into custody to next appear at Wolverhampton Crown Court on Thursday.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-dom, vaping and tobacco: Key points at-a-glance</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/c1a2234c-dbec-11ee-aeab-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 15:31:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/c1a2234c-dbec-11ee-aeab-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Non-dom&amp;rsquo;, vaping and tobacco: Key points at-a-glance Jeremy Hunt unveils the contents of this year&amp;rsquo;s Budget in the House of Commons. It was the last scheduled Budget before the next general election, which is expected to take place later this year. Here is a summary of the main announcements. The Budget is published in its entirety at the bottom of the page.&#xA;National Insurance, a payroll tax, cut by 2p in the pound for employees and the self-employed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the new vaping tax and when will it start?</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/6b7734d0-dcc8-11ee-9aea-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 15:25:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/6b7734d0-dcc8-11ee-9aea-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What is the new vaping tax and when will it start? Vaping is nowhere near as harmful as smoking cigarettes. But health experts agree that anyone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t smoke should not start. The government has said it will introduce a new tax on vaping products. It has already announced plans to ban disposable vapes, to help cut the number of children vaping.&#xA;Vaping products duty will start in October 2026. The duty will be in place until the end of the current fiscal year in October 2015.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the new vaping tax and when will it start?</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/9a0cbf84-dbf8-11ee-b4bc-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 15:25:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/9a0cbf84-dbf8-11ee-b4bc-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What is the new vaping tax and when will it start? Vaping is nowhere near as harmful as smoking cigarettes. But health experts agree that anyone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t smoke should not start. The government has said it will introduce a new tax on vaping products. It has already announced plans to ban disposable vapes, to help cut the number of children vaping.&#xA;Vaping products duty will start in October 2026. The duty will be in place until the end of the current fiscal year in October 2015.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Red panda found in luggage at Bangkok airport</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/06d59544-dbf6-11ee-9327-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 14:58:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/06d59544-dbf6-11ee-9327-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Red panda found in luggage at Bangkok airport Snakes, parrots and monitor lizards were among 87 animals seized at Suvarnabhumi Airport. They were allegedly discovered in the suspects&amp;rsquo; checked luggage as they tried to fly to Mumbai. The suspects face a maximum of 10 years behind bars.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why England have so much to prove in foothills of Himalayas</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/5d1db7ce-dbfb-11ee-8d7e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 14:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/5d1db7ce-dbfb-11ee-8d7e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Why England have so much to prove in foothills of Himalayas CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What does the Budget mean for you?</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/3b5d8c2a-dbee-11ee-8161-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 13:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/3b5d8c2a-dbee-11ee-8161-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What does the Budget mean for you? Jeremy Hunt announced a cut in the rate of National Insurance (NI) paid by 27 million employees across the UK. For employees paid between £12,571 to £50,270 a year, the current NI rate is 10% on earnings (down from 12% before January) The chancellor said this would fall to 8% in April. Higher earners will take home an additional £754 a year, according to calculations by investment companies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Election poll tracker: How do the parties compare?</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/a18cb32a-dbf5-11ee-a984-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 13:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/a18cb32a-dbf5-11ee-a984-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Election poll tracker: How do the parties compare? Conservative MPs will be hoping that the tax cuts announced in the Budget will please voters. Chancellor Jeremy Hunt cut the main rate of National Insurance for employees from 12% to 10%. Now he&amp;rsquo;s gone further with an additional cut to 8% and he also cut the rate for self-employed people. The latest poll by Ipsos MORI has the Tories down to 20 per cent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sons publish book García Márquez wanted destroyed</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/3643ab88-dbf4-11ee-b468-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 13:43:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/3643ab88-dbf4-11ee-b468-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Sons publish book García Márquez wanted destroyed CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. Please share your best photos of the United States with CNN iReport.&#xA;The Colombian writer, who died in 2014, was best known for pioneering the magical realist style of writing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guy Ritchie reimagines The Gentlemen for Netflix series</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/7c31662e-dbf6-11ee-a766-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 13:08:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/7c31662e-dbf6-11ee-a766-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Guy Ritchie reimagines The Gentlemen for Netflix series Guy Ritchie&amp;rsquo;s The Gentlemen is returning for an eight-part TV series. The film took audiences on a journey of mayhem and marijuana. Ritchie said there were themes and storylines which were &amp;ldquo;worth exploring#34%; further following the film. The 2019 film starred Matthew McConaughey, Colin Farrell and Hugh Grant.&#xA;None of them have returned to the franchise to appear in the TV series. Theo James takes the lead opposite supporting characters played by Vinnie Jones, Ray Winstone, Joely Richardson and Max Beesley.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rahm criticises world rankings as LIV ends interest</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/1753a45a-dbfc-11ee-bfc8-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 12:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/1753a45a-dbfc-11ee-bfc8-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Rahm criticises world rankings as LIV ends interest Masters champion Jon Rahm said the Official World Golf Ranking (OWGR) is not a good system. LIV Golf withdrew its application to join the OWGR in October. CEO Greg Norman told players it will not pursue its bid for world ranking points. Two-time major winner and world number three Rahm is among the players to have switched from the PGA Tour.&#xA;LIV Golf Hong Kong begins on Friday.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real midfielder Bellingham banned for two games</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/36ab875a-dbfc-11ee-b1c4-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 12:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/36ab875a-dbfc-11ee-b1c4-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Real midfielder Bellingham banned for two games CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grandparents charged with toddlers murder</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/d7410334-dbf7-11ee-9c16-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 12:17:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/d7410334-dbf7-11ee-9c16-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Grandparents charged with toddler&amp;rsquo;s murder Two-year-old Ethan Ives Griffiths was discovered at the home of Michael Ives and Kerry Ives in Garden City, Flintshire. He was taken to Alder Hey Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital in Liverpool where he later died. The pair were also charged with assault and neglect.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>K-pop star apologises after relationship goes public</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/dd5fb4ae-dbf2-11ee-a719-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 12:12:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/dd5fb4ae-dbf2-11ee-a719-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>K-pop star apologises after relationship goes public Karina, real name Yu Ji-min, has led the four-woman aespa since their debut in 2020. Last year, their record-breaking album My World sold 2. 1m copies in South Korea. In a letter shared on Instagram, the 23-year-old vowed to heal the wounds.&#xA;Pop stars in South Korea and Japan work in a notoriously pressurising industries. Just a decade ago, it was common practice for K-pop agencies to ban new stars from dating or even having a personal mobile phone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>School checking absent pupils bins, cars and post</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/20bf5d42-dbfa-11ee-b47b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 11:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/20bf5d42-dbfa-11ee-b47b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>School checking absent pupils&amp;rsquo; bins, cars and post CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. Please share your best photos of the United States with CNN iReport.&#xA;Astrea Academy Woodfields in Doncaster is checking driveways, boiler flues and lights to see if people are home or away on holiday.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>North &lt;title&gt; Tompkins dropped as Wales change centres for France</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/cfb40ad6-dbfb-11ee-9d63-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 11:37:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/cfb40ad6-dbfb-11ee-9d63-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>North Tompkins dropped as Wales change centres for France CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My son Ali has already died: Fathers plea for Gazas starving children</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/a08d55b0-dbf0-11ee-9ded-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 11:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/a08d55b0-dbf0-11ee-9ded-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;My son Ali has already died&amp;rsquo;: Father&amp;rsquo;s plea for Gaza&amp;rsquo;s starving children Ali was born in wartime and there was no food or anything for his mother to eat - a matter which caused his kidneys to fail. His life got worse day after day. We tried to get him treated at hospitals, but there were no help. The UN warns of famine if aid deliveries are not substantially increased.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Super Tuesday: Everything Points to Trump vs Biden</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/a476c658-dbf9-11ee-8dd7-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 06:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/a476c658-dbf9-11ee-8dd7-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Super Tuesday: Everything Points to Trump vs Biden CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MP says Milton Keynes misrepresented by EastEnders</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/0fcfde14-dbf8-11ee-bb1f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 06:14:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/0fcfde14-dbf8-11ee-bb1f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>MP says Milton Keynes misrepresented by EastEnders CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. Please share your best photos of the United States with CNN iReport.&#xA;The character of Bianca Jackson, played by Patsy Palmer, returned to screens in scenes set in her home in Milton Keynes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starling murmurations fascinate car park crowd</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/c9238e62-dbf6-11ee-a161-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 06:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/c9238e62-dbf6-11ee-a161-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Starling murmurations fascinate car park crowd Thousands of birds have been returning night after night to the Kingfisher Shopping Centre car park in Redditch since January. Crowds have been flocking to the roof of the shopping centre car park to watch murmurations of starlings. They have attracted dozens of birdwatchers. Starlings are in the red category on the RSPB&amp;rsquo;s conservation status which means their population is in decline.&#xA;Justin thought the Redditch starlings arrived from a roost at Brandon Marsh, a nature reserve more than 30 miles away in Warwickshire.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can the Panama Canal save itself?</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/7a9ccda6-dbf3-11ee-a775-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 00:02:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/7a9ccda6-dbf3-11ee-a775-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Can the Panama Canal save itself? Unlike the Suez Canal, the Panama Canal is fed by a freshwater lake. The water level is falling critically low. A lack of rain and the El Nino weather phenomenon have contributed to the second driest year in the canal&amp;rsquo;s 110-year history. Last October was the driest month since records began.&#xA;The canal region saw 41% less rainfall than normal. The drought threatens to continue disrupting the $270bn (£213bn) worth of cargo that flows through the Atlantic-Pacific shortcut annually.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukrainian woman gives Welsh pub new lease of life</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/0606b228-dbf7-11ee-a4e5-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 22:58:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/0606b228-dbf7-11ee-a4e5-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Ukrainian woman gives Welsh pub new lease of life Vladyslava Krapyvka left her home in Kyiv along with her youngest son after Russia&amp;rsquo;s invasion in 2022. She has taken on the lease of The Lamb in Newport. The city centre pub closed in 2023, but welcomed back customers on St David’s Day with a weekend of live music. The Lamb, on Bridge Street, will stock craft ales, lagers, ciders and spirits.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Womens League Cup semi-final: Williamson returns as Arsenal host Aston Villa</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/2a266d66-dbfb-11ee-9a7d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 17:05:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/2a266d66-dbfb-11ee-9a7d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Women&amp;rsquo;s League Cup semi-final: Williamson returns as Arsenal host Aston Villa CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Champions League: Man City v Copenhagen &lt;title&gt; Real Madrid v RB Leipzig</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/f4dbf310-dbfa-11ee-84b7-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 17:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/f4dbf310-dbfa-11ee-84b7-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Champions League: Man City v Copenhagen Real Madrid v RB Leipzig CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is a recession and how could it affect me?</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/542a2e7e-dbf9-11ee-a3e5-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 16:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/542a2e7e-dbf9-11ee-a3e5-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What is a recession and how could it affect me? The Office for National Statistics publishes figures for the UK&amp;rsquo;s Gross Domestic Product. This is the value of all the goods and services the UK produces. The latest ONS figures show that the economy shrank 0. 3% between October and December 2023.&#xA;The Bank of England has since suggested that the downturn might already be over. UK economy grew by 0.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is a recession and how could it affect me?</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/a6d68f4e-dcc8-11ee-818a-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 16:01:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/a6d68f4e-dcc8-11ee-818a-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What is a recession and how could it affect me? The Office for National Statistics publishes figures for the UK&amp;rsquo;s Gross Domestic Product. This is the value of all the goods and services the UK produces. The latest ONS figures show that the economy shrank 0. 3% between October and December 2023.&#xA;The Bank of England has since suggested that the downturn might already be over. UK economy grew by 0.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winter warmth brings early blossom across the UK</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/3da69b64-dbf5-11ee-aa07-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 15:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/3da69b64-dbf5-11ee-aa07-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Winter warmth brings early blossom across the UK Some blooms have emerged four weeks earlier than usual, according to the National Trust. Scientists say it&amp;rsquo;s part of a broader trend as a result of climate change. A study by Cambridge University in 2022 found that the UK and its flowers are blooming one month earlier than they used to. Gardeners at Kew Gardens in London say it&amp;rsquo;s unusual to have so many species in bloom.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump must earn our votes, Haley says as she quits presidential race</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/f0e400b0-dbee-11ee-8c46-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 12:25:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/f0e400b0-dbee-11ee-8c46-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Trump must earn our votes, Haley says as she quits presidential race CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is council tax and how much is it going up?</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/d7d297bc-dbf8-11ee-8876-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 10:49:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/d7d297bc-dbf8-11ee-8876-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What is council tax and how much is it going up? Councils in England have until 11 March to decide how much to put council tax up by and whether services need to be cut. Those with social care duties can raise council tax by up to 4. 99%, without triggering a referendum. Millions of households are expected to see their council tax bills rise in April.&#xA;Councils can increase bills by more than 5% without a referendum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>China sets ambitious economic target for 2024</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/5be945c6-daac-11ee-8712-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 04:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/5be945c6-daac-11ee-8712-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>China sets ambitious economic target for 2024 Premier Li Qiang made the announcement at the opening of the annual National People&amp;rsquo;s Congress. It comes as China struggles to reinvigorate its once-booming economy. Mr Li acknowledged that China&amp;rsquo;s economic performance had faced &amp;ldquo;difficulties. Beijing says that last year the economy grew by 5.&#xA;2%, which even at that level is low for China. Research will be stepped up in new technologies, including artificial intelligence (AI) and life sciences.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Children starving to death in northern Gaza - WHO</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/dedc1d6e-daa7-11ee-be53-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 03:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/dedc1d6e-daa7-11ee-be53-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Children starving to death in northern Gaza - WHO Tedros Adhanom Ghebreyesus said the agency&amp;rsquo;s visits over the weekend to the Al-Awda and Kamal Adwan hospitals were the first since early October. A lack of food resulted in the deaths of 10 children and severe levels of malnutrition, he said. A sixteenth child died on Sunday at a hospital in the southern city of Rafah. An estimated 300,000 people are living with little food or clean water in northern Gaza.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UN says rape likely committed in Hamas attack on Israel</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/4645860c-dab2-11ee-b08b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 02:18:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/4645860c-dab2-11ee-b08b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>UN says rape likely committed in Hamas attack on Israel Hamas has denied its gunmen sexually assaulted women during the attacks. UN team found reasonable grounds to believe that conflict-related sexual violence occurred in multiple locations during the 7 October attacks. These happened in at least three locations - the Nova music festival site and its surroundings, Road 232, and Kibbutz Re&amp;lsquo;im. Hamas gunmen infiltrated southern Israel on 7 October - killing about 1,200 people and taking 253 others hostage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Medical leaders back rise in physician associates</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/383bb538-daab-11ee-9500-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 02:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/383bb538-daab-11ee-9500-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Medical leaders back rise in physician associates NHS has 3,286 PAs, who assist healthcare teams and are not authorised to prescribe or request scans. British Medical Association (BMA) is concerned about a new law allowing the General Medical Council to regulate PAs. The doctors&amp;rsquo; union says it blurs the lines between doctors and PAs and could risk patient safety. Like PAs, AAs are healthcare professionals who work as part of a multidisciplinary team with supervision from a named senior doctor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teen girl restrained and stripped by prison staff</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/d93dd4c8-daa8-11ee-8125-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 02:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/d93dd4c8-daa8-11ee-8125-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Teen girl restrained and stripped by prison staff CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. Please share your best photos of the United States with CNN iReport.&#xA;Vulnerable girl had her clothes removed by an all-male team of prison officers. Wetherby Young Offender Institution is some of the most complex and vulnerable in the country.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Papers: NHS budget warning and Hunt to keep fuel tax cut</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/64ef4ef8-daad-11ee-997e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 01:21:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/64ef4ef8-daad-11ee-997e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The Papers: NHS budget warning and Hunt &amp;rsquo;to keep fuel tax cut&#39; CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of London for next week&amp;rsquo;s gallery. Visit CNN.&#xA;com/Travel next week for a new gallery of snapshots from around the world. For more travel news, visit CNN&amp;rsquo;s Travel page.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Firths wet shirt from Pride and Prejudice on sale</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/3c165042-daaa-11ee-8e6b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/3c165042-daaa-11ee-8e6b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Firth&amp;rsquo;s wet shirt from Pride and Prejudice on sale CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. Please share your best photos of the United States with CNN iReport.&#xA;The shirt was worn by Colin Firth in the 1995 adaptation of Pride and Prejudice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One of worst displays Ive ever seen - Sheff Utds new low</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/f145e384-dab8-11ee-a160-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:13:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/f145e384-dab8-11ee-a160-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;One of worst displays I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen&amp;rsquo; - Sheff Utd&amp;rsquo;s new low CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concern as the gambling industry embraces AI</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/712d3382-daae-11ee-9a38-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:06:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/712d3382-daae-11ee-9a38-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Concern as the gambling industry embraces AI Danny Cheetham started visiting local bookies aged 18, gambling on the Fixed Odds Betting Terminals (FOBTs) It wasn&amp;rsquo;t long before he transitioned to online games. The ease of access and the solitary nature of online gambling exacerbated his habits, he says. The ethical dilemma here is whether the pursuit of profit is being prioritised. EquinEdge uses AI to analyse data such as horse performance, track conditions, and jockey and trainer statistics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Watch: My biggest financial regret is...</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/743275a2-daa8-11ee-bb6b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/743275a2-daa8-11ee-bb6b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Watch: &amp;lsquo;My biggest financial regret is&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Ukraine, the show must go on - even underground</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/cd7f3338-daae-11ee-ab76-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:02:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/cd7f3338-daae-11ee-ab76-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>In Ukraine, the show must go on - even underground The Kharkiv National Opera and Ballet is about to burst back into sound - underground. The bunker theatre is being prepared beneath the main auditorium, down several flights of stairs. It has no dress circle, chandeliers or Champagne - but a lot of grey concrete. The theatre&amp;rsquo;s general director, Ihor Touluzov, explains.&#xA;The main stage has been closed off since the Russian invasion of Crimea in 2003.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kate Middletons uncle joins Celebrity Big Brother</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/0d3a927c-dab1-11ee-b89a-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 23:08:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/0d3a927c-dab1-11ee-b89a-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Kate Middleton&amp;rsquo;s uncle joins Celebrity Big Brother Gary Goldsmith, uncle of Catherine, Princess of Wales, has entered the Celebrity Big Brother house. He said it is the one show he had previously said he would never do. X Factor judges Sharon Osbourne and Louis Walsh will also be in the house. They will be tasked with watching their fellow contestants and rating them.&#xA;The series started on Monday and is hosted by AJ Odudu and Will Best.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emma Caldwell s mother to meet first minister</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/7108d0bc-dab0-11ee-bee6-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 22:58:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/7108d0bc-dab0-11ee-bee6-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Emma Caldwell&amp;rsquo;s mother to meet first minister Margaret Caldwell wants a judge to look into the failings by police in the case. The mother of Emma Caldwell is to meet the first minister on Tuesday to call for a public inquiry into the investigation of her daughter&amp;rsquo;s murder. The first minister is due to meet Margaret Caldwell on Tuesday. Packer was found guilty of 11 counts of rape and three counts of sexual assault.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Government defeated in Lords over Rwanda bill</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/f3592930-daac-11ee-929a-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 22:43:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/f3592930-daac-11ee-929a-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Government defeated in Lords over Rwanda bill The legislation would deem Rwanda a safe country to send asylum seekers to, in a bid to stop removals being derailed by appeals. But peers backed changes to make it easier for judges to challenge this. The bill will continue its passage through the Lords on Wednesday, when opposition peers could inflict further defeats. Ministers want to send an unspecified number of asylum seekers to the east African country.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kerr pleads not guilty to racially aggravated offence</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/5bf48280-daaa-11ee-947c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 21:59:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/5bf48280-daaa-11ee-947c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Kerr pleads not guilty to racially aggravated offence CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Murder investigation after girl, 10, dies</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/22737418-daa9-11ee-8601-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 21:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/22737418-daa9-11ee-8601-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Murder investigation after girl, 10, dies Child was found with injuries in Rowley Regis, West Midlands. She was confirmed dead at an address on Robin Close, police said. A 33-year-old woman, believed to be known to the girl, has been taken into custody for questioning. Police cordon remained in place on the street this evening.&#xA;A blue tent was visible near the front of a terraced property which was guarded by a police car.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Murder investigation after girl, 10, dies</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/fa6e3e36-dab6-11ee-98e7-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 21:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/fa6e3e36-dab6-11ee-98e7-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Murder investigation after girl, 10, dies Child was found with injuries in Rowley Regis, West Midlands. She was confirmed dead at an address on Robin Close, police said. A 33-year-old woman, believed to be known to the girl, has been taken into custody for questioning. Police cordon remained in place on the street this evening.&#xA;A blue tent was visible near the front of a terraced property which was guarded by a police car.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police officer drags homeless man along ground</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/f98015e0-daab-11ee-826c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 21:05:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/f98015e0-daab-11ee-826c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Police officer drags homeless man along ground CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. Please share your best photos of the United States with CNN iReport.&#xA;Footage shows a police officer dragging a rough sleeper along the ground. The officer was then seen deliberately treading on the man&amp;rsquo;s stomach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump: The Sequel? An Americast x Panorama Special</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/5ec25396-dab6-11ee-8dad-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 20:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/5ec25396-dab6-11ee-8dad-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Trump: The Sequel? An Americast x Panorama Special CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Top court says states cant ban Trump from ballots</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/c981f4fa-daa9-11ee-9f6f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 19:46:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/c981f4fa-daa9-11ee-9f6f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Top court says states can&amp;rsquo;t ban Trump from ballots Colorado had barred Mr Trump from its Republican primary, arguing he incited the 2021 Capitol riot. The court ruled that only Congress, rather than the states, has that power. Mr Trump is the front-runner for the Republican nomination and looks likely to face a rematch with Democratic President Joe Biden in November. Mr Trump said the decision was &amp;lsquo;very well crafted&amp;rsquo; and will bring the country together.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>France makes abortion a constitutional right</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/a3e87cb6-daac-11ee-8c66-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 19:24:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/a3e87cb6-daac-11ee-8c66-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>France makes abortion a constitutional right France has become the first country in the world to explicitly include the right to abortion in its constitution. The overwhelming 780-72 vote saw a standing ovation in the parliament in Versailles when the result was announced. President Emmanuel Macron described the move as &amp;ldquo;French pride#34. Around 85% of the public supported amending the constitution to protect the right to end a pregnancy.&#xA;It becomes the 25th amendment to modern France&amp;rsquo;s founding document, and the first since 2008.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transparency tool launched by BBC Verify</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/d47edbfe-dab1-11ee-9d60-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 18:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/d47edbfe-dab1-11ee-9d60-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Transparency tool launched by BBC Verify CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three charged over death of two-year-old boy</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/6458d422-dab8-11ee-8779-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 18:29:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/6458d422-dab8-11ee-8779-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Three charged over death of two-year-old boy Michael and Kerry Ives have been charged with murder. Shannon Kayleigh Ives, 27, from Mold, also faces charges. They have been remanded into custody to appear in crown court on Wednesday. They are accused of causing the assault, ill treatment, neglect or abandonment of a child to cause unnecessary suffering.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Would a £150,000 wage tempt you to a Scottish island?</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/776eef46-daaf-11ee-a81e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 18:28:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/776eef46-daaf-11ee-a81e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Would a £150,000 wage tempt you to a Scottish island? Island GP practice offering £150,000 to attract new doctors to live and work there. Isle of Rum is seeking a new school teacher for its five primary pupils and two nursery children - with a package worth £68,000. It is part of efforts to tackle a recruitment crisis in many rural services. NHS Western Isles is offering a 40% ‘enhanced rate’ above a typical salary.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I spent my 18th birthday wishing my missing mum would come home</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/f9d3655e-dab7-11ee-aa92-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 18:03:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/f9d3655e-dab7-11ee-aa92-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;I spent my 18th birthday wishing my missing mum would come home&amp;rsquo; Mother-of-three Khasha has been missing since October. She was last seen at the flat she shared with her partner in Edinburgh. Officers have searched a nearby canal and nearby woodland. Police say she was last in contact with her family in November.&#xA;For confidential support call the Samaritans in the UK on 08457 90 90 90, visit a local Samaritans branch or click here for details.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nexus counselling contract extended for one year</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/8be640ac-dab7-11ee-823d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 17:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/8be640ac-dab7-11ee-823d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Nexus counselling contract extended for one year Nexus was awarded a three-year contract in April 2019 to provide the counselling service, with an option for two one-year extensions. Health minister Robin Swann said the extension will allow proper consideration, decision and implementation of the best way forward for counselling services of this nature. Nexus chief executive Joanne Barnes said the charity is delighted for victims and survivors. She said there is some work yet to be done to look at what a service will look like in this interim year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gatcombe Horse Trials cancelled after 40 years</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/9af88c26-dab2-11ee-a60d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 16:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/9af88c26-dab2-11ee-a60d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Gatcombe Horse Trials cancelled after 40 years The Festival of British eventing at Gatcombe Park has been cancelled due to the cost of running the event. The event was due to take place on the weekend of September 14 and 15. The festival was originally due to run until the end of the month on September 28 and 29. Gatcombe Park began hosting the festival in the 1980s, after Princess Anne and her first husband Captain Mark Phillips &amp;ldquo;first had the dream.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How gangs came to dominate Haiti</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/f6288c70-daaf-11ee-aadb-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 15:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/f6288c70-daaf-11ee-aadb-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How gangs came to dominate Haiti Gangs have taken control of large swathes of Haiti&amp;rsquo;s capital and rural areas. Government without a single elected official and a gang leader who openly threatens the prime minister. Thousands of prisoners on the loose after gangs stormed the jails they were in. The scenes unfolding in Haiti are shocking even to those who have been following the rise of armed groups.&#xA;The most recent outbreak of gang violence has been fuelled by the assassination of President Jovenel Moïse on 7 July 2021.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When is the Budget and what will it mean for my money?</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/cbfd6ade-dab3-11ee-bcd7-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 14:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/cbfd6ade-dab3-11ee-bcd7-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>When is the Budget and what will it mean for my money? Reports suggest several measures are being considered to raise money to fund tax cuts. The most recent of which is raising duty on flying business class. The Treasury has declined to comment on the reports. The Chancellor of the Exchequer makes a Budget statement in the House of Commons.&#xA;The 2024 spring Budget will take place on Wednesday, 6 March.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>£100m Church fund not enough to address slavery links, says report</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/688b28a6-dab3-11ee-9eae-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 11:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/688b28a6-dab3-11ee-9eae-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>£100m Church fund not enough to address slavery links, says report CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. Please share your best photos of the United States with CNN iReport.&#xA;The Church welcomed the report by the Church Commissioners charity. But it would not commit to raising the fund to the report&amp;rsquo;s £1bn target.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Northern lights give spectacular surprise display across UK</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/29388dba-dab3-11ee-bffd-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 08:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/29388dba-dab3-11ee-bffd-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Northern lights give spectacular surprise display across UK CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. Please share your best photos of the United States with CNN iReport.&#xA;Sudden spike in solar activity - which causes the lights - saw an aurora &amp;ldquo;red alert issued on Sunday evening.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jeremy on the Hunt for Tax Cuts</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/f4369500-dab5-11ee-b56d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 12:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/f4369500-dab5-11ee-b56d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Jeremy on the Hunt for Tax Cuts CNN. com will feature iReporter photos in a weekly Travel Snapshots gallery. Please submit your best shots of the U. S.&#xA;for next week. Visit CNN. com/Travel next Wednesday for a new gallery of snapshots. We will feature a selection of the best shots from across the globe.&#xA;Read More</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five ways to save on train tickets as fares rise</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/97634af4-dab4-11ee-8311-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 02:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/97634af4-dab4-11ee-8311-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Five ways to save on train tickets as fares rise The jump is likely to be unwelcome for rail passengers, adding to the rising cost of living seen in recent years. It comes at a time when passengers have faced disruption to services due to strikes by rail workers over the past 18 months. Regulated fares cover about 45% of fares, including season tickets. Advance train tickets are usually released up to 12 weeks before your departure date, although some go on sale as far as 24 weeks in advance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much is the minimum wage going up?</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/9f1fa9da-dab5-11ee-9b97-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 14:01:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/9f1fa9da-dab5-11ee-9b97-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How much is the minimum wage going up? From 1 April, employees 21 and over will be entitled to the National Living Wage. The rate will be £11. 44 an hour, up from £10. 42 an hour.&#xA;The Real Living Wage - a higher amount voluntarily paid by some UK businesses - will remain the same. From 1 April, the National Minimum Wage will apply to younger employees between 16 and 20.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How much income tax and National Insurance do I have to pay?</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/511cc82c-dab4-11ee-a6fd-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 14:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/511cc82c-dab4-11ee-a6fd-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How much income tax and National Insurance do I have to pay? There is speculation that the government might cut income tax or National Insurance in the spring Budget. NI contributions have already fallen for millions of employees, with a reduction for self-employed workers due to take effect in April. But changes to the way tax is calculated mean that the amount of tax people pay overall is at record levels.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who gets 15 hours of free childcare and when do I apply?</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/2cce92ba-dab5-11ee-823e-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 16:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/2cce92ba-dab5-11ee-823e-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Who gets 15 hours of free childcare and when do I apply? The deadline is approaching for working parents in England to apply for 15 hours of free childcare a week for their two year olds. The government hopes that extending free childcare to this age group from April - and to all under fives in 2025 - will get more parents back to work. The deadline to get free hours for two-year-olds in the spring term is 31 March.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Download now</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/72549814-dcc9-11ee-a2b8-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 10:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/72549814-dcc9-11ee-a2b8-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Download now With the latest news and analysis from our journalists around the world and the unique human stories behind current events, we&amp;rsquo;ve got the best of our journalism in one place on the BBC News app. Depending on the contract you have, data charges may apply for accessing the internet on your mobile device. The BBC does not charge you to access mobile content. You may find some costs are included in your existing price plan or that you can opt for a data package that gives reduced charges for accessing the internet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Download now</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/b5839e42-dab6-11ee-92a2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 10:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/b5839e42-dab6-11ee-92a2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Download now With the latest news and analysis from our journalists around the world and the unique human stories behind current events, we&amp;rsquo;ve got the best of our journalism in one place on the BBC News app. Depending on the contract you have, data charges may apply for accessing the internet on your mobile device. The BBC does not charge you to access mobile content. You may find some costs are included in your existing price plan or that you can opt for a data package that gives reduced charges for accessing the internet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Download now</title>
      <link>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/df96c9ea-dbf9-11ee-a90a-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 10:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fiveminutesread.github.io/post/df96c9ea-dbf9-11ee-a90a-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Download now With the latest news and analysis from our journalists around the world and the unique human stories behind current events, we&amp;rsquo;ve got the best of our journalism in one place on the BBC News app. Depending on the contract you have, data charges may apply for accessing the internet on your mobile device. The BBC does not charge you to access mobile content. You may find some costs are included in your existing price plan or that you can opt for a data package that gives reduced charges for accessing the internet.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
