<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>China on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/china/</link>
    <description>Recent content in China on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 06:16:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/china/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Simon Harris - a man in a hurry to the top</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/4d903cd6-e9df-11ee-bb36-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 06:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/4d903cd6-e9df-11ee-bb36-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Simon Harris - a man in a hurry to the top Simon Harris, 37, is a year younger than Leo Varadkar was when he took the same job in 2017. Harris organised his first political meeting at just 16 years of age. He was a county councillor at 22, a TD (member of the Irish Parliament) at 24. Harris dropped out of college without finishing his degree.&#xA;Mr Harris was born in 1986 and grew up in the coastal town of Greystones, County Wicklow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jealous K-pop fans try to dictate their idols&#39; private lives</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/221a79a4-e9da-11ee-ad6b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:07:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/221a79a4-e9da-11ee-ad6b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Jealous K-pop fans try to dictate their idols&amp;rsquo; private lives K-pop star Karina posted a handwritten apology on Instagram earlier in March. The apology came after she acknowledged that she was in a relationship with actor Lee Jae-wook. It opens a window into the world of K-pop&amp;rsquo;s super fans. They stream their favourite stars&amp;rsquo; music round the clock to boost chart rankings.&#xA;When news of Karina&amp;rsquo;s relationship broke, some fans drove a truck to her management agency.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Gaza war is testing the limits of US diplomacy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/be7d94ce-e93b-11ee-8987-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 03:19:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/be7d94ce-e93b-11ee-8987-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How Gaza war is testing the limits of US diplomacy US Secretary of State Antony Blinken met with Israeli protesters in Tel Aviv. He was seen gripping the hands of protesters calling for a deal to release the hostages held by Hamas. It was a strong message from America#39;s top diplomat to both the Israeli public and its prime minister. The US has been putting pressure on Israel to act on the crisis in Gaza.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hong Kong passes tough security law</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1992721a-e5e7-11ee-9428-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 11:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1992721a-e5e7-11ee-9428-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Hong Kong passes tough security law Article 23 targets new offences like external interference and insurrection. It was fast-tracked through its final stage by the city#39;s pro-Beijing parliament in less than two weeks. Critics fear it will further erode civil liberties in Hong Kong. It expands on a controversial national security law earlier imposed by China.&#xA;Scores of people have been arrested under the NSL since it was passed in 2020.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raducanu&#39;s lower back injury &#39;nothing serious&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/18a07d7c-e5f9-11ee-a46b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 11:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/18a07d7c-e5f9-11ee-a46b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Raducanu&amp;rsquo;s lower back injury &amp;rsquo;nothing serious&#39; The 21-year-old was due to face China#39;s Wang Xiyu in the first round on Tuesday. Raducanu was beaten in straight sets by world number two Aryna Sabalenka in the third round at Indian Wells last week. It is not known whether the injury will impact her selection for Great Britain&amp;rsquo;s King Cup squad. Raducanu had recorded back-to-back victories for the first time since winning three in a row at Indian Wells 12 months ago.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Hong Kong&#39;s tough new security law?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/a1020e5e-e5ec-11ee-9490-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 11:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/a1020e5e-e5ec-11ee-9490-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>What is Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s tough new security law? A full draft of Article 23, which covers treason, sedition and state secrets, was tabled on 8 March. It follows a national security law (NSL) imposed by Beijing in 2020. Authorities credit it with restoring stability in the city after widespread pro-democracy protests. Mr Lee says he will sign the bill into law and gazette it on 23 March.&#xA;The law was tabled a week after the end of a month-long consultation period.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is TikTok really a danger to the West?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/f15885cc-e5ec-11ee-b97b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/f15885cc-e5ec-11ee-b97b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Is TikTok really a danger to the West? TikTok has been accused of harvesting huge amounts of data. The app collects details such as location, what specific device is being used and which other apps are on it. China has attacked a bill going through US Congress that could ultimately see TikTok banned in the States. TikTok is owned by Beijing-based tech giant ByteDance, making it unique as a non-American mainstream app.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why firms are bringing their manufacturing back home</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/56b66b1a-e12d-11ee-b95d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:06:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/56b66b1a-e12d-11ee-b95d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Why firms are bringing their manufacturing back home Reshoring is when a company decides to stop getting its manufacturing done overseas, such as in China, and instead returns the work to its home country. Chris Ball and Ian Whateley are the bosses of Shropshire-based Advanced Chemical Etching (Ace) Ace makes precision metal components for customers in the aerospace, automotive, electronics and telecoms sectors. More than half of UK manufacturers are now reshoring, according to a study.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
