<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oil on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/oil/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oil on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 07:54:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/oil/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hygiene poverty is a sign of crisis, says charity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6b9b6f5a-e9e1-11ee-b81f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 07:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6b9b6f5a-e9e1-11ee-b81f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Hygiene poverty is a sign of crisis, says charity The Hygiene Bank helps people who cannot afford basic essential toiletries. A new survey found that more than three million people in the UK are thought to be experiencing hygiene poverty. Volunteers at one of the charity&amp;rsquo;s schemes, in Bromley, south-east London, said a school washed pupils&amp;rsquo; clothes. The charity receives donations from the community, which are sorted by volunteers.&#xA;34;It often the first sign that a family is falling into crisis when they can&amp;rsquo;t afford these basic essentials,’ she said.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Oasis&#39; first tour venues, 30 years on</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/5549aa36-e938-11ee-9fbf-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 02:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/5549aa36-e938-11ee-9fbf-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Revisiting Oasis&amp;rsquo; first tour venues, 30 years on Exactly 30 years ago, a little-known band called Oasis set out on their first headline tour. Mark Davyd was asked to book a gig by a rising Scottish band called Whiteout at his venue in Kent in March 1994. He wasn#39;t keen when he found out that an unfamiliar Mancunian group would also be on the bill. He wanted to put on a local support act instead - but the agent stressed it was a joint headlined tour.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is this the worst economic inheritance since WW2?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b3f29028-e6f6-11ee-b805-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 11:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b3f29028-e6f6-11ee-b805-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Is this the worst economic inheritance since WW2? There are certainly problems facing the next government, but other governments in the last 80 years have also faced big economic challenges. Margaret Thatcher came to power in 1979 at the time of an oil crisis and rapidly-rising prices. The coalition government of 2010 followed a global financial crisis. Net debt as a percentage of Gross Domestic Product (GDP) is currently at levels last seen in the early 1960s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The WhatsApp group that saved trafficked women</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/cbb90e4a-e52e-11ee-87b2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/cbb90e4a-e52e-11ee-87b2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The WhatsApp group that saved trafficked women BBC Africa Eye investigates how a WhatsApp group helped save more than 50 Malawian women trafficked to Oman to work in slave-like conditions. WARNING: Some people may find details in this story distressing. A 32-year-old woman breaks down in tears as she relives the abuse she experienced when she found herself working as a maid in Oman. Malawi woman says she was forced to have anal sex by her boss.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heat pumps too expensive, government warned</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/34a478c0-e52c-11ee-ad9f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:14:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/34a478c0-e52c-11ee-ad9f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Heat pumps too expensive, government warned Despite its target, only 55,000 heat pumps were sold in the UK in 2022. Sales must increase dramatically, said the UK#39;s spending watchdog. To meet UK climate change targets, the government wants to install 600,000 low-carbon heat pumps annually by 2028. Heating in UK homes produces 18% of the country#39;s greenhouse gas emissions.&#xA;Only 55,000 heat pumps were sold in the UK in 2022. National Audit Office (NAO) said ministers were optimistic to think that target could be reached by 2028.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Putin&#39;s fifth term as Russian leader was never in doubt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/900399c0-e52d-11ee-909f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 18:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/900399c0-e52d-11ee-909f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Why Putin&amp;rsquo;s fifth term as Russian leader was never in doubt Kremlin ensured Putin had no credible opponent so it was always certain he would secure a fifth term by a landslide. It was at a grand military awards ceremony last December that Vladimir Putin, 71, told the Russian public he would stand for the presidency again. He said: &amp;ldquo;Now is the time for making decisions. I will be running for the post of president of the Russian Federation&amp;rdquo; Kremlin rarely leaves its choreography to chance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia says it repelled multiple drone attacks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/379bb48e-e46a-11ee-985b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 10:36:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/379bb48e-e46a-11ee-985b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Russia says it repelled multiple drone attacks Russia&amp;rsquo;s defence ministry says its forces have destroyed dozens of drones. The biggest attack happened in the southern Russian region of Krasnodar. The attacks come as Russia holds a general election in which President Vladimir Putin is guaranteed to win. In Ukraine, officials reported an overnight barrage of Russian drones and missiles on the port city of Odesa.&#xA;Five drones were downed in different areas while flying towards the capital.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The bomb scare, the police and the drag queen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/6127453a-e469-11ee-8db7-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 03:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/6127453a-e469-11ee-8db7-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The bomb scare, the police and the drag queen Robert McCready, then 27, from Ballywalter in County Down, was getting ready to go out with friends for the opening of a new gay bar in Belfast. He was going out dressed as his drag persona the Baroness Titti Von Tramp. This is the story of the drag queen, the police Land Rover, the bomb scare and a photo that travelled the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aid reaches shore in Gaza after first sea delivery</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/27bf0efc-e399-11ee-a3c2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 09:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/27bf0efc-e399-11ee-a3c2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Aid reaches shore in Gaza after first sea delivery The US charity behind the mission, World Central Kitchen, is carrying out the mission in co-operation with the United Arab Emirates. The shipment contained 200 tonnes of food desperately needed for Gaza, which the UN says is on the brink of famine. Aid agencies have accused Israel of impeding aid deliveries, a charge vehemently denied. The shipment arrived on board Spanish charity ship Open Arms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US Open champion Clark leads Players as McIlroy toils</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2a140628-e3ab-11ee-97d3-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 23:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2a140628-e3ab-11ee-97d3-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>US Open champion Clark leads Players as McIlroy toils Wyndham Clark four shots clear at halfway point of Players Championship. US Open champion carded a second seven-under-par 65. Xander Schauffele and Nick Taylor are on 10 under, with Matt Fitzpatrick and Maverick McNealy a stroke further back. Rory McIlroy slipped back to six under with a 73.&#xA;Scheffler posts five birdies in his 69 despite playing most of the round in discomfort.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trying to stay alive in a town tormented by drugs, alcohol and suicide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1897f9d2-e2d3-11ee-bfed-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 08:25:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1897f9d2-e2d3-11ee-bfed-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Trying to stay alive in a town tormented by drugs, alcohol and suicide Blackpool has the highest rate of deaths linked to alcohol, drug abuse and suicide in England. BBC News met a team of former addicts trying to turn around the lives of people in the town. Paul Earnshaw is about to start a detox course, followed by what could be up to six months of rehab. Sitting on a sofa in the Blackpool offices of the charity Empowerment, Paul is reflecting on where he has ended up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fear and chaos await Haitian migrants forced back over border</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/22cf15a4-e222-11ee-84a7-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 14:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/22cf15a4-e222-11ee-84a7-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Fear and chaos await Haitian migrants forced back over border A constant stream of trucks pulls up carrying undocumented Haitian migrants. They are being deported back to their home country. Haiti is in the grip of its most acute humanitarian crisis since the devastating earthquake in 2010. One man says he was taken from his home after three years in the Dominican Republic.&#xA;More than 350,000 people have been internally displaced in Haiti.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How fast are prices rising in the UK?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/00d0df86-e534-11ee-bc51-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 09:59:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/00d0df86-e534-11ee-bc51-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How fast are prices rising in the UK? Prices in the UK are no longer rising as fast as wages, official figures show. However, inflation of 4% in January was still significantly above the Bank of England#39;s target. This means knock-on effects for interest rates could be significant. Core inflation was 5.&#xA;1% in January, according to the Bank of England. This excludes the price of energy, food, alcohol and tobacco.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How fast are prices rising in the UK?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1dd39b02-e5f5-11ee-84f2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 09:59:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1dd39b02-e5f5-11ee-84f2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How fast are prices rising in the UK? Prices in the UK are no longer rising as fast as wages, official figures show. However, inflation of 4% in January was still significantly above the Bank of England#39;s target. This means knock-on effects for interest rates could be significant. Core inflation was 5.&#xA;1% in January, according to the Bank of England. This excludes the price of energy, food, alcohol and tobacco.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How fast are prices rising in the UK?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/da30ae84-e2da-11ee-94d4-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 09:59:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/da30ae84-e2da-11ee-94d4-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How fast are prices rising in the UK? Prices in the UK are no longer rising as fast as wages, official figures show. However, inflation of 4% in January was still significantly above the Bank of England#39;s target. This means knock-on effects for interest rates could be significant. Core inflation was 5.&#xA;1% in January, according to the Bank of England. This excludes the price of energy, food, alcohol and tobacco.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ukraine-based groups claim raids into Russia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/17bf968e-e074-11ee-998b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 12:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/17bf968e-e074-11ee-998b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Ukraine-based groups claim raids into Russia The Freedom of Russia Legion (FRL) and Siberian Battalion (SB) posted videos purportedly showing their fighters in Russia. The SVR and an exiled Russian politician claimed two villages were now in control of &amp;ldquo;liberation forces. Ukraine&amp;rsquo;s military denied any involvement in Tuesday&amp;rsquo;s cross-border raids. The Il-76 military-transport plane crashed shortly after take-off.&#xA;The ministry said an engine fire caused the crash. Russia said Ukraine had launched 25 drones on targets across Russia, but the attack was thwarted.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaza medics tell BBC that Israeli troops beat and humiliated them</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/fb3d476a-e071-11ee-9a4f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 06:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/fb3d476a-e071-11ee-9a4f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Gaza medics tell BBC that Israeli troops beat and humiliated them Ahmed Abu Sabha, a doctor at Nasser hospital, described being held for a week in detention. He said muzzled dogs were set upon him and his hand was broken by an Israeli soldier. Two other medics wanted to remain anonymous for fear of reprisals. They told the BBC they were humiliated, beaten, doused with cold water, and forced to kneel in uncomfortable positions for hours.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How fast are prices rising in the UK?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/90d3da0a-e081-11ee-9978-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 10:20:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/90d3da0a-e081-11ee-9978-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>How fast are prices rising in the UK? Prices in the UK are no longer rising as fast as wages, official figures show. However, inflation of 4% in January was still significantly above the Bank of England&amp;rsquo;s target. This means knock-on effects for interest rates could be significant. Core inflation was 5.&#xA;1% in January, according to the Bank of England. This excludes the price of energy, food, alcohol and tobacco.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My abusive ex-boyfriend was given a verbal warning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/4e8c4320-dfba-11ee-8590-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 06:12:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/4e8c4320-dfba-11ee-8590-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>My abusive ex-boyfriend was given a verbal warning Lauren Hardie was left with bite marks, bruising on her arms, shoulder and eye. She posted videos online of an attack she had secretly recorded on her phone. The 24-year-old nurse says she felt so let down by the justice system she turned to social media to expose him. Lauren is one of seven women whose journey through the justice system feature in the BBC Scotland Disclosure documentary.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saudi oil giant sees sharp fall in profits</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/4c635cc6-deea-11ee-8861-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 11:24:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/4c635cc6-deea-11ee-8861-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Saudi oil giant sees sharp fall in profits profits fell 25% to $121bn (£91bn) profits after a record-smashing year in 2022. But the figure is still the second-highest profit ever for the state-backed company. The firm said it was boosting its payments to shareholders and looking for opportunities to invest in China. Saudi Arabia is aiming to diversify the country&amp;rsquo;s economy, using income from its energy sector to fund the transition to renewable energy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Red Bull victorious but things anything but serene behind the scenes&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/135a6414-de7d-11ee-b8f3-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:14:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/135a6414-de7d-11ee-b8f3-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Red Bull victorious but things anything but serene behind the scenes&amp;rsquo; Red Bull driver Max Verstappen wins his 29th race in a row. The Dutchman has been in fine form since returning to Formula One in 2013. But he has been dogged by allegations of sexual misconduct. He has been accused of using a female masseuse as a &amp;lsquo;favourite&amp;rsquo; Red Bull has always been a secretive organisation that tightly controlled the flow of information to the outside world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FF7 actress&#39;s nervous wait for fan reactions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/30d74bf0-de79-11ee-ba7b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 01:43:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/30d74bf0-de79-11ee-ba7b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>FF7 actress&amp;rsquo;s nervous wait for fan reactions Briana White plays Aerith Gainsborough in Final Fantasy 7 (FF7) Rebirth. The game is the second part of a trilogy that remakes the legendary, influential 1997 Japanese role-playing game (JRPG) Briana provides the English language voiceover for Aerith. Rebirth has been released last week and is packed with side activities and mini-games that can push the play time closer to 100 hours. Fans have been racing to get to the end of the game to see whether that departure from the original storyline does occur.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The worlds largest robots are setting sail</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/d2309930-dcc5-11ee-9a0c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:04:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/d2309930-dcc5-11ee-9a0c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The world&amp;rsquo;s largest robots are setting sail Ocean Infinity is building a fleet of 23 vessels that will survey the seabed for offshore wind farm operators and check underwater infrastructure for the oil and gas industry. The new vessel, the Armada, has cameras, microphones, radars, GPS and all manner of satellite communications. But for a ship that&amp;rsquo;s 78m in length there are only 16 people on board. A traditional ship carrying out the same kind of work would need a crew of 40 or 50.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
