<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scotland on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/scotland/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scotland on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 11:00:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/scotland/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Doctors&#39; A&lt;title&gt;E safety warnings snubbed by watchdog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/053cb2ca-eaa7-11ee-9a10-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 11:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/053cb2ca-eaa7-11ee-9a10-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Doctors&amp;rsquo; AE safety warnings snubbed by watchdog Aamp;E consultants at Glasgow&amp;rsquo;s Queen Elizabeth University Hospital wrote to Healthcare Improvement Scotland (HIS) to warn patient safety was being compromised. They offered 18 months worth of evidence of overcrowding and staff shortages to back their claims. But HIS did not ask for this evidence. HIS has issued a &amp;ldquo;sincere and unreserved apology&amp;rdquo;&amp;quot; to the consultants and upheld two complaints about the way it handled their whistleblowing letter about patient safety.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Briton &#39;overjoyed&#39; at completing one of world&#39;s toughest races</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/92cebdb0-e9dd-11ee-a67f-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 11:27:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/92cebdb0-e9dd-11ee-a67f-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Briton &amp;lsquo;overjoyed&amp;rsquo; at completing one of world&amp;rsquo;s toughest races Jasmin Paris from Midlothian completed the Barkley Marathons in Tennessee with just one minute 39 seconds to spare. The course, at Frozen Head State Park, changes every year but covers 100 miles involving 60,000ft of climb and descent. Only 20 people have ever made it to the end of the race within the allotted 60 hours. Jasmin lost her voice from heavy breathing during the race.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Briton becomes first woman to finish one of world&#39;s toughest races</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2be828e8-e92e-11ee-a363-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 11:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2be828e8-e92e-11ee-a363-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Briton becomes first woman to finish one of world&amp;rsquo;s toughest races Jasmin Paris from Midlothian completed the Barkley Marathons in Tennessee with just one minute 39 seconds to spare of the 60-hour cut off. The course, at Frozen Head State Park, changes every year but covers 100 miles involving 60,000ft of climb and descent. Only 20 people have ever made it to the end of the race within the allotted 60 hours since it was extended to 100 miles in 1989.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sunak declines to back MP&#39;s Down&#39;s syndrome abortion law change</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/7763a334-e6f8-11ee-b7fb-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 17:33:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/7763a334-e6f8-11ee-b7fb-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Sunak declines to back MP&amp;rsquo;s Down&amp;rsquo;s syndrome abortion law change Currently, pregnancies involving foetuses with Down#39;s syndrome can be terminated up to the point of birth. Conservative MP Sir Liam Fox is leading a cross-party campaign to bring the time limit into line with foetus without serious disabilities. Leading charity the Down&amp;rsquo;s Syndrome Association has called for a review of the law in light of advances in medical science. The time limit for most UK abortions was 24 weeks into pregnancy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electricity upgrade plan includes miles of pylons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/b9e1acdc-e5eb-11ee-a95c-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 11:12:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/b9e1acdc-e5eb-11ee-a95c-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Electricity upgrade plan includes miles of pylons Some 4,000 miles of undersea cables and 1,000 power lines are needed. The investment would add between £20 to £30 a year to customer bills. The plans were written up by the National Grid, which runs the electricity network. The government said the ESO&amp;rsquo;s plans were preliminary and yet to pass a planning process.&#xA;The £58bn estimate is for work needed between 2030 and 2035.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Scotsman swapping sprinting for a shot at NFL</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/9d931764-e537-11ee-98dd-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 09:55:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/9d931764-e537-11ee-98dd-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>The Scotsman swapping sprinting for a shot at NFL The 23-year-old finds himself in the final weeks of the NFL#39;s International Player Pathway. 16 athletes from the around the world who may never before have known the brown leather of a football are given the opportunity to step on to the sport#40;s biggest stage. Olatoke has taken that Scottish gallus streak stateside. American football has grown exponentially in the UK over the past decade.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>St Patrick’s celebrations to take place across NI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/e4341e06-e470-11ee-853b-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 12:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/e4341e06-e470-11ee-853b-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>St Patrick’s celebrations to take place across NI Thousands gather in towns and cities across Northern Ireland to celebrate St Patrick. In Belfast the parade got under way at City Hall at 13:30 GMT. In Downpatrick a pilgrimage walk was led by religious leaders from Saul Church to Down Cathedral, the saint#39;s burial place. In Cushendall more than 200 people attended the village#34;s first St Patrick#38;s festival.&#xA;Police warned of traffic disruption in many areas due to the festivities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scottish childminder numbers halve in a decade</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/19e0fe2a-e471-11ee-b866-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 11:05:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/19e0fe2a-e471-11ee-b866-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Scottish childminder numbers halve in a decade Scottish Labour obtained the figures in response to a written question at Holyrood. The number of childminders dropped from just over 6,200 in December 2012 to 3,530 in December 2022. The figures were obtained by Scottish Labour from the Scottish Office for National Statistics. The government said it valued the role of childminders and was working to recruit and retain staff.&#xA;As of December last year there were 3,225 people working in the profession.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Election is a straight fight with Tories - Yousaf</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/1f84098a-e39f-11ee-8c25-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 09:59:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/1f84098a-e39f-11ee-8c25-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Election is a straight fight with Tories - Yousaf The SNP leader is due to speak at a party event in Perth. He is expected to call on members to make Scotland #34;Tory free. It comes as a recent poll suggested the SNP and Labour are level with voters. In October last year, Labour defeated the SNP in the Rutherglen and Hamilton West by election with a swing of 20.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World&#39;s largest trees are &#39;thriving in UK&#39;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/43b9133c-e128-11ee-878d-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 01:33:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/43b9133c-e128-11ee-878d-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>World&amp;rsquo;s largest trees are &amp;rsquo;thriving in UK&#39; An estimated 500,000 trees are in the UK compared to 80,000 in California. In California they can reach 90m-high, but in UK the tallest is 54. 87m. But that#39;s because the introduced trees are still very young.&#xA;Giant redwoods were first brought to the UK by the Victorians. They were the ultimate botanical status symbol. Today, some form sweeping avenues while others stand in ones or twos.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which debts and bills should I pay first?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/9accd360-e881-11ee-94b2-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 09:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/9accd360-e881-11ee-94b2-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Which debts and bills should I pay first? 11 million adults in the UK struggle to pay their bills in January. This is a rise of 3. 1 million compared with 2022. Citizens Advice says you should work out how much you owe and who to pay.&#xA;There are what are known as priority debts and bills. If you do not pay them, you could lose your home or face court proceedings.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
