<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Red Bull on Five Minutes Reads</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/red-bull/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Red Bull on Five Minutes Reads</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 08:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/red-bull/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sainz wins in Australia after Verstappen retires</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/80588798-e9e6-11ee-a174-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 08:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/80588798-e9e6-11ee-a174-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Sainz wins in Australia after Verstappen retires Carlos Sainz leads Charles Leclerc to a Ferrari one-two in the Australian Grand Prix. Max Verstappen retires with a brake failure after just four laps. The race ended under a virtual safety car after a crash for George Russell. The Mercedes driver lost control at Turn Six on the final lap.&#xA;Alonso and Russell were called to the stewards, who penalised the Spaniard 20 seconds, dropping him to eighth place.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Verstappen takes Australia pole with Hamilton 11th</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/446d8a70-e942-11ee-af62-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 08:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/446d8a70-e942-11ee-af62-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Verstappen takes Australia pole with Hamilton 11th Red Bull&amp;rsquo;s Max Verstappen fights off a challenge from Ferrari driver Carlos Sainz to take pole position for the Australian Grand Prix. Red Bull#39;s Max VerStappen fought off a challenges from Ferrari&amp;rsquo;s Carlos Sianz to claim pole position. Sainz was quickest in the first two parts of qualifying but the world champion bounced back in the top 10 shootout. Lando Norris will start third ahead of Ferrari#39;s Charles Leclerc after a grid penalty for Red Bull&amp;rsquo;s Sergio Perez.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leclerc tops Australian GP second practice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/4bd845c2-e887-11ee-a6a1-7440bb76babf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 08:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/4bd845c2-e887-11ee-a6a1-7440bb76babf/</guid>
      <description>Leclerc tops Australian GP second practice Ferrari&amp;rsquo;s Charles Leclerc was 0. 381 seconds faster than Red Bull&amp;rsquo;s Max Verstappen. Carlos Sainz was third, from Lance Stroll and Fernando Alonso of Aston Martin and George Russell of Mercedes. Lewis Hamilton in the second Mercedes was 18th fastest.&#xA;Verstappen ran later than his rivals because of the enforced delay to his programme. He should have had the better of the track conditions when he set his fastest lap.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
